I'm I'm sick of multi-millionaires
我真是受够了那些千万富翁。
telling kids who can't afford to turn
告诉那些负担不起转学费用的孩子们
the heating on you just need to be more
你家的暖气需要调高一些。
entrepreneurial it's sick Dan it's sick
创业精神真糟糕，丹，真糟糕
well your video where you talk about if
嗯，你那个谈到如果的视频是这样的
you don't have a rich dad you're screwed
如果你没有个有钱的老爸，你就完蛋了。
well to me if I had have come across
对我来说，如果我遇到……
your content at 19 20 years old I would
你19、20岁时的内容我会……
have been screwed my friends can't feed
我的朋友们都倒霉透了，他们连饭都吃不上。
their kids okay if it was that easy why
如果事情真那么容易，他们的孩子就没事了。
is everybody not doing it I'll tell you
难道大家都不这么做吗？我告诉你。
why people aren't doing it it's because
人们不这么做的原因是：
you like to say one thing back on
你喜欢反驳别人。
that today's debate is fiery to say the
今天的辩论可谓异常激烈。
least but important nonetheless as I sat
然而，最不重要但却至关重要的是，当我坐在那里时……
down with two leading experts in wealth
与两位财富管理领域的顶尖专家一起探讨
and Entrepreneurship and the economy to
以及创业精神和经济
discuss the state of the US the state of
讨论美国的现状
the UK and the Western World do you
英国和西方世界，你觉得呢？
think the reason the average Brit
想想普通英国人为什么会这样
American are getting poorer is because
美国人越来越穷的原因是
they don't know how to create wealth no
他们不知道如何创造财富。
the reason people are getting poorer is
人们变得越来越穷的原因是
because of big governments record levels
因为政府规模庞大，创下历史新高。
of taxes an outdated schooling system
税收和过时的教育体系
technology and remote working you sure
科技和远程办公肯定
about that how do you disagree with
关于这一点，你有什么不同意见？
those opinions living standards are
这些观点认为生活水平是
falling because of growing wealth in
由于财富增长而下跌
equality if you allow the rich to get
如果允许富人获得平等，那就意味着平等。
richer they squeeze the middle class and
越富有，中产阶级就越受挤压。
the poor class out of things like
贫困阶层无法获得诸如此类的东西
housing let's cut tax on people who are
住房方面，让我们减免那些人的税收
working hard and let's raise tax on the
努力工作，让我们提高税收吧
richest and most powerful people in the
世界上最富有、最有权势的人
world that's an overly simplified view
这是一个过于简化的世界观
of things we now have a th000
我们现在拥有的东西有千种
millionaires a month leaving which means
每月有百万富翁离开，这意味着
every ordinary person who pays 10 grand
每个支付10000美元的普通人
a year in tax will now have to pay 20
一年的税款现在需要缴纳20
grand a year in tax you end up cutting
每年少交一千英镑的税，最终你会减少
off your nose to spite your face if we
我们
are a country that don't try and do
是一个不尝试的国家
things which are necessary because they
必需品，因为它们
are hard then our kids will live in
如果生活艰难，我们的孩子将生活在其中。
poverty what do you want people to do
贫困，你想让人们做什么？
there's a lot of different ways Backle
Backle有很多不同的方式
up this has always blown my mind a
这件事一直让我感到震惊。
little bit 53% of you that listen to the
听过这番话的人中，有53%的人有点儿……
show regularly haven't yet subscribed to
定期观看但尚未订阅
the show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，我能请你帮个忙吗？
before we start if you like the show and
在我们开始之前，如果你喜欢这个节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen to
我们每周都会听你的节目。
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈将帮助我们找到合适的客人
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do thank you so
请继续做我们正在做的事情，谢谢。
much
很多
Gary
加里
Daniel Daniel you've been on the show a
丹尼尔，你上过这个节目……
few times before so I want to start with
之前有过几次，所以我想先从……开始。
Gary and understand a little bit about
加里，我对他略知一二。
your backstory and who you are and
你的背景故事和你是谁
having been through the trading game and
经历过交易游戏之后
read and watched many many of your
阅读和观看了很多你的作品
videos over time I have a a sort of deep
随着时间的推移，我对视频产生了一种深深的……
understanding of that but for anyone
理解这一点，但对于任何人来说
that doesn't know you can you give me a
不知道你能给我一个
picture of the context that um has
嗯，上下文的图片
brought you to where you are today
把你带到今天的位置。
writing about the things you're writing
写你正在写的东西
about today and running the YouTube
今天的内容以及运营 YouTube
channel and speaking to the subject
频道和谈论这个话题
matter that you're speaking about today
你今天谈到的事情
take me right back and give me as much
带我回去，给我尽可能多的东西
as you possibly can okay so my name is
尽可能地，好的，我的名字是
Gary Stevenson uh I was born in a place
加里·史蒂文森：呃，我出生在一个地方
called ilford which is in outer East
名叫伊尔福德，位于东部外围。
London quite a poor family little
伦敦一个相当贫穷的家庭
Terrace House by the railway you know
你知道铁路旁的那栋露台别墅吗？
playing football in the streets kind of
在街头踢足球
stuff
东西
um always very good at maths since I was
我从小数学就很好。
a kid very talented Master student
一个非常有天赋的孩子，硕士研究生
eventually able to get into the London
最终得以进入伦敦
School of Economics which is an
经济学院是一个
extremely Elite University economics
顶尖大学经济学
University in the center of London which
位于伦敦市中心的大学
is basically a kind of investment
本质上是一种投资
banking boot camp got a job as a Trader
参加银行业训练营后，我找到了一份交易员的工作。
started working full-time as a
开始全职工作
short-term interest rates Trader at City
城市短期利率交易员
Bank in London in June
六月在伦敦的银行
2008 when I was 21 obviously yeah
2008年我21岁的时候，当然是的。
exactly that's just before the big
没错，就在大事件发生之前。
credit crash the big Leman crisis and I
信贷危机、莱曼大危机以及我
watched the Leman Crisis happen in front
亲眼目睹了莱曼危机的发生
of my eyes I was um short-term interest
我当时的目光，嗯，只是短期兴趣。
rate trading is basically like
利率交易基本上就像
short-term loans and during the credit
短期贷款和信贷期间
crisis what credit crisis is is nobody
信贷危机是什么？没人知道。
can borrow any money so like short-term
可以借到任何金额的钱，比如短期贷款
loans become really really important
贷款变得非常重要
important my desk which was like
我的办公桌很重要，就像
historically an unfashionable area of
历史上曾是一个不时尚的地区
trading became like the center of the
交易变得像中心一样
crisis or one of the centers of the
危机或中心之一
crisis people started making tons of
危机时期的人们开始大量生产
money um I was working with all these
钱，嗯，我当时在处理所有这些事情。
crazy people and you can imagine me like
疯子，你可以想象我就是这样的人。
I turn up 21 years old and then like
我21岁的时候出现，然后就喜欢
within three months like everyone around
三个月内，就像周围所有人一样。
me is making a ton of money during the
我在这期间赚了很多钱
credit crisis but what really interested
信贷危机，但真正令人感兴趣的是什么？
me was what happened after the crisis
危机过后发生的事情让我感同身受。
itself which was so we're betting on
正是这一点，所以我们才押注于此。
interest
兴趣
rates long story short interest rates
利率，简而言之就是利率。
come down when the economy is weak and
经济疲软时下降
they go up when the economy is strong or
当经济强劲时，它们就会上涨。
when the economy is overheating from an
当经济过热时
inflation perspective in 2018 all the
2018年通胀前景
interest rates go to zero so suddenly
利率突然降至零
our job is basically predicting and
我们的工作基本上就是预测和
betting on when will those interest
押注这些兴趣何时会兴起
rates go back up which is when will the
利率何时会回升？
economy recover and this is super
经济复苏，这真是太棒了！
interesting right in
很有意思。
2008 because all the interest rates went
2008年，因为所有利率都下降了。
to zero so quickly like before 2008 it's
像2008年之前那样迅速归零。
important to remember rates would move
需要记住的是，利率会变动。
from like five and a half to five and a
大概从五点半到五点半
quarter and then here in 2008 everywhere
季度，然后是2008年这里到处都是
in the world slashing to zero Bo half a
在世界范围内，削减至零 Bo 一半
percent exactly and everybody all the
百分之百准确，每个人都完全
economists were like wow this is going
经济学家们当时都惊呆了，心想：哇，这可真是……
to cause a massive recovery because they
导致大规模复苏，因为他们
thought that interest rates were
认为利率是
powerful and everybody predicted that
强大，人人都预料到了。
rates would come back up in 2009 which
利率将在2009年再次上涨。
of course we knowed they didn't then
我们当然知道他们当时并不知道。
everybody predicted that rates would go
所有人都预测利率会下降
up in 2010 which we now know they didn't
2010年的时候，我们现在知道他们并没有这样做。
and then at the beginning of 2011
然后在2011年初
everybody was predicting rates would
所有人都预测利率会
definitely go up this year and this to
今年肯定会上涨，而且会涨到
me was so interesting so interesting
我真是太有趣了，太有趣了
because you know I studied master and
因为你知道我读的是硕士，
economics at one of the best economics
经济学，在最好的经济学之一
universities in the world and now I'm
世界各地的大学，现在我是
working with these traders who are
与这些交易员合作
getting paid millions of pounds a year
年薪数百万英镑
million pounds a year to predict the
每年花费数百万英镑来预测
economy to predict the interest rates
预测利率的经济数据
and everybody is wrong year after year
年复一年，每个人都错了。
after year and this
一年之后，这
was I was so amazing to me for a couple
我曾是多么美好的一件事，持续了几个月。
of reasons first of all it's like wow
首先，原因很简单，简直太棒了！
like this is a big thing that we as a
这就像是件大事，我们作为一个人
society should understand and like we're
社会应该理解并喜欢我们
getting it wrong but secondly
首先，我弄错了；其次，
if all of the best guys in the world are
如果世界上所有最优秀的人都是
getting this wrong then if I can figure
如果我弄错了，那我就能明白了。
this out I can make a ton of money here
这样做我能赚很多钱
G how much money did you make for City
G，你在曼城赚了多少钱？
Bank at the age of 24 years old that
24岁时在银行工作
year so that year 2011 I put this big
所以，2011年那一年，我做了这个大决定。
bet on that it would get worse forever
我敢肯定情况会永远恶化。
and I was City bank's most profitable
而我则是花旗银行最赚钱的员工。
Trader in the world that year and I made
那一年，我成为了世界顶级交易员，并且赚了不少钱。
them just over $ 35 million you made
你赚了他们超过3500万美元。
them $35 million you eventually decide
你最终会决定给他们3500万美元
to leave City Bank yeah why
离开花旗银行？是啊，为什么？
I mean I think that's an interesting
我的意思是，我觉得这很有意思。
question right you know in the sense
这个问题问得好，你知道，从这个意义上来说。
that I've just explained to you what
我刚才已经向你解释过了。
happened which is I made a ton of money
结果我赚了很多钱。
by betting on the collapse of Western
通过押注西方崩溃
Society uh I did it in 2011 I did it
社会，呃，我在2011年做的，我做的。
again in 2012
2012年再次
um I would prefer for it not to collapse
嗯，我希望它不要坍塌。
step and I'm trying to stop it from
一步，我正在试图阻止它
collapsing when you say it collapsing
当你说它崩溃时，它就崩溃了
what exactly you're referring to that
你具体指的是什么？
you you don't want to
你不想
collapse so you you born in Botswana
崩溃了，所以你出生在博茨瓦纳
right yeah do you still have family
对，你还有家人吗？
there um I've got family in Nigeria
嗯，我在尼日利亚有家人。
which is where my my family are from I
那是我家人的故乡。
was born in Botswana because we were
出生在博茨瓦纳，因为我们是
visiting there but got family in Africa
去那里旅行，但我在非洲有家人。
do you go to Nigeria much no I I've got
你经常去尼日利亚吗？不，我去过。
home in Cape Town in South Africa so I
我家在南非开普敦，所以我
see the it's a great place if you want
如果你想的话，这里是个好地方。
to see inequality I think there
我认为，要看到不平等现象，就必须正视这一点。
is a naivity in in in this country in
在这个国家，天真是一种天真。
places like the US that the kind of
像美国这样的地方，那种
inequality the kind of broad poverty
不平等，即广泛的贫困
that you see in places like South Africa
在南非等地你会看到这种情况
in places like Nigeria in places like
在尼日利亚等地，在诸如……的地方
India can't happen
印度不可能发生
here it will happen here that is the
这里将会发生这一切，就是这样。
future of this country that is the
这个国家的未来，就是
future of the US and I'm not just saying
美国的未来，我可不是随便说说。
that I'm betting on it and I've been
我押注于此，而且我一直如此。
betting on it for 15 years and I've been
我押注它已经15年了，我一直……
right for 15 years that is what I'm
没错，15年来我一直都是这样。
trying to avoid
尽量避免
Daniel where did you come from yeah so I
丹尼尔，你从哪里来？嗯，所以……
grew up in Australia um and I was born
我在澳大利亚长大，嗯，我出生
to low-income family I grew up in a
我成长在一个低收入家庭。
place that had 24% Unemployment uh
失业率高达24%的地方
pretty much the only jobs or
几乎只有这些工作或
opportunities around me were things like
我周围的机会包括：
uh the trades building construction Pest
呃，建筑施工害虫防治行业
Control um hospitality and tourism um so
控制酒店和旅游业
uh at 14 I got a job at McDonald's and
呃，我14岁的时候在麦当劳找到了一份工作，
then I'm got a job in a bar and Pizza
然后我在一家酒吧和披萨店找到了一份工作。
Hut delivery driving and I discover
小屋送货司机，我发现
entrepreneurship so I discover books
创业精神促使我发现书籍
about entrepreneurship and I discovered
关于创业，我发现
that some people make millions similar
有些人也通过类似的方式赚到了数百万美元。
to yourself you saw Canary WF I read a
你对自己说，你看到了金丝雀 WF，我读到
book about business ownership and as we
一本关于企业所有权的书，正如我们
sit here today can you give me the
今天坐在这里，你能给我……吗？
overview of your business success since
自那时以来您的业务成功概览
then yeah so I now have a group of
是的，我现在有一群
companies that I've either started or
我创办的公司或者
bought um there's I've just sold a
买了，嗯，我刚卖掉了一个
company so there's seven companies in
公司里共有七家公司。
the group um I've started a couple of
我创建的小组……嗯，我已经创建了几个……
software companies one of our companies
软件公司，我们的一家公司
is now the fastest growing one of the
现在是增长最快的
fastest growing companies in the UK um
英国增长最快的公司
we you know we're a software business uh
你知道，我们是一家软件公司。
I've got a couple of agencies I've got a
我有几个代理机构，我有一个
Education and Training business and
教育和培训业务及
where when you think about the UK and
当你想到英国时，你会想到什么？
broadly the Western world today
当今西方世界总体而言
what is your assessment of where we're
您如何评价我们目前的处境？
at as a country and what's concerning
作为一个国家，有哪些令人担忧的问题？
you because Gary expressed quite
你是因为加里表达了相当
articulately that his big concern is
他清晰地表达了他最关心的问题。
that because of wealth INE equality
因为财富导致不平等
we're going to end up in a similar
我们最终会陷入类似的境地。
position to the likes of India what are
与印度等国相比，它们的地位是什么？
you concerned about I agree that it
你担心的，我同意。
wasn't that long ago that we had real
不久之前，我们还拥有真正的
serious wealth inequality in this
这方面存在严重的财富不平等现象。
country there are amazing photos from
那个国家有很多令人惊叹的照片
like a 100 years ago of kids working in
就像一百年前的孩子们在……工作一样
mines and kids doing oyster shocking and
地雷和孩子们在进行牡蛎电击作业
all this horrible work and um you know
所有这些糟糕的工作，嗯，你知道的
there's a there's a book Charles Dickens
有一本书，查尔斯·狄更斯
wrot wrote called The Tale of Two Cities
写成名为《双城记》
and the opening line of the book is it
而这本书的开篇第一句就是……
was the best of times it was the worst
这是最好的时代，也是最坏的时代。
of times and I think we've actually
很多次了，我认为我们实际上已经
gotten to that point here where some
到了这里，一些
people in the UK it's the best of times
英国人民，这是最好的时代。
if you uh like in your situation you're
如果你……就像你目前的情况一样
you know you're booming you're a
你知道你很成功，你是一个
globally successful business um I've got
全球成功的企业，嗯，我有
a globally successful business and then
一家全球成功的企业，然后
there are a lot of people who completely
有很多人完全
cannot relate to this their you know
无法理解他们的感受，你知道的。
Energy prices are now the most expensive
能源价格目前处于最高水平。
in the Western World house prices are
在西方世界，房价是
completely unaffordable it used to be
以前完全买不起
used to take 3 years to for a deposit
过去需要3年时间才能拿到存款
it's now 20 years if you you know
现在已经20年了，如果你知道的话。
theoretically 20 years if you can save
理论上，如果你能存钱的话，可以存20年。
for a deposit food prices are through
押金用于食品价格。
the roof so we're we're in a really diff
屋顶，所以我们现在处境非常不同。
like for anyone who is not tapped into
就像任何没有接入网络的人一样
digital economy fast growth and all of
数字经济快速增长以及所有
that sort of stuff life is getting
生活就是这样。
harder and worse um and things are
更难更糟了，嗯，事情是
collapsing um if you if you would um go
崩溃了，嗯，如果你，如果你愿意，嗯，去
with that the there is a predictable
因此，存在一种可预测性。
path countries go on and there's this
各国继续前行，还有这一点
thing called the economic freedom index
所谓的经济自由指数
and the economic freedom index basically
以及经济自由指数基本上
says how economically free are you how
你说你经济上有多自由？
how much access do you have to free
你有多少免费访问权限？
markets um do can you start a business
市场啊，你能创业吗？
can you scale a business um does
你能把业务规模扩大吗？嗯，可以吗？
anything inhibit your ability to run
任何会阻碍你跑步能力的事情
your own life countries that have high
你自己的生活，那些拥有高水平的国家
degrees of economic freedom have very
经济自由度具有非常大的程度
low poverty they have widespread
低贫困率，他们普遍存在
affluence and countries that have low
富裕程度低的国家
economic freedoms have high poverty and
经济自由与高贫困率相关，
it can be the difference between less
这可能是差别的大小。
than 10% right up to 70% poverty rates
贫困率从10%到70%不等。
um and when countries go on a path
嗯，当国家走上一条道路
towards economic freedom poverty just
迈向经济自由，摆脱贫困
drops so India for examp example has
例如，印度的降幅就很大。
been on that path and they announced
他们一直走在那条路上，并且宣布
today that they've almost eradicated uh
今天他们几乎已经根除了呃
abject poverty or extreme poverty um the
赤贫或极端贫困
UK went on that path of low economic
英国走上了低迷经济的道路。
freedom to high economic freedom and we
从自由到高度经济自由，我们
saw poverty rates come right down but in
贫困率大幅下降，但在
2008 when the global financial crisis
2008年全球金融危机
happened one of the things that happened
其中一件发生的事情发生了。
is the government said we need to step
政府说我们需要采取行动
in and we need to take charge and
我们需要掌控局面。
everyone said please do um so they came
大家都说请这样做，所以他们就来了。
in and they said all right we're going
他们进去后说，好的，我们走。
to ramp up debt ramp up taxes uh to pay
增加债务，增加税收，呃，为了支付
for the debt and we're also going to put
为了偿还债务，我们还要投入
it all regul in and unfortunately that
这一切都很正常，不幸的是……
starts to reduce economic freedom then
然后开始削弱经济自由
the pandemic happens and they say oh
疫情爆发后，他们却说哦
we're going to spend more money again
我们又要花更多钱了。
through debt we're going to have more uh
通过债务，我们将拥有更多……
taxes more regulations less economic
税收增加、监管增多、经济效益下降
freedom so the UK we went from an 82
所以英国从82年获得了自由
when I arrived in 2006 went from 82 out
我2006年到任时，排名从82位跃升至42位。
of 100 down to 68 out of 100 so we're
从100分降到68分（满分100分），所以我们是
less economically free and predictably
经济自由度和可预测性降低
what we will always see happen if you
如果你这样做，我们总会看到这样的事情发生。
lower people's economic freedom more
降低人们的经济自由度
poverty
贫困
uh less affluence uh the Millionaires
呃，不太富裕的人，呃，百万富翁们
and the wealth creators leave uh the
财富创造者们离开了……
people who are stuck in um dead end jobs
那些困在毫无前途的工作中的人
uh or no jobs get incredibly frustrated
呃，或者没有工作会让人非常沮丧
everyone starts looking for someone to
每个人都开始寻找某人
blame people are angry and they're like
人们责怪别人，他们很生气，他们会这样想。
who do we blame and who do they blame
我们该责怪谁？他们又该责怪谁？
it's very different because in the US we
情况截然不同，因为在美国我们
blame us blam someone different to the
责怪我们，责怪别人。
UK so we have a historical cultural
英国，所以我们拥有悠久的历史文化
memory in the UK we have a cultural
英国的记忆，我们拥有文化
memory that the people to blame are the
人们记住，应该受到谴责的人是
rich so so uh we have landlords and uh
有钱，所以，呃，我们有房东，呃……
aristocracy and the landed gentry those
贵族和乡绅
guys are to blame right so blame the
都是男人的错，对吧？所以要怪就怪男人。
rich is what we say in the UK in the US
在英国和美国，我们用“rich”这个词。
they have a very different view their
他们的观点截然不同。
cultural memory is that they're
文化记忆就是他们是
anti-government they want limited
他们想要限制反政府行为。
government in 2023 there was this song
2023年政府有这首歌
that came out called uh rich men north
那本书叫做《北方富人》。
of uh Richmond and it was the number one
呃，里士满，而且是第一名。
song in America and the lyrics of the
这首歌在美国以及歌词
song basically says people in Washington
这首歌基本上是在说华盛顿的人们
do not care about working people um they
他们根本不在乎劳动人民。
ATT taxing everything we touch you can't
AT&amp;T 对我们接触的一切都征税，你无法控制。
earn money they depreciate the dollar um
他们赚钱，却导致美元贬值。
they tax tax tax tax tax and they want
他们征税，他们想要
to control Our Lives those are the
掌控我们的生活，那就是
lyrics of the songs controlling our
控制我们歌曲的歌词
lives and taxing us so the American uh
美国人靠这种方式谋生并向我们征税。
reaction to this is who's to blame
对此的反应是：谁该为此负责？
government so we want smaller government
政府规模越小，我们越希望政府规模越小。
we want a department of government
我们想要一个政府部门
efficiency to come in we want someone as
为了提高效率，我们需要一个这样的人
a wrecking ball who will come in and
一个会闯进来的破坏者
smash government the British instinct is
推翻政府是英国人的本能。
hate the rich it must be the Rich's
憎恨富人，一定是富人的错。
fault so when we look for like all all
故障，所以当我们寻找所有的一切时
of the Western countries that
西方国家
implemented lower economic
实施了较低的经济政策
freedoms created more poverty less
自由反而导致更多贫困
affluence and more disruption to their
富裕以及对他们的更多干扰
economies so both us and UK for example
例如，美国和英国的经济状况都是如此。
and Australia as well but both sides of
澳大利亚也是如此，但双方都是
the pond want someone to blame it's just
池塘想找个人来背锅，它就是这样。
that the Americans blame government and
美国人指责政府和
we blame the rich Gary I'm sure you you
我们责怪有钱的加里，我肯定你……
have a lot to to say there I know you
我知道你有很多话想说。
both use the word collapsing so you
两者都使用了“崩溃”这个词，所以你
agree that there's a problem here but I
我同意这里存在问题，但是
think you from studying both of your
想想你从研究你们俩的经历中学到的东西
sort of perspectives you think that this
你认为这种观点是怎样的？
the solution and the cause of the
解决方案和原因
problem is different I mean I put bets
问题不一样，我的意思是，我下了注。
on I put bets on I put bet that's what I
我下了注，我下了注，那就是我
do I put bets on um at the beginning of
我一开始就押注他们吗？
covid we knew the government was going
新冠疫情期间，我们知道政府会采取什么措施
to give enormous amount of money out um
拿出巨额资金
total amount of money now UK government
英国政府目前的总金额
deficit since the beginning of Co is is1
自Co开始以来，赤字为is1
trillion pounds US number is $4
万亿英镑的美元价值为4美元
trillion that's you know 20,000 per UK
万亿，也就是每人 2 万英镑。
adult
成人
my background is I understand that when
我的背景是，我明白当
the distribution gets worse when
当分布情况恶化时
inequality gets worse living standards
不平等加剧，生活水平下降
full so when when the UK government was
所以，当英国政府……的时候，一切都很顺利。
going to give a trillion pounds out all
将会拿出1万亿英镑来支付所有费用
I wanted to know was who's going to end
我想知道的是谁会赢。
up with that money that's all I wanted
把钱都拿走，那正是我想要的。
to know and um I mean the US number 13
要知道，嗯，我是指美国排名第13位。
trillion 14 trillion is just outlandish
万亿，14万亿，简直太离谱了。
but I think the most amazing thing I've
但我认为我做过的最不可思议的事情
ever seen in my whole
我这辈子都没见过这样的景象
life was that at the beginning of Co the
生活就像Co公司成立之初那样。
very beginning of Co we knew governments
在公司成立之初，我们就知道政府
across the world we're going to be
我们将遍布世界各地
giving out tens of trillions of pounds
发放数万亿英镑
dollars
美元
Euros nobody even thought to ask who's
欧元？没人想到要问问是谁的？
going to get tens of trillions richer
将会变得富有数万亿美元
nobody in the conservatives nobody in
保守派中没有人
labor nobody in the Republicans nobody
共和党内没有人是劳工代表
in Democrats nobody in the media nobody
民主党人中没有人，媒体中也没有人
in Academia nobody the central banks
在学术界，没有人关注中央银行。
nobody asked this it's
没人问过这个问题，是
it's it's it's almost beautiful it's
它，它，它几乎美极了。
it's unbelievable it's unbeliev so I I
难以置信，难以置信，所以我……
sat down and I did I did the analysis at
我坐下来，然后进行了分析。
the beginning because lockdown is
封锁开始于
essentially Banning the spending of the
实质上禁止支出
rich
富有的
and replacing that spending of the rich
并用这些钱来取代富人的支出。
with printed money from government what
用政府印制的货币做什么
happens is the government gives workers
事情的经过是政府给工人提供劳动力。
money they use that money to pay their
他们用这些钱来支付他们的
bills to pay their rent pay their
支付房租、支付账单
mortgage it goes to the rich the rich
抵押贷款最终都流向了富人。
can't spend it because they're locked
因为被锁定，所以无法使用。
indoors and what you get is essentially
室内，你得到的基本上是
an enormous amount of money from the
来自……的巨额资金
government to the poor to the rich and
政府对穷人、对富人以及
this massive massive transfer of wealth
这种大规模的财富转移
um that was obviously going that was so
嗯，那显然是那样的。
obviously going to happen at the
显然，这种情况将会发生在……
beginning of Co nobody discussed it
公司成立之初，没人讨论过它。
which I think is itself
我认为这本身就是
amazing let me ask you a question right
太好了，那我问你个问题吧？
if we were now to pause the economy for
如果我们现在暂停经济活动
2 years and during that pause massively
两年，在此期间大规模
increase wealth inequality what do you
财富不平等加剧，你打算怎么做？
think would happen to Broad living
想想布罗德生活会怎么样
conditions when we
当我们处于这种情况时
unpaused see one of the things that I
未暂停的画面显示了我所看到的其中一件事
think happened during the pandemic is
疫情期间发生的事情是
everything went digital and um
一切都数字化了，嗯
entrepreneurs and investors did actually
企业家和投资者确实做到了。
think about what would happen the
想想会发生什么
investors immediately boomed stocks like
投资者立即大量买入此类股票。
zoom and uh Microsoft and we ended up
Zoom 和微软，最后我们……
with the Magnificent 7 um I don't know
至于《七侠荡寇志》，嗯……我不知道。
if you you know there's seven big tech
如果你知道有七大科技巨头，你就会明白。
companies in the USA market and those
美国市场上的公司以及那些
big seven companies have gone from five
七大公司已从五家减少到五家。
trillion valuation to 17 TR trillion
市值达到17万亿美元
valuation uh in the time of the pandemic
疫情期间的估值
and if you think about what did the
如果你想想是什么……
pandemic do uh everyone had to work from
疫情期间，每个人都不得不居家办公。
home so we all had to have Microsoft
家里所以我们都必须有微软
subscriptions everyone went onto website
订阅者们都访问了网站
so we all went to AWS uh Amazon we all
所以我们都去了AWS，也就是亚马逊，我们都
started buying and learning how to buy
开始购买并学习如何购买
from Amazon rather than buying from from
而不是从亚马逊购买
our local high streets every business in
我们当地的商业街上，每家企业
the world figured out how to run their
世界找到了运行他们的方法
business remotely uh we had this massive
远程办公方面，我们遇到了很大的问题。
transformation it wasn't it was like
转变？那不是转变，那就像……
it's actually a wholesale transformation
这实际上是一次彻底的变革。
of society that we all learned how to
我们都学会了如何融入社会
live and work differently um I saw a
生活方式和工作方式都不一样，嗯，我看到了。
boom in entrepreneurship so what I saw
创业蓬勃发展，我看到了什么？
as an entrepreneur accelerator um
作为创业加速器
someone who runs an entrepreneur
经营企业的人
accelerator is just there was this
加速器就在那里。
sudden boom in people launching
创业人数突然激增
businesses uh setting up Shopify
企业正在搭建 Shopify
accounts setting up YouTube uh
设置 YouTube 帐户
businesses so the money really has moved
企业，所以资金确实已经转移了。
from the traditional economy the 2019
从传统经济来看，2019 年
High Street economy over to the digital
从商业街经济转向数字化
economy and what we see is that the
经济，以及我们看到的情况是……
investors know what's going on and they
投资者们都知道发生了什么，而且他们
just invest in This Magnificent Seven
投资《七侠荡寇志》吧！
company I think 50% of the gains of the
我认为该公司50%的收益来自
S&amp;P 500 is tech companies um so all the
标普500指数包含科技公司，所以所有这些
money just goes flooding into the the
资金源源不断地涌入
technology companies my my belief is
我认为科技公司是
that technolog is really dividing people
那项技术真的在分裂人们
that essentially if you take anyone from
基本上，如果你从任何人那里……
any background if they work in
如果他们从事相关工作，任何背景都无关紧要
technology uh if they're in Media Tech
技术方面，呃，如果他们从事媒体技术的话。
Finance any of that stuff that operates
为所有这些运营活动提供资金
online they tend to actually do pretty
在网上，他们往往做得相当不错。
pretty well after the pandemic I ask you
疫情结束后很久，我才问你这个问题。
a question yeah go for do you think the
一个问题，嗯，你觉得呢？
average Brit American Australian whoever
普通的英国人、美国人、澳大利亚人，无论他们是谁
the person out there is watching if they
外面有人在看着他们
quit their job and go work in Tech do
他们辞掉工作，去科技行业工作。
you think they'll be able to get
你认为他们能够得到
Financial Security relatively
财务安全相对而言
easily depends when you defi Define
这很容易取决于你何时定义定义
Financial Security the issue with house
房屋财务安全问题
prices the ability to raise a family
价格决定了养家糊口的能力
have a home yeah so having a home is a
有个家，是的，所以有个家是……
big issue right so here's here's what I
这是个大问题，对吧？所以，这就是我的看法。
here's what I see with houses cuz houses
这就是我看到的房子，因为房子
annoy me as well my dad bought a house
我爸买了房子，这事儿也让我很恼火。
for
为了
$188,000 which is about 10,000 or less
18.8万美元，约合1万英镑或更少。
than 10,000 and it's probably worth
超过 10,000 英镑，而且可能值这个价
over a million dollars um uh today so
今天超过一百万美元了，嗯……
something went wrong and and this by the
出问题了，而且这是由……
way is not UK specific uh the socialist
这种方式并非英国特有的，呃，社会主义者
countries had house prices go through
各国房价经历了波动
the roof if you go to Norway or Sweden
如果你去挪威或瑞典，就会看到屋顶。
their house prices grew by 600% uh in
他们的房价上涨了600%。
then it's happening everywhere it's not
那么，如果这种情况并非到处都在发生，那就说明它到处都在发生。
specific to anywhere it's happening
具体而言，取决于事件发生的地点。
everywhere but but what happened what
到处都是，但发生了什么事？
what has definitely in the UK is we
在英国，真正确定的是……
actually have um a housing traffic jam
实际上，我们遇到了住房方面的交通堵塞问题。
so in this country in the UK we have 9.5
所以，在英国，我们有9.5
million homes that have two or more
百万户家庭拥有两套或两套以上房产
spare bedrooms big family homes have two
大家庭住宅通常有两个备用卧室。
or more spare bedrooms and when you look
或者更多空余卧室，当你查看时
into who owns those houses 78% of
78%的房屋所有者是谁
housing wealth is Baby Boomers um and
住房财富属于婴儿潮一代。
now anecdotally I take my kids
现在，就我个人经验而言，我会带我的孩子们去。
trick-or-treating at uh Halloween and we
万圣节的“不给糖就捣蛋”活动，我们
go down a street that is big family
沿着一条大家庭所在的街道走。
homes and you go knock on the doors and
你挨家挨户去敲门，
it's all people over 65 right and living
都是65岁以上的人，对吧？
in a big family home with empty spare
一栋大家庭住宅，有空余的备用房间
bedrooms we you think the average
卧室，你认为平均
American over 65 is living luxuriously
65岁以上的美国人过着奢华的生活
the average American over 65 so more
65岁以上的美国人平均水平更高
than half of the US economy is in the
超过一半的美国经济都处于……
hands of baby boomers right so they own
婴儿潮一代的双手，所以他们拥有
all the houses the the houses got bought
所有被买下的房子
up cheap baby boomers still own those
便宜的婴儿潮一代仍然拥有那些
houses to this day the big family homes
时至今日，这些大家庭住宅依然存在。
with multiple spare bedrooms are empty
多间空余卧室
um and now that creates this traffic jam
嗯，现在这就造成了交通堵塞。
people my age my grandparents yeah they
我这个年纪的人，我的祖父母，是的，他们
all owned property
所有自有财产
all four of
这四个
them died with
他们一同死去
nothing um because that wealth which
没什么，嗯，因为那笔财富
they had in in property was was used in
他们拥有的房产被用于
equity release schemes they they it was
他们，他们，那是股权释放计划
used in paying through their retirement
用于支付他们的退休费用
it was used in End of Life Care um do
它被用于临终关怀。
you think when those old people die
你觉得那些老人去世的时候会怎么样？
young people today will be rich there is
如今的年轻人将来会很富有。
half the economy held by baby burus it's
一半的经济都掌握在小布鲁斯手中。
either going to be passed down or passed
要么会传承下去，要么会传给别人。
into the age care industry or passed
进入老年护理行业或通过
into the but the issue of why we can't
但问题是，为什么我们不能
get homes two things government
获得住房两件事政府
massively inflated the value of homes
大幅抬高了房屋价值
through debt so they just in injected
他们通过债务注入资金
like low interest rates that you
比如低利率
involved in who who is the debt to well
牵涉其中的人是谁，谁欠了钱
the debt is to anyone who can take out
任何能借钱的人都欠这笔债。
Al loan because if a 0% interest rates
因为如果利率为0%，那么贷款利率将为零。
or 2% interest R you think it's the debt
或者2%的利息，你认为这是债务吗？
is the ordinary families do you think
你觉得普通家庭怎么样？
ordinary families are the creditors when
普通家庭是债权人时
you say ordinary families you mean
你说普通家庭，是指
bottom third so if your average British
底部三分之一，所以如果你是普通的英国人
or American family now has half a
或者，美国家庭现在有一半
million pounds of debt crit it's anyone
数百万英镑的债务，批评者认为任何人都可能面临这种情况。
who could get their at that particular
谁能到达那个特定地点
time anyone who could get their hands on
任何能弄到手的人都会花时间
a loan to buy a house but who has the
贷款买房，但谁有钱？
credit who has who is on the other side
把功劳归于对方的人
of the debt so if the average British
如果普通英国人背负债务的话
family million P banking license does
家庭百万 P 银行牌照
the average British family have half
英国普通家庭平均拥有一半
million pound of credit well a lot of
百万英镑的信贷，嗯，很多
people have got a lot of equity in their
人们在他们的资产中拥有大量股权
home now you think the average British
现在回家了，你觉得普通的英国人
family is sitting on half a million
这家人坐拥五十万美元。
pound cash I'd love to look at the what
英镑现金，我很想看看什么
the actual number is but it's a couple
实际数字是，但这是一对
hundred thousand worth of equity 78 what
价值十万美元的股权 78 什么
about the credit on the line credit on
关于信贷额度
the line owns the credit on the line in
该线路拥有线路上的信用
mind it's disproportionately older
请注意，它的年龄比例过高。
people so
人们如此
think the average British old person is
认为英国老年人的平均水平是
sitting on million millions of pounds of
坐拥数百万英镑
cash not millions of cash no equity well
现金，不是数百万美元现金，没有股权
someone is on the other side of just one
有人就在这一个的另一端。
say the difference the difference is if
比如说，区别在于……
you inflate the value of a house you
你抬高了房屋的价值
don't have cash you have a house that's
你没有现金，但你有一套房子。
worth a lot of money so 78% of home
价值不菲，所以占房屋价值的78%。
ownership wealth is in the hands of
所有权财富掌握在谁手中？
people over 65 now it's baby boomer
现在65岁以上的人，是婴儿潮一代了。
generation and they got a great gift
他们这一代人收到了一份很棒的礼物
from the government which is the
来自政府，也就是
government said we're going to just give
政府说我们只会给予
free loans away if someone previously
如果之前有人获得免费贷款，那就太好了。
could have only afforded to take out a
只能负担得起贷款
200 Grand loan with low interest rates
20万英镑低利率贷款
they can afford a 300 Grand L do you
他们买得起30万英镑的Grand L，你呢？
think it's okay that the average British
认为普通英国人这样做是可以接受的。
or American young person will never own
否则，美国年轻人将永远无法拥有
any wealth the issue is not whether it's
任何财富，问题都不在于它是否……
okay or not the issue is what do you do
不管好不好，关键在于你怎么做。
about it I do you own wealth I've got
关于这件事，我确实拥有你自己的财富。
wealth yeah you own wealth but depends
财富，没错，你拥有财富，但这取决于……
what you call Wealth I do so do we three
你所谓的财富，我称之为财富，我们三个也称之为财富。
multimillionaires do we think it's okay
千万富翁们，我们觉得这样可以吗？
that the average Brit or American young
普通英国或美国年轻人
person will never own any wealth that to
一个人永远不会拥有任何财富。
me that's because I don't think that's
对我来说，那是因为我不认为那是……
okay to me that's not the debate is it
好吧，对我来说，这不是争论的焦点，对吧？
okay it's not well it it's not okay no
好吧，情况不太好，真的不太好，不行。
we want widespread would you rather that
我们希望广泛传播，你更愿意这样吗？
the people who currently are
目前这些人
multi-millionaires would you rather that
千万富翁们，你更愿意……
all of the world was owned by their kids
整个世界都归他们的孩子所有。
I think that the way you see the world
我认为你看待世界的方式
as a Trader is that the world is a zero
作为交易员，我认为世界是零。
sum game and that there's basically the
博弈论，基本上就是这样。
pi is a fixed pi and it gets sliced up
π 是一个固定的 π 值，它会被分割成若干部分。
how fast is the growing now there's
现在增长速度有多快？
something like this what's UK GDP growth
类似这样的问题：英国GDP增长情况如何？
at the moment yeah it's not it's not
目前还不是，还不是
high right 1% how much did your wealth
高位1%的人，你的财富有多少？
grow in the last year uh exponentially
过去一年呈指数级增长
okay so if our weals my wealth probably
好吧，如果我们的财富，我的财富可能
grew about 20% in the last year maybe 30
过去一年增长了约20%，也许30%。
okay okay if our worlds are growing 30%
好吧好吧，如果我们的世界正在增长30%
and the economy is growing at 1% where
经济增长率为1%，
is it coming from if it's not coming
它从哪里来？如果它不是从哪里来？
from our viewers so I'll tell you where
观众们都这么说，所以我来告诉你们在哪里
my wealth comes from my wealth comes
我的财富来源于我的财富
from building technology companies and
从构建技术公司和
the way it works is pretty weird which
它的运作方式相当奇怪，
is that I invent something out of my
就是我用我的发明创造一些东西
head and I go to investors and I say to
我和领导一起去找投资者，我说
the investors here's what we're going to
各位投资者，我们接下来要这样做……
create and I give them a spreadsheet and
创建表格后，我会给他们一个电子表格。
then they say we'll give you a couple
然后他们说我们会给你几个
hundred grand to get started which is
启动资金需要十万美元，这
called seed Capital but on paper makes
名为种子资本，但账面上却……
me worth a couple of million right but
我身价几百万美元，对吧？
there there's nothing has been taken
那里什么都没拿走。
from anyone at this point uh the
此刻，从任何人的角度来看……
investors have said okay we'll invest
投资者们已经表示同意，我们会投资。
some money then as the business succeeds
随着生意成功，就能赚到一些钱。
some more investors come along and they
又有一些投资者加入进来，他们
say we'll give you a little bit more
我们说我们会多给你一点。
money to keep growing it um and I'm
需要资金来继续发展，嗯，我是
innovating something new and let's say
创新，比如说
investors come in and give me a million
投资者们进来，给我一百万美元。
pounds and for 10% of the company and
英镑，以及公司10%的股份。
the rest of the company's worth 9
公司其余部分价值9
million or $9 million right so I'm not
一百万美元还是九百万美元，对吧？所以我不是
stealing something from the existing
从现有物品中偷东西
economy I'm bringing something from
我从经济领域带来了一些东西
outside of the economy into the economy
从经济之外进入经济
um and my quote unquote net worth is
嗯，我的所谓“净资产”是
growing exponentially because investors
呈指数级增长，因为投资者
say we'll give you a little bit of money
比如说，我们会给你一点钱
that values the rest of the pie at a lot
这使得剩余部分的价值大大增加。
of money but there's everyone's getting
虽然钱不多，但每个人都能得到。
richer in the in the wealth create
在创造财富方面更加富有
there's where there's wealth extraction
那里是财富攫取之地。
which is what Traders do they extract
这就是交易员们提取的东西。
from the existing economy um and they
从现有的经济体系来看，嗯，他们
bet on uh the economy and then there's
押注经济，然后还有……
wealth creation which what entrepreneurs
企业家们是如何创造财富的？
do they come up with new ideas better
他们是否能更好地提出新想法
ways of doing things and they build
他们创造做事的方式，并以此为基础进行建设。
wealth so do you think the reason our
所以你认为财富是我们的原因吗？
viewers the average Brit American are
观众，尤其是英国和美国观众，是
getting poorer is because they don't
他们越来越穷是因为他们不……
know how to create wealth no the reason
知道如何创造财富，无需理由
people are getting poorer is because
人们越来越穷的原因是
economic freedoms are being eroded when
经济自由正在受到侵蚀
we have high economic that with taxes
我们拥有高经济实力，税收也很高。
well anything that imp it could be
嗯，任何有那么重要的东西都可能。
anything that impacts economic freedom
任何影响经济自由的因素
so uh taxes and regulations are big was
所以，税收和监管是很大的问题。
economic freedom higher in the 50s uh
20世纪50年代的经济自由度更高。
50s was okay so 50s was a interesting
50年代还不错，所以50年代是个有趣的年代。
time we we were in food Russians in this
当时我们正在吃俄罗斯食物。
country till uh 1956 so we had 10 years
直到1956年，我们这个国家才解散，所以我们有10年的时间。
of food rations after the war um we had
战后食品配给方面，嗯，我们有
a labor shortage uh because only really
劳动力短缺，呃，因为实际上只有……
men worked women hadn't entered the
男人们工作，女人们还没有进入这个行业。
workforce in Mass um there had been
马萨诸塞州的劳动力，嗯，曾经有过
three or 400,000 men killed in war so we
战争中丧生了三四十万人，所以我们
actually had this big labor shortage the
实际上，当时存在严重的劳动力短缺问题。
whole country needed to rebuild because
整个国家都需要重建，因为
of the blitz had bombed it so we had
闪电战的轰炸摧毁了它，所以我们……
this huge need for economic activity and
对经济活动的巨大需求
not enough people to do it we only had
人手不够，我们只有
2% unemployment people who had had their
2%的失业率是指那些曾经失业的人
blown off were put to work at that
被吹走的人都投入到那项工作中。
particular time so we had this boom this
特定时期，所以我们经历了这次繁荣。
postwar boom and we also had the postwar
战后繁荣，我们也经历了战后经济衰退。
baby boom which drove consumption uh and
婴儿潮推动了消费。
then when we got to the 60s we had the
然后到了60年代，我们有了
Roaring 60s or the um The Swinging 60s
咆哮的六十年代，或者更确切地说，摇摆的六十年代
right pretty amazing time in Britain and
在英国的这段时间真是太棒了。
Along Comes high taxes uh and they put
高税收随之而来，他们……
up the taxes massively at the end of the
在年底大幅提高税收
60s um and it pretty much crashed the
60年代，嗯，它几乎崩溃了。
economy one of the things that happened
经济是其中一件发生的事情。
so what were the tax rates in the 50s
那么，50年代的税率是多少？
well they went up as high as 80 to 90%
它们最高涨到了80%到90%。
uh for the top for the top ear I think
嗯，顶部，也就是上耳部分，我想是这样的。
it was in the 60s you sure about that I
那是在六十年代，你确定吗？
think the 50s are unique what is the
认为50年代是独一无二的，那是什么？
answer feel like you they went up off
回答感觉就像他们升空了
the wall they went up after the war well
战后他们建起的那堵墙
in the US actually tax rates started got
在美国，税率实际上开始下降
before the war but also the size of
战前，以及战后规模
government as a percentage of GDP was
政府支出占GDP的比例为
like 30% it was a tiny like we're we're
大概30%吧，就像我们一样，微不足道。
now 45% of the UK economy is government
现在英国经济的45%是政府部门。
spending we have got a mass who funds
我们有一大批资金来源。
that spending debt they the bank of
他们偿还银行债务
England allows them to print endless
英国允许他们无限量印刷。
amounts of debt which deflates Gary I
债务数额令加里·I 感到沮丧
want to get your opinion here cuz you're
想听听你的意见，因为你
asking a lot of questions but I actually
问了很多问题，但我实际上
don't know your opinion I just want to
我不知道你的看法，我只是想……
know what Daniel thinks and I want our
我知道丹尼尔的想法，而且我想要我们的
viewers to be able to research Daniel's
观众可以研究丹尼尔的
opinions but how how do you disagree
意见，但你如何才能不同意
with those opinions listen Daniel's a
听听丹尼尔的观点
businessman he's obviously a very
他显然是一位非常成功的商人。
successful businessman you know I I've
你知道，我是一位成功的商人。
not been any I'm not a businessman I'm
我不是商人，我不是商人
not going to pretend to be a businessman
我不会假装自己是商人。
I'm an economist I make money by being
我是一名经济学家，我靠……赚钱。
right on the economy Daniel's a good
丹尼尔对经济形势的看法很正确，他是个好人。
businessman and I'm right on the economy
商人，我对经济形势非常了解。
you know it's a simple as that basically
你知道，事情基本上就是这么简单。
you know I'm not a good businessman but
你知道我不是个好商人，但是
I've got 15 years of being right on this
我在这方面已经坚持了15年了。
on the economy and look and I know
关于经济，你看，我知道
you're probably a wealthy man you
你可能是一位富有的人。
probably don't want to pay high taxes
可能不想缴纳高额税款
you probably don't want your kids to pay
你可能不想让你的孩子付钱。
high taxes but we exist in an economy
高税收，但我们生活在一个经济体系中
where wealth is being extracted out of
财富是从哪里被榨取的
the middle class out of the working
中产阶级脱离了劳动阶层
class very very rapidly it's benefiting
班级发展非常迅速，受益匪浅
people like the three of us at this
像我们三个这样的人
table it will benefit our kids you know
你知道，这张桌子会让我们的孩子受益。
our kids will be rich their kids will be
我们的孩子会很富有，他们的孩子也会很富有。
poor and I just think we should be
贫穷，我只是觉得我们应该……
honest with them capitalism's finished
坦白说，资本主义已经结束了。
we won well done Stephen well done
我们赢了，干得好，斯蒂芬，干得好！
Daniel well done Gary it's over now our
丹尼尔，干得好，加里，结束了，我们的
kids will be rich their kids will be
孩子们会很富有，他们的孩子也会很富有。
poor they'll pay the tax taxes we won't
穷人要交税，我们不用交税。
pay the taxes we'll avoid it I'll make
交税我们就能避免，我会做的
money betting on it year after year why
为什么每年都有钱押注它？
are we lying to them why are we lying to
我们是不是在对他们撒谎？我们为什么要对他们撒谎？
them yeah I I think that's an overly
是的，我觉得那太过分了。
simplified view of things I don't an
我对事物的简化看法
overly simplified view of things that
对事物过于简单化的看法
has made me a multimillionaire yeah well
让我成了千万富翁，是啊。
look entrepreneurs take bets on the
看看企业家们是如何下注的
economy as well we take bets differently
经济方面，我们也采取不同的投注方式。
um when we start a company we're betting
嗯，当我们创办公司时，我们就是在打赌。
on how the econ the average British and
关于英国普通民众的经济状况以及
American worker at the 50th percentile
美国工人处于第50百分位
do you think their kids will be richer
你认为他们的孩子会更富有吗？
than they are it depends if we have
这取决于我们是否拥有
economic freedom or not right we're
经济自由与否，我们是对的
going to have a split test on this right
准备做个A/B测试，对吧？
we're going to have a split test we're
我们将进行A/B测试。
going to have the UK seems like we're
看来我们即将拥有英国
going to have more taxes more
税收将会增加
regulations and it seems like the us is
法规，而且看起来美国是
going to have less taxes and less
税收会减少，而且会减少
regulations here's what I've noticed
以下是我注意到的一些规定
I've noticed that places like Singapore
我注意到像新加坡这样的地方
that have small governments um have got
那些政府规模较小的国家……有
widespread affluence there's not a lot
普遍富裕的情况并不多。
of poverty in Singapore yeah except for
新加坡的贫困问题确实存在，除了……
the cleaners living in the closets yeah
住在壁橱里的清洁工，是的。
you know uh look but we don't count them
你知道，呃，你看，但我们不把它们算进去。
in the statistics just like we don't
就像我们在统计数据中看不到的那样，我们没有。
count our viewers that that's not
统计一下我们的观众人数，那可不是这样。
widespread in well there's a lot of
普遍存在，有很多
people W I've seen them in the closets
我见过那些躲在壁橱里的人
I've seen them in the closets there are
我曾在壁橱里见过它们。
there are some but they're not
有一些，但它们并不
singaporeans well also you only count
新加坡人也一样，你只算
the rich ones look the the also the
有钱人看起来也……
issue is is that they've come from even
问题在于，他们来自……
worse conditions in many cases people
在许多情况下，人们的处境更糟。
mve to Singapore for an increase in
前往新加坡以增加
lifestyle right the um you could take
生活方式，嗯，你可以采取
Ireland or Switzerland right
爱尔兰或瑞士
economically free places Ireland was
经济自由的地区，爱尔兰曾是……
economically in a disaster in think the
经济上，一场灾难正在发生，想想看。
average Irish person lives well well the
普通爱尔兰人的生活相当不错。
their
他们的
economy their economy almost collapsed
他们的经济几乎崩溃了。
in 2011 and they went down the road of
2011年，他们走上了这条路
lower taxes lower regulations and they
降低税收，减少监管，它们
attracted all sorts of businesses into
吸引了各种各样的企业
the economy and do you think that works
经济形势如何？你认为这有效吗？
well for the average Irishman who
对于普通的爱尔兰人来说，
doesn't own a home in Dublin the the if
如果在都柏林没有房产，
you measure everything by Home Ownership
你用房屋所有权来衡量一切
I'm measuring people by the average I
我用平均值来衡量人们。
want to know what the average man or
想知道普通男人或
woman today lives that by the way I I'm
如今的女性过着这样的生活，顺便说一句，我是
also Furious about the home ownership
也对房屋所有权感到愤怒
thing everyone is um I think it's
大家都在讨论的，嗯，我觉得是这样的。
utterly ridiculous the way like the idea
这个想法简直荒谬至极。
that homes are now worth 10 times the
现在房屋的价值是以前的10倍
average wage all of that difference is I
平均工资所有这些差异都是我
blame government for that uh I blame
都怪政府，我怪他们
high taxes where they've because of high
高税收是因为高
taxes they can take out more debt they
他们可以用税收来承担更多债务
can then inflate the economy do you
然后就能刺激经济增长，你觉得呢？
think if we shrink the government if we
想想如果我们缩小政府规模，如果我们
start to slash government spending do
开始大幅削减政府开支
you think that would improve living
你认为这会改善生活质量吗？
conditions well the UK government is 45%
条件良好，英国政府占45%。
of the economy like that's a huge
像这样的经济状况是巨大的
government it's think using additions
政府认为应该使用附加项
will increase in the next few years
未来几年将会增长
because we have US Government now that's
因为我们现在有了美国政府。
planning to slash the US government well
计划大幅削减美国政府预算
that's what the US voters have asked for
这就是美国选民的要求。
do you think it would improve living
你认为这会改善生活吗？
conditions uh do I think it'll improve
情况嘛，我觉得会好转吗？
the average American if they're smaller
如果他们个头较小，那么平均而言，美国人的个头会更小。
government yeah I trust market so you
政府？是的，我相信市场，所以你
think the average US American will be
认为普通美国人会是
rich in years than the here what I trust
比我信任的这里更有年华
I trust economic freedom if people have
我相信经济自由，如果人们拥有……
freedom they create better decisions for
自由让他们能够做出更好的决定
their own life there's two ways to make
他们自己的生活有两种实现方式。
decisions right there's two ways you
现在做决定有两种方法：
have freedom I got less freedom than I
我拥有的自由比我拥有的要少。
did when I ared just because my sister
当我睡觉的时候，我做了这件事，只是因为我姐姐
can't pay the rent is that freedom the
付不起房租就是自由吗？
if you're living in a country she can't
如果你住在她无法居住的国家
to live in the city that she was born in
居住在她出生的城市
I I agree you and I agree on the problem
我同意你的观点，我也同意这个问题。
you keep bringing back to the problem I
你总是把这个问题带回到我身上。
keep bringing it back to people because
不断地把它带回给人们，因为
the people who watch We're millionaires
观看《我们是百万富翁》的人们
okay the people who watch us are mostly
好吧，观看我们节目的观众大多是
not
不是
millionaires is life going to get better
百万富翁的生活会越来越好吗？
for them they life will get better if
对他们来说，如果……他们的生活将会变得更好
you are connected to the most productive
你与最有生产力的人联系在一起。
parts of the economy um if you pretend
经济的某些部分，嗯，如果你假装的话。
that it's 1955 and you recreate the
现在是1955年，你重现了……
postwar era conditions if you try to go
战后时代的条件，如果你试图去
back to 1955 I don't think that's going
回到1955年？我觉得不太可能。
to work so so let me ask on that then
为了工作，那我就问一下吧。
the point about if you're connected to
关于你是否连接到
the most productive parts of the economy
经济中最具生产力的部分
I was quite um quite surprised when I
我当时相当……相当惊讶。
was doing some research on this to find
我正在做这方面的研究以查找
that there's quite big differences
两者之间存在相当大的差异。
between the UK and the US in terms of
英国和美国之间在以下方面
GDP growth in Q4 2024 the US economy
2024年第四季度美国经济GDP增长
grew by 6% while the UK growth was 0.1%
增长了6%，而英国的增长率为0.1%。
so they're doing significantly better in
所以他们在以下方面做得明显更好：
that regard US GDP per head stands at
就美国人均GDP而言，目前为
$82,000 per head whereas the UK stands
每人82,000美元，而英国则为
at $49,000 per head and stock market
每人 49,000 美元，以及股票市场
performance which is an indication of I
表现表明我
guess what ever Rose by 300% in the US
你猜怎么着？美国上涨了300%。
whereas the footsy 100 declined by 20%
而 Footsy 100 指数下降了 20%。
Which is the UK stock market
那就是英国股市
productivity growth since 2018
自2018年以来的生产率增长
productivity increased by 30% in the
生产率提高了30%
United States which has outpaced the the
美国已经超越了……
UK and lastly income growth since 2007
英国，以及自2007年以来的收入增长情况。
American income per head has increased
美国人均收入有所增长
by 72% while it has decreased in by 2%
增长了72%，而下降了2%。
in the UK in dollar terms so they seem
以美元计价，在英国似乎
to be doing better from if you just look
如果你只是观察，就会发现情况会好转。
at the economy um why is that is that
经济方面，嗯，为什么会这样呢？
because they lean more into technology
因为他们更倾向于科技
and Innovation and Entrepreneurship and
以及创新和创业精神
is it because of the things you were
是因为你所经历的那些事吗？
saying earlier about their attitude
之前谈到他们的态度
towards the Govern like reduced
朝着治理方向发展，就像减少
government spending versus tax the rich
政府支出与对富人征税
why I'm Keen to hear Gary's view on this
我之所以很想听听加里对此的看法，是因为……
because I understand yours because
因为我理解你的感受，因为
you've just said it yeah I think these
你刚才也说了，是的，我认为这些
are great statistics um and of course
这些都是很棒的统计数据，当然
the US has a strong reput reputation for
美国拥有良好的声誉
being very free markets and being very
非常自由的市场，而且非常
small states in the last 5 years 10
过去5年中，小州数量为10个
years 15 years
15年
we've had a UK government that has been
我们一直以来都拥有一个这样的英国政府。
aggressively slashing the state and the
大幅削减国家开支和
US State's bigger than ever it's 45% of
美国州比以往任何时候都更大，占45%
the economy and the us we had a
经济和我们曾经拥有的
government in the last four years which
过去四年来的政府
has been running a massive massive
一直在运行一个庞大的庞大
deficit so in that period of
因此，在那段时期存在赤字
time it appears the government which has
时间似乎表明，政府已经……
been aggressively increasing its deficit
一直在积极增加其赤字
has massively overperformed the
表现远超预期
government which has been aggressively
政府一直积极
slashing the
大幅削减
state that's what it looks to be from
看起来就是这样。
the last I mean b Joe Biden in
最后我指的是乔·拜登
enormously increased the deficit
赤字大幅增加
enormously and the conservatives were
保守派人士对此反应强烈。
austerity government for 14 years which
长达14年的紧缩政府
one seems to have given the better
其中一人似乎表现更好。
numbers well I mean there were austerity
数字方面，我的意思是，当时存在紧缩政策。
in name only they went from 30% uh the
名义上，他们从30%……
state was 30% of GDP to 45% of
州占GDP的30%至45%
government services haveed now they're
政府服务现在它们是
the government is terrible at doing most
政府在大多数方面都做得非常糟糕。
things that's the problem you you you
这就是问题所在，你，你，你
don't want you don't think that spending
不想让你觉得花钱
on government service has been slashed
政府部门的职位已被大幅削减
let me let me zoom out a little you
让我稍微拉远镜头，你
think the police spending has been
我认为警务支出已经……
slashed OH police spending is definitely
俄亥俄州大幅削减警务开支绝对是
do you know where it ends up it ends up
你知道它最终会去哪里吗？它最终会去哪里？
with like big corporates uh big
就像大型企业，呃，大
Consulting who get paid $50 million to
咨询公司每年获得 5000 万美元的报酬
produce a report to tell government some
撰写一份报告，向政府汇报一些情况
thing right all of these big I won't
所有这些大事，我不会做。
name names but all the big consulting
点名道姓，但所有的大型咨询公司
firms they're all blood suckers to
这些公司都是吸血鬼。
government they they know that the money
政府他们知道这笔钱
is in the government and they set up
身处政府之中，他们设立了
business models to extract that money
利用商业模式来榨取这些资金
from government uh and it also is in the
来自政府，而且它也在……
financial trading side of things the one
金融交易方面的事情是……
of the issues that we've got right and
我们已经做对的问题以及
this is a big big issue as well cuz you
这也是个大问题，因为你
care about wealth inequality one of the
关心财富不平等是其中之一
biggest issues I see is that during the
我看到的最大问题是，在
pandemic we all learned to work remotely
疫情期间，我们都学会了远程办公。
and remotor became the norm and what I
电机逐渐成为常态，而我
see at the moment is huge amounts of
目前看到的是大量的
what would have been normal British jobs
原本应该是英国普通的工作
are going to the Philippines going to
即将前往菲律宾
India going to uh Vietnam people who
印度人要去越南，呃，那些人
work remotely now we now have a thousand
现在我们可以远程办公了，我们现在有1000人
millionaires a month leaving to go to
每月有百万富翁离开去
Dubai we have 120,000 British people
迪拜有12万英国人
living in Dubai uh in in that economy
住在迪拜，嗯，在那种经济环境下。
the world's become incredibly mobile and
世界已经变得极其流动，
one of the things that's happening is
其中一件正在发生的事情是：
that what would have previously been
那是以前会发生的事情
good British jobs uh are getting moved
英国的好工作正在流失。
overseas to lower cost countries and
前往海外低成本国家
that's technology that drives that wedge
正是这项技术加剧了这种分化。
the US is very smart in that they've
美国非常聪明，因为他们……
built a technology Powerhouse and the UK
打造了一个科技强国和英国
has completely lost our technology
完全失去了我们的技术
industry our tech industry is in Decline
我们的科技行业正在衰落。
same same across Europe China and the us
欧洲、中国和美国的情况都一样。
know that the game is Tech and they've
知道游戏是科技类的，而且他们已经
basically pulling all the tech company
基本上把所有科技公司都拉走了
into the into their uh borders and
进入他们的边界，
what's happening a lot is the erosion of
目前经常发生的是侵蚀现象
good jobs and the erosion of of just
好工作和公平竞争的侵蚀
normal well-paying uh jobs because they
因为他们是收入不错的普通工作。
they're going and it's a bit of a
他们要走了，这有点……
self-fulfilling Loop that the more we
自我实现的循环，即我们越是……
lose millionaires the tax burden falls
百万富翁减少，税负下降
on everyone else so they put the taxes
所以他们把税收转嫁给了其他人。
up and then the millionaires say oh the
起来，然后百万富翁们说，哦，
taxes are too high so they leave um I've
税收太高，所以他们就离开了……嗯，我已经……
watched some of the most incredible
观看了一些最不可思议的
entrepreneurs that you would want here
你想在这里看到的创业者
that would employ your sister at a high
那将使你妹妹获得一份高薪工作。
rate um and they've picked up and left
给他们打分，然后他们就收拾东西离开了。
cuz the taxes are too high so you saying
因为税收太高了，所以你是这么说的
we should tax working people less well
我们应该减少对劳动人民的征税。
the the the overall government has to be
整个政府必须是
smaller uh you can't whoever what do you
更小的呃，你不能不管你做什么
want to cut in the government if you uh
想削减政府开支的话，呃
yeah I mean you'd have to Child Services
是的，我的意思是，你得联系儿童服务机构。
we'd have to no police no education NHS
我们将没有警察，没有教育，也没有国民医疗服务体系（NHS）。
all I know is this pensions you go to
我只知道这就是你要去的养老金
Switzerland they SP single mothers 25%
瑞士单身母亲占25%
disabled benefits what do you want to
残疾福利，你想要什么？
cut hold up all I know is in Switzerland
等等，我只知道我在瑞士
I tell you what I want the government is
我告诉你我想要的政府是什么样的
TA on those entrepreneurs and raise the
TA 关注这些企业家并提高
taxes on the billionaires because I
对亿万富翁征税，因为我
worked my tits off how many billionaires
我拼了命地工作，结果有多少亿万富翁？
are in the UK there's a lot of
在英国有很多
billionaires in the UK 150 yeah so tax
英国的亿万富翁有150个，所以税收……
them more what do they pay listen I went
他们更愿意付出什么，听着，我去了
my tits off and I paid it was 50% top
我脱了胸罩，付了钱，打了五折。
rate tax 50% top rate tax plus National
税率为最高税率的50%，外加国家税
Insurance 60% million to bring my family
保险赔付6000万美元，让我的家人过上好日子
out of poverty at the same time the Duke
摆脱贫困的同时，公爵
of Westminster inherited 10 billion and
威斯敏斯特继承了100亿英镑，
paid nothing do you think that's fair
你觉得没付一分钱公平吗？
that's not true okay why is it not true
那不是真的，好吧，为什么不是真的？
because the Duke of Westminster is one
因为威斯敏斯特公爵是其中之一
of the highest tax payers in the country
全国纳税最多的群体
what does he pay well on the trust the
他在信托基金上支付的收益是多少？
groer estate uh they don't pay
格罗尔庄园，呃，他们不付钱。
inheritance tax because trusts can't die
因为信托不会消亡，所以要征收遗产税。
they pay something called periodic taxes
他们缴纳一种叫做定期税的税款。
which how much 6% every 10 years 6% so
每十年增长6%，也就是多少？
they pay 0.6% so I paid 16% and this guy
他们付0.6%，所以我付了16%，还有这个人
pays 0.6% apples with apples inheritance
支付0.6%的苹果与苹果继承
tax is 40% across the course of your
整个过程中税率为 40%。
life if a trust is uh if a person lives
如果信托存在，那么如果一个人活着
who owns a trust for 70 years then 6%
持有信托70年的人，收益率为6%。
time 7 would be 42 so they actually pay
乘以 7 就是 42，所以他们实际上付钱了。
more so he pays 0.6% a year Pro 0.6%
因此他每年支付 0.6% 的费用。
that would be the same as what percent
那相当于多少百分比？
did I pay per no no no but that's 60% so
我付钱了吗？不不不，但那是60%呢。
you're saying I pay what 60 of a 0.6
你的意思是，我付了0.6的60块钱？
what 100 times the tax not comparing
税收是原来的100倍，这根本算不上比较。
apples with apples wait why is it not
苹果配苹果，等等，为什么不呢？
apples with apples this guy pays 0.6% a
同等条件下，这家伙支付的利率是0.6%。
year I paid 60% a year that's
我一年付了60%，那是
inheritance tax I paid that 60% every
我每年都缴纳遗产税，税率高达60%。
year Daniel every year I paid you're pay
丹尼尔，每年我都付你工资
income tax so why have I du P more than
所得税，所以为什么我缴纳的税款比P多？
the Duke of Westminster pays income tax
威斯敏斯特公爵缴纳所得税
he probably he probably makes your bill
他很可能……他很可能负责你的账单。
blush yeah think can pay his income tax
脸红了，嗯，我想我能交得起他的所得税。
yeah well if he's going to live he has
是啊，如果他想活下去，他就得……
to withdraw money to have his income he
他要取款才能维持收入
also let me give you a list of all the
另外，让我给你列一份所有清单……
taxes he would pay he'd pay income tax
他将缴纳税款，他将缴纳所得税。
corporate tax he'd pay stamp Duty when
他缴纳公司税时需要缴纳印花税
he buys a building he pays uh uh any of
他买了一栋楼，他付了……呃……任何……
the other taxes vat when he spends money
他花钱时还要缴纳其他税费，比如增值税。
all the same taxes apply to a duuk as
所有相同的税费都适用于 duuk as
they apply to anybody else so you think
它们也适用于其他人，所以你觉得
he pays income tax on on the income on
他需就其收入缴纳所得税。
that any income he draws okay well our
他获得的任何收入都还可以，好吧，我们的
viewers can research whether he pays
观众可以自行调查他是否支付报酬。
income tax on his income because I don't
因为我不知道，所以他收入的所得税需要缴纳。
think he does
他认为他确实
it's in a trust but the only difference
它放在信托里，但唯一的区别
with the trust versus income is that the
信任与收入之间的关系在于……
trust pays periodic tax versus
信托定期缴纳税款
inheritance tax 0.6% but we're only
遗产税为0.6%，但我们只有
talking inherit that that's just one
谈论继承，那只是其中之一
type of tax you think he's paying 60% on
你认为他缴纳的税种是哪种，税率为60%？
his income he's one of the highest
他的收入位居前列。
taxpayers in the UK I'm not like his big
英国的纳税人，我跟他不一样，他可不是那种大人物。
fan club but the truth is he's one of
他是粉丝俱乐部成员，但事实是他也是其中之一。
the highest taxpayers in the UK um he's
英国最大的纳税人，嗯，他是……
one of the biggest Employers in the UK
英国最大的雇主之一
he's one of the like one of the biggest
他是其中最顶尖的人物之一。
land owners in the UK land owners in the
英国的土地所有者
UK right uh so uh the the issue is is
英国对吧，呃，所以，呃，问题是……
does he pay tax all the same taxes that
他是否缴纳所有相同的税种？
apply to you apply to him uh and if you
申请给你，申请给他，呃，如果你
want to set up a trust you can also pay
想设立信托也可以付款
periodic taxes as well um which would be
定期税收，嗯，也就是……
on top of all the other taxes so what
除了其他所有税费之外，那又怎样？
would you say but it's just not true
你会这么说，但这根本不是真的。
that he doesn't pay tax no what would
他不缴税，那会怎么样？
you say this guy has inherit 1010
你说这家伙继承了1010
million P so he's worth 10 billion PS
他身价百万，所以他价值100亿PS。
what would you say will be the total
您认为总金额会是多少？
amount of tax he will pay in his
他将缴纳的税款金额
lifetime well I know that just the
一生，我知道，仅仅是
smallest if I make 10 million I pay 60%
最小的结果是，如果我赚了1000万，我支付60%。
just one sec you're not you're talking
等一下，你不是在说话
about income versus the transfer of an
关于收入与转移
estate so why why is it that the be 10
房产，所以为什么是10
million P just you're comparing your
百万P，你只是在和你比较而已
income yeah versus the amount he
收入，是的，与他的金额相比。
inherited which is not a fair thing
继承，这不公平。
that's not income that's his income he
那不是收入，那是他个人的收入。
inheritance is not income so wait wait
继承的财产不是收入，所以等等
wait wait wait wa so if I get given1
等等等等，所以如果我得到1
billion I don't pay any tax but if I
十亿 我不交任何税，但如果我
work for10 billion I pay 60% well if you
为100亿工作，我支付60%的薪水，如果你……
inherit this is the tax system that you
继承的就是你继承的税收制度。
want you'll end up in a system where the
你想让你最终进入一个怎样的系统？
kids of the richual own everything
富家子弟拥有一切
that's what I'm saying that's what I'm
我就是这个意思，我就是这个意思。
saying and that's fun because that's our
这么说很有趣，因为那是我们的
kids you're not telling the truth about
孩子们，你们没有说实话
his let's support it let's have a tax
让我们支持它，让我们征税。
system where your kids and my kids and
系统里有你的孩子和我的孩子
Steven's kids are multimillionaires and
史蒂文的孩子们都是千万富翁，
these guys out there can't afford to
这些人负担不起
feed their kids and put the heat in
养活孩子，然后开暖气
that's not what I'm saying but that's
我不是那个意思，但那就是……
what you will get that is what you will
你将得到的就是你所拥有的。
get that's listen that's what I'm
明白了，听着，这就是我的意思。
betting on that's fine because I'll make
赌这个没问题，因为我会赢
money in the markets it's fine and
市场上的资金没问题，
you'll make money and you'll make money
你会赚钱，你会赚钱
it's our viewers who will be poor and
真正贫穷的是我们的观众，而且
that's fine that's fine that's fine for
那很好，那很好，那很好
us let's let's explore the other
我们一起去探索其他领域吧。
alternative right so let's say tax the
另一种选择，比如说征税
rich right so let's play the game of tax
富人，对吧？那就来玩税收游戏吧。
the rich tax the owners not the workers
富人向企业主征税，而不是向工人征税。
the owners
业主
so the issue that we have with the rich
所以，我们与富人之间的问题在于
is that is the number one most valuable
这是最有价值的第一要素。
Assets in the economy now in tangible
经济中的有形资产
assets so there's this chart called the
资产，所以有这样一个图表叫做
S&amp;P 500 of the 500 richest countries in
标准普尔500指数涵盖了全球最富裕的500个国家。
the country uh in the world in the US
世界上这个国家，美国
sorry um in
抱歉，嗯……
1970s 75% of the value of the S&amp;P 500
1970年代标普500指数市值的75%
was physical assets like property um and
是像房产之类的有形资产吗？
today it's less than 10% uh it's closer
今天不到10%，嗯，更接近了。
to 5% you think that housing is not
5%的人认为住房不是
particularly important just just let's
尤其重要的是，我们……
stick stick with what I'm saying okay
坚持我说的，好吗？
the the the PowerHouse the engine room
动力房
of the economy is digital assets and
经济的组成部分是数字资产，
that's reflected in uh the S&amp;P 500 for
这一点反映在标普500指数中。
example which is 95% intangible assets
例如，其中95%是无形资产。
one of the issues that we have is that
我们面临的问题之一是：
the richest people are completely mobile
最富有的人完全可以自由行动。
now so they can be absolutely anywhere
现在他们可以出现在任何地方
in the world so if you come up with this
在这个世界上，如果你能想出这个主意……
idea of let's tax richest people 1% if a
如果……的话，我们不妨考虑对最富有的1%的人征税。
tiny proportion of them leave we're all
离开的人寥寥无几，我们都是其中之一。
in trouble so this really rich guys
遇到麻烦了，所以这些真的很有钱的人
M what do they own companies and why are
M公司拥有哪些企业？为什么？
those companies worth money because
这些公司之所以值钱，是因为……
investors say they are and where do the
投资者们说他们是，那他们在哪里？
revenues come from globally okay the
收入来自全球范围内的……
issue is is that these companies operate
问题在于这些公司是如何运营的。
globally now so take my company for
现在全球范围内都是如此，所以请考虑我的公司。
example my company has 8,000 customers
例如，我的公司有8000名客户。
in 150 countries okay we could be
在150个国家，我们可能……
anywhere if you P what country is your
如果你在任何地方 P 你的国家是哪里
biggest single Revenue Source probably
最大的单一收入来源可能是
the US now let's say you move to Cayman
假设你现在从美国搬到开曼群岛
Island and the US says we're going to
岛屿和美国方面表示我们将要
tax your Revenue at point of sale M what
在销售点对您的收入征税 M 什么
can you do well that's different right
你能做得很好吗？那不一样，对吧？
because that's not taxing billionaires
因为那样就不是在对亿万富翁征税。
that's taxing
那很费力。
companies see when you say tax the rich
企业看到你喊“向富人征税”时的反应。
on their wealth yeah that's different to
就他们的财富而言，是的，那不一样。
saying tax companies a consumption tax
向企业征收消费税
oh but you just said the're Rich owned
哦，但你刚才说它们是富人拥有的。
companies you said that's what they own
你说那些公司拥有
yeah but you're saying how do you tax
是啊，但你又在问该如何征税了。
them right so do they do you tax their
对他们来说，所以他们也这么做，你对他们征税吗？
wealth which is what they own or do you
他们拥有的财富，或者你认为的财富，是指他们所拥有的东西吗？
tax the companies where they trade um
对那些在当地进行交易的公司征税
typically consumption taxes get passed
通常情况下，消费税会得到通过。
on to Consumers it's not consumption tax
对消费者而言，这不是消费税。
it's the tax on the ownership yeah but
是的，这是对所有权征收的税，但是
if you simply say when you're doing
如果你只是简单地说你在做什么的话。
revenues then that's a consumption we
那么，收入就是我们的消费。
start to tax if we start to taxit by the
如果我们开始乘坐出租车，就要开始征税了。
way I'm not exactly against you on on
我并不是完全反对你。
companies I think it's disgusting that a
我认为这些公司令人作呕。
British company can can take out a
英国公司可以采取
Facebook ad to sell to a British
Facebook广告，向英国人推销
consumer a British product and Facebook
消费者购买英国产品和Facebook
pretends to be in Ireland on that
假装自己在那一天身在爱尔兰
transaction um and Amazon you can buy
交易嗯，亚马逊你可以买
something on Amazon in Britain from a
英国亚马逊上的某件商品
British supplier from a British
来自英国的英国供应商
warehouse and Amazon pretends to be in
仓库里，亚马逊假装在那里
Luxembourg in that situation and that
卢森堡在这种情况下以及
sucks right like that that does not seem
真糟糕，就是这样，似乎不是。
fair and it strikes me as very strange
公平地说，这让我觉得非常奇怪。
that the government is okay with that
政府对此表示同意。
right now the government is chasing down
现在政府正在追捕
moms and dads who sell a few things on
在网上卖一些东西的爸爸妈妈们
eBay uh and chasing them for taxes but
eBay，呃，还有追讨税款，但是
they don't talk to eBay uh they they
他们不跟eBay沟通，呃，他们
they're paranoid about someone doing a
他们很担心有人会做某事
little bit of a side hustle on Facebook
在Facebook上做点副业
but Facebook's fine to pretend to be an
但Facebook却可以假装成……
Ireland so I don't agree with all of all
爱尔兰，所以我并不完全同意所有观点。
of that right like I think where missing
就像我觉得缺失的那部分一样。
some serious tricks here but the idea
这里面有些高明的技巧，但这个想法
with taxing billionaires at wealth
对亿万富翁的财富征税
billionaires will just leave they just
亿万富翁们只会离开，他们只会
get up and leave and and not just
起身离开，而且不仅仅是
billionaires but what the billionaires
亿万富翁，但亿万富翁们究竟是怎样的呢？
own what the billionaires own companies
拥有亿万富翁拥有的公司
and where do companies get their money
公司从哪里获得资金？
from revenues and where do the revenues
收入来源以及收入去向
come from purchasing people purchasing
源自购买者
where do those people live all over the
这些人都住在哪些地方？
world we can tax them at that point
世界，到那时我们就可以对他们征税了。
that's consumption tax this is the thing
这就是消费税。
that's a consumption tax no it's not
那是消费税，不，不是。
it's V is a tax on Revenue tax these
它的V是对收入税的征税
guys on profits based on where the
那些靠利润赚钱的人，他们的利润取决于……
revenues come from so it's very easy to
收入来源如此，所以很容易……
move profits internationally see Steven
将利润转移到国际市场，参见史蒂文
had a uh Starbucks cup when he buys that
他买的时候手里拿着一个星巴克杯子。
Starbucks yeah it's bought from a
星巴克，是的，是从……买的
British company who licenses the
授权的英国公司
Starbucks logo from Luxembourg or
来自卢森堡的星巴克标志
somewhere like that so 15% so here we
大概是那个程度，所以是15%，所以这里我们
are saying oh we're going to tax their
他们说，哦，我们要对他们征税。
profits they say ah I wish we were
他们说利润丰厚，啊，我希望我们也能如此。
profitable sorry unfortunately we had to
盈利能力 抱歉，很遗憾我们不得不
do that licensing deal with that
和那边达成许可协议
International I know how profit shifting
国际上，我知道如何转移利润。
works okay so are you you think are you
没问题，所以你觉得呢？
telling
讲述
me compan selling to the UK the US
我公司向英国和美国销售产品
enormous amount of of profit in the US
美国巨额利润
and they turn around and say actually
然后他们转过身来说，实际上
our profit is not in the US the
我们的利润不在美国。
difference you think the US is in is is
你认为美国所处的不同之处在于……
incapable of going and looking if that's
如果那是……的话，我没能力去查看。
seeing where they really where the
看看他们到底在哪里
profit is I'm not saying that you can't
利润就是……我不是说你不能……
do this I'm saying that the benefits of
这样做的好处是……
doing it it's so hard to tax wealth for
这样做很难对财富征税。
example or it's so hard to tax uh
例如，或者说征税太难了。
Millionaires and billionaires that that
那些百万富翁和亿万富翁
you end up cutting off your nose despite
尽管如此，你最终还是割掉了自己的鼻子。
your face um for every like if we
你的脸，嗯，每次点赞，如果我们
Britain for example and we build a brand
例如英国，我们打造了一个品牌
which is that we're anti- wealth we
也就是说，我们反对财富。
don't want you to ever have more than 10
不想让你拥有超过10个
million if you've got more than 10
如果你有超过1000万，那就太好了。
million we punish you every young
我们惩罚你们每一个年轻人，一百万
entrepreneur who comes to me and says
一位企业家来找我说
dan do you think I should start a
丹，你觉得我应该开始吗？
company here in this country I'm going
我要去这家公司。
to say well if you do uh they'll take it
也就是说，如果你这么做，他们会接受的。
as soon as you start to make it they'll
你一旦开始制作，他们就会
take it as soon as if you're successful
一旦成功，就立即领取。
if you get investment they're going to
如果你获得投资，他们就会……
tax you at your wealth if you sell the
如果你出售房产，你的财富将需要缴纳税款。
company they're going to take it off you
公司会把它从你身上拿走。
I'm going to basically say to that young
我基本上要对那个年轻人说
entrepreneur don't build your business
企业家不要建立你的企业
in brit go start it somewhere that
在英国，去某个地方开始吧。
they're more proactive and positive
他们更加积极主动。
towards entrepreneurs are we seeing that
我们是否看到，对于创业者而言，
now with this they call it the
现在他们称之为
millionaire Exodus which is for people
百万富翁出埃及记，这是为人们准备的
that don't know the UK has set to lose
那些不知道英国即将失败的人
the greatest proportion of millionaires
百万富翁比例最高
in the world um this Parliament I'll put
在世界上，嗯，这个议会，我会把它
a graph on the screen which is this one
屏幕上的图表就是这个。
here this one here and that little red
这里，这个，还有那个小红
line here is US losing all of our
这条线代表美国失去了我们所有的
millionaires at the moment and in 2024
目前和 2024 年的百万富翁人数
it's an estimated that 10,800 high net
据估计，有10,800名高净值人士
worth individuals left the UK which is
离开英国的有价值的个人
57% increase from the previous year
比上年增长57%
which means that 1 millionaire is
这意味着1个百万富翁是
departing every 45 minutes the UK
每45分钟一班，英国
millionaire Exodus is equal to losing
百万富翁出埃及记等同于失败
530,000 average taxpayers and another
53万普通纳税人和其他
stat the top 10% of earners in the US
统计美国收入最高的10%人群
account for nearly half of all consumer
几乎占所有消费者的一半
spending the top 1% of income taxpayers
花费收入最高的1%纳税人
in the UK are projected to contribute
预计英国将做出贡献
about 30% of total income tax from 2024
2024年起约占所得税总额的30%。
to
到
2025 why are all these millionaires
2025年，为什么这些人都是百万富翁？
running away well it's not because
逃跑并不是因为
they're taxing their world because we
他们向世界征税，因为我们
don't have any wealth taxes why why do
为什么没有财富税？
you think they're leaving I think the
你认为他们要离开吗？我认为是
reason they're leaving is because the UK
他们离开的原因是英国
economy is is really really weak because
经济形势非常疲软，因为……
the UK consumer is really really weak
英国消费者真的非常脆弱
because you've absolutely crushed the
因为你已经彻底碾压了
spending power of your average British
英国普通民众的购买力
family your average British family can
一个普通的英国家庭
barely afford to feed the kids and turn
勉强才能养活孩子，然后……
the heating on so why are you going to
暖气都开了，你为什么要走？
start a business here when the customers
当顾客
are absolutely impoverished look it
看起来绝对贫困潦倒
corresponds with a new tax that we
与我们新征收的税款相对应
brought in which was um we ended the
引入的那个就是，嗯，我们结束了
non-dom scheme so the non-dom scheme
非域方案，因此非域方案
basically said if you're living in the
基本上是说，如果你住在
UK but you've got businesses all over
英国，但你的企业遍布各地
the world uh then we only tax you on
世界啊，那么我们只对你征税
what you've got in the UK um and if you
你在英国拥有什么，嗯，如果你
die in the UK uh we'll only tax you on
如果你在英国去世，我们只会对你征税。
your UK assets for inheritance tax if
如果您在英国拥有资产，需要缴纳遗产税，请告知我们。
you're a non-dom uh but if you die in
你是非主导者，呃，但是如果你死了
the UK and you've got uh wealth in India
英国，还有你在印度的财富。
once that nonon scheme ended they
一旦那个非自愿计划结束，他们
basically said we will tax you on
基本上就是说我们会对你征税
everything globally if you're an
如果你是全球范围内的所有事物
economic uh if you're a tax resident in
经济方面，如果您是税务居民……
the UK everything you've got globally we
英国拥有你在全球范围内的一切
want 40% of it so unfortunately every
想要其中的40%，所以很遗憾，每
wealth manager contacted their clients
财富管理经理联系了他们的客户。
and said you can't stay here you're
他说你不能留在这里，你是
going to have to get out um it's it's
我得离开……嗯……是的……
gotten really bad a th000 people a month
情况变得非常糟糕，每月有数千人感染。
are leaving and in the UK 1% of people
正在离开，在英国，有1%的人
pay 30% of the taxes 10% of people pay
缴纳30%的税款，而只有10%的人缴纳税款。
60% of the taxes and you imagine if
60%的税收，你想象一下如果
we're sitting out at dinner and there's
我们正在外面吃晚饭，然后……
10 of us out to dinner and one person
我们一行十人外出吃饭，还有一个人
says hey I've got this I get I'll get
他说，嘿，我有这个，我明白，我会明白的。
60% of the bill tonight we say to them
我们告诉他们，今晚账单的60%要付给他们。
no it should be 70% should be 80% and
不，应该是70%，应该是80%。
they say you know what I'll get up and
他们说你知道我会起床的，
leave so they leave everyone else's bill
他们离开时会留下其他人的账单。
just doubled so what's going to happen
刚刚翻了一番，接下来会发生什么？
is if we drive the millionaires out of
如果我们把百万富翁们赶出去……
this country everyone every ordinary
这个国家，每个人都是普通人。
normal person who pays 10 grand a year
普通人每年支付1万美元
in tax will now have to pay 20 grand a
现在，她将不得不缴纳 2 万英镑的税款。
year in tax so the reason they left
税务年度，所以他们离开的原因是……
because we used to allow them to not pay
因为我们过去允许他们不付款。
tax and we Ta on their Global incomes on
税收以及我们对他们全球收入的征税
their Global isn't it a bit more like if
他们的全球战略难道不是更像是……
we were 10 of us at dinner and there was
我们一行十人共进晚餐，当时……
one guy who came on to dinner on the
有个男人来和我共进晚餐
condition he wouldn't pay their leaves
条件是他不会支付他们的休假工资
because these guys weren't paying tax
因为这些人没有缴税。
anyway the reason they left is because
总之，他们离开的原因是……
they weren't paying tax it's like saying
他们没有缴税，这就好比说……
um it's like saying hey I'll pay 60% of
嗯，这就像说，嘿，我愿意支付60%的费用……
this table and they say at the table hey
这张桌子，他们在桌边说：嘿
wait a second we also want you to pay
稍等片刻，我们还需要您付款。
for everything that's happening at other
对于其他方面正在发生的一切
restaurants as well isn't it a bit more
餐馆也是如此，不是吗？
like these guys we're stretching on a
就像这些家伙一样，我们正在拉伸
condition you you yourself said the
条件是你，你自己说的
reason why they left is because we let
他们离开的原因是因为我们放任自流
them live here on the condition that
他们住在这里有一个条件：
they didn't have to pay taxes on their
他们不必为他们的财产缴纳税款。
Global yeah taxes matter right so why
全球税收确实很重要，对吧？那么为什么呢？
why is everyone going to Dubai Dubai
为什么大家都要去迪拜？
they're going there because there's no
他们去那里是因为没有
tax these guys they live in Dubai their
向这些住在迪拜的人征税
money comes from the West they are
钱来自西方，他们是
making money from the West while your
你一边从西方赚钱，一边……
average Western ordinary person watching
普通西方人观看
this show now cannot afford to buy a
这个节目现在买不起……
house cannot afford to have a family we
我们家负担不起养家糊口。
can tax those revenues at the point of
可以在以下情况下对这些收入征税：
sale why do we allow these it's a called
销售，为什么我们允许这些？这叫做
a consumption tax no it's not it's a tax
消费税？不，它不是消费税，它是一种税。
on tax on profit not tax on consumption
对利润征税，而不是对消费征税
you just said at point of sale which
你刚才说的是销售点，
means it's a consumption tax based on
这意味着它是一种基于消费的税
the profits you look at how much profit
你看利润，就是看利润有多少。
they where the profits exactly it's not
他们确实获得了利润，但事实并非如此。
consumption tax what I'm saying so no so
消费税，我的意思是，所以，不，所以
if you tax profits yeah right then those
如果你对利润征税，那当然可以。
profits have to accumulate in that
利润必须积累起来。
country and because of the digital
国家，并且因为数字化
ecosystem that we now have the world we
我们现在所拥有的生态系统，我们这个世界
now live in I can lease the database off
我现在住在这里，我可以租用数据库。
of my company in Luxembourg I can uh
我公司在卢森堡的，我可以……
license the I can license my logo from
我可以授权我的徽标。
understand how profit
了解如何盈利
shifting listen these guys are not
换个角度听，这些人不是
gandal you just say we don't accept
甘达尔，你只是说我们不接受
profit shifting we don't need to accept
我们无需接受利润转移这种做法。
profit shifting China does not accept
中国不接受利润转移行为
profit shifting we did not accept profit
我们不接受利润转移。
shifting 50 years ago we do not have to
50年前的转变我们不必
accept profit shifting but you have a
接受利润转移，但你有一个
government class who are extremely
极其政府阶层
wealthy and a media class are extremely
富裕阶层和媒体阶层极其
wealthy saying it's impossible to tax
富人说征税是不可能的
rich people and I would like to say I
有钱人，我想说我
will agree 100% it is difficult to tax
我完全同意，征税确实很困难。
rich people it is very very very
有钱人非常非常非常
difficult to tax rich people I don't I
很难对富人征税，我不这么认为。
don't come here saying I want to tax
别跑来跟我说我想征税。
rich people because it's easy I know
我知道，有钱人之所以有钱，是因为他们很容易成功。
it's hard I know probably I'm going to
我知道这很难，我可能要……
lose I know our viewers kids will live
输了我知道我们的观众孩子们会活下去
in Desperate poverty I know that I do
在极度贫困中，我知道我
this because it is hard if we are a
这是因为如果我们是……就很难
country which says to ourselves we don't
一个对自己说我们不这样的国家
try and do things which are necessary to
尝试去做那些必要的事情
keep our kids out of poverty because
让孩子们远离贫困，因为
they are hard then our kids will live in
如果它们很艰难，我们的孩子将生活在其中。
poverty I don't need to be here I'm a
贫穷，我不需要待在这里，我是一个
multimillionaire just like you I could
我也可以像你一样成为千万富翁。
be in the Philippines drinking panac
在菲律宾喝帕那克
laders I come in here because I come
我来这里是因为我来了
from a poor background and it's ordinary
出身贫寒，这很普通。
families like my family like the kids I
像我家这样的家庭，喜欢我的孩子
grew up with whose kids are going to be
从小就认识那些孩子将来会成为……
in poverty it's difficult but it is
在贫困中，这很难，但并非不可能。
necessary sometimes we have to do things
有时候，我们必须做一些事情。
not because they're easy but because
不是因为它们容易上手，而是因为
they are hard that is what makes a rich
它们很难，这才是富人之所以富有的原因。
country rich and that is what protects
国家富裕，而这正是保护它的原因。
ordinary people listen our grandparents
普通人听从祖父母的建议
lived in poverty did they say let's not
他们生活在贫困之中，他们说过“我们不要这样”吗？
change it because it's hard no they
改吧，因为这很难，不，他们
didn't they fought and they demanded
他们不是奋起反抗并提出要求吗？
they demanded Health Care education
他们要求接受医疗保健教育
housing food and they got it they got it
他们得到了住房和食物，他们得到了。
that's why my parents could live a good
这就是为什么我的父母能够过上好日子。
quality life they got those things they
他们拥有了那些高品质的生活。
got those things and they were aware
他们得到了那些东西，而且他们也知道。
that in order to do that you could not
为了做到这一点，你不能
allow the super rich who have been
允许那些超级富豪们
living lives of luxury for hundreds and
数百人过着奢华的生活
hundreds of years to eat everything
几百年时间吃光一切
while ordinary families couldn't afford
而普通家庭却负担不起。
to feed their kids I know it's difficult
我知道养活孩子很困难。
I know it's difficult and I know I'm
我知道这很难，我也知道我
probably going to lose I know that I
我知道我可能会输。
know I'm probably going to lose and that
我知道我可能会输，而且
means our viewers will be poor but I do
这意味着我们的观众会很穷，但我确实如此
it anyway because I do not want this
不管怎样，我还是这么做了，因为我不想要这个。
country that I grew up in to fall into
我成长的国家让我陷入了
desperate poverty I agree with you on
我同意你对极度贫困的看法。
the passion and I agree with you on the
这份热情，我同意你的看法。
problem I don't agree with you on the
我不同意你的观点。
solution because in 2019 we be kids in
解决方案，因为在2019年我们还是孩子。
2020 and that's not what I'm saying in
2020年，那不是我要说的。
2020 we made a decision globally to shut
2020年，我们决定在全球范围内关闭
down the economy and we taught everyone
经济衰退，我们教会了所有人
that they can live and work from
他们可以在那里生活和工作
anywhere the biggest threat to
任何地方最大的威胁
everything you're saying is remote
你说的这些都太遥远了。
working the fact that we can live and
意识到我们可以生存下去，
work work from anywhere our grandparents
我们的祖父母在任何地方都能工作
their boss if their boss owned a company
如果他们老板拥有一家公司，那么他们的老板就是他们的老板。
that company had to physically be in the
那家公司必须实际位于
country and the boss had to physically
国家和老板不得不亲自前往。
be in the country if we look at today
如果我们看看今天的情况，就会发现身处这个国家。
there are plenty of fitness trainers who
有很多健身教练
work for a gym and the owner of that gym
在一家健身房工作，也是这家健身房的老板。
is somewhere overseas plenty of people
海外某个地方人很多
work in live work in a restaurant and
在餐厅里边工作边生活
the owner of the restaurant lives
餐馆老板住在
overseas you can live in you can run a
在海外，你可以生活，你可以经营……
business from anywhere in the world
随时随地开展业务
right now so the problem that we face is
所以，我们现在面临的问题是：
that you're describing on one hand you
一方面，你描述的是……
say we need to tax it at the point of
假设我们需要在某个点对其征税
sale which is a consumption tax and not
销售税属于消费税，而非其他税项。
tax on profit okay and then you say a
对利润征税，好的，然后你说……
tax on profit and then you say oh but
对利润征税，然后你说，哦，但是
then we'll stop profit shifting by the
那么我们将停止通过以下方式转移利润：
way I'm also actually all for this idea
其实我也非常赞同这个想法。
of stopping profit I I've already said I
关于停止盈利，我已经说过了。
think it's utterly ridiculous the way
我觉得这种做法简直荒谬至极。
that many of these global companies are
许多这样的全球性公司
treated and if we don't stop that then
治疗，如果我们不阻止这种情况发生……
all the money just flows out to the tech
所有资金都流向了科技公司。
companies um so I'm I'm with you on that
公司，嗯，所以我同意你的看法。
but when you say tax the rich the actual
但当你提到向富人征税时，实际情况
people who own the companies those
那些拥有这些公司的人
people can be anywhere right now so but
现在人们可能身处任何地方，但是
but their revenues can't their customers
但他们的收入却无法惠及他们的客户。
their customers are where their
他们的客户都在哪里？
customers are their customers are where
顾客就是他们的顾客，他们在哪里
their customers are listen Amazon
他们的客户都在听亚马逊的。
doesn't pay any UK tax doesn't pay any
不缴纳任何英国税款
us tax where are the customers in the UK
美国税务部门，英国的客户在哪里？
and Us in UK US do you really think it's
我们英国和美国，你们真的认为这是真的吗？
impossible for us to tax that well
我们不可能对那块地征税。
you're talking about taxing people at 10
你这是在说对10岁的人征税吗？
million plus right so this is a lot of
超过一百万美元，对吧？所以这很多……
startup entrepreneurs Jeff Bez is a lot
创业企业家杰夫·贝兹（Jeff Bez）非常出色。
more than 10 million jez Jeff worth a
超过1000万杰兹·杰夫身价
lot more than you talk about anyone
比你谈论任何人要多得多
above 10 million is on your radar you
超过1000万美元已进入您的关注范围。
don't want people worth 11 million
不想找身价1100万美元的人
pounds we pay more I'm not just talk
我们付的钱更多，我不是在说说而已。
it's not that Dan if you you you're
丹，如果你是你，你就不是那样
worth more than 10 million pounds so if
价值超过1000万英镑，所以如果
we tax people
我们对人民征税
on as Gary says that have more than 10
正如加里所说，他们有超过10个
million what are your options to avoid
百万，你有哪些避免的选择？
say if your objective was to avoid that
比如说，如果你的目标是避免这种情况
what options do you have look if if my
你有哪些选择？看看如果我
objective was to avoid it I pass a board
目标是避免这种情况，我经过了一块板子。
resolution that we're moving the head
决议是我们要移动头部
office somewhere else yeah um we move
办公室搬到别的地方，嗯，我们搬家。
the intellectual property somewhere else
其他地方的知识产权
I pick up and move my family somewhere
我带着家人搬到某个地方。
else and within about a week or two
否则，大约一两周内就会发生这种情况。
we've got a we work office somewhere
我们在某个地方有个WeWork办公室。
else I've got a new house on Airbnb
否则，我在Airbnb上租了一套新房子。
somewhere else and I cut ties with the
我去了别的地方，并与他断绝了关系。
UK and I'm non- tax resident here and I
我来自英国，但并非英国税务居民。
can I have a digital business I can
我可以拥有一家数字企业吗？
literally make my head office anywhere
我真的可以把总部设在任何地方。
in the world if there was a particular
如果世界上存在某种特定的东西
country that turned hostile towards uh
那个对……抱有敌意的国家
our operations they not have to withdraw
我们的运营无需撤出
service from that thing you know so that
你知道，从那件事中获得服务，这样
that's possible but it's unlikely that
这有可能，但可能性不大。
that would actually happen but
那件事确实会发生，但是
ultimately if I choose to get up and
最终，如果我选择起床，
leave then I get up and leave now the
然后我就起身离开。
the the bigger issue is would I have
更大的问题是，我是否……
even come here in the first place and
首先，他们甚至会来到这里。
then there's another issue and here's
然后还有另一个问题，那就是……
the other issue Gary for you you've just
加里，你刚才提到的另一个问题是……
had 750,000 subscribers to your YouTube
你的 YouTube 频道有 75 万订阅者。
channel 820 it's 8:20 right so it's
820频道，现在是8点20分，对吧？
going up fast I could have one of my
上升得很快，我可能拥有我的一个
analysts at a consulting company do
咨询公司的分析师们
valuation of your brand and do valuation
对您的品牌进行估值并进行估值
of your YouTube channel we could say
我们可以说，关于你的YouTube频道
this is a fast growth media company and
这是一家快速发展的媒体公司，
it's worth 11 million right so we could
它价值1100万美元，对吧？所以我们可以
come up with a forecast and a projection
做出预测和展望
and we say Gary's economics is actually
我们说加里的经济学实际上是
a new Fast growth media brand it's worth
一个快速增长的新兴媒体品牌，它的价值
11 million now your channel now you have
现在你的频道有1100万粉丝了，你现在拥有
to pay 100 Grand a year in extra taxes
每年额外缴纳 10 万美元税款
because you're a millionaire sorry 1% on
因为你是百万富翁，抱歉，只有1%
wealth above 10 million on 11 million is
超过1000万的1100万财富是
going to be 10 grand taxes oh you're
税款要1万美元，哦，你是
saying only on the part above that's how
仅就以上部分而言，情况就是这样。
taxes work so it's not on everything
税收制度决定了它并非适用于所有商品。
it's okay so it's a it's a marginal tax
没关系，这是边际税。
that's how taxes work it's so okay so
这就是税收运作方式，没关系。
but is it fair that like who gets to
但是，谁有权……这公平吗？
decide what wealth Is wealth and what
确定什么是财富，以及什么才是财富。
it's worth because wealth let's just hit
它的价值在于财富，让我们直击要害吧。
me out wealth is a a technical term for
财富是一个技术术语，指的是
unrealized gains right it's not real uh
未实现的收益，对吧？它不是真的。
you know someone buys a house for 20
你知道有人花了20美元买了一栋房子吗？
grand and it's worth 200 Grand uh
很棒，价值20万美元。
they've still got the same house but now
他们仍然住在同一栋房子里，但现在
they've got wealth um if someone starts
他们很有财富，嗯，如果有人开始……
a business and a tiny little seed
一家企业和一颗小小的种子
investor puts in a little angel
投资者投入了一位小天使
investment uh now they've got wealth on
投资，呃，现在他们已经积累了财富。
paper but who gets to say what is wealth
纸面上的东西，但谁又能定义什么是财富呢？
um like for
嗯，比如……
example if you introduce wealth taxes
例如，如果您引入财富税
theoretically that will actually reduce
理论上，这实际上会减少
the value of wealth of things anyway
财富和物品的价值无论如何
because things in inside that economy
因为经济内部的事情
are now subject to a disadvantage so
现在处于不利地位，因此
therefore investors will be unlikely to
因此，投资者不太可能
invest in them to a certain point and
对它们进行一定程度的投资，
also people start cutting and dodging
人们也开始切割和躲避
and weaving and ducking and weaving so
编织、躲避、再编织
they say oh our UK operations worth 10
他们说，哦，我们在英国的业务价值10
million so we're now going to start a
一百万，所以我们现在要开始一个
second company over in some other
第二家公司在其他方面
country and make sure that that's where
国家，并确保那是那里
the wealth accumulates so it's
财富不断积累，所以……
incredibly difficult because it is just
极其困难，因为它只是
unrealized gains I know I know it's
未实现的收益，我知道，我知道，是
difficult yeah I know I know these guys
很难，是啊，我知道，我认识这些人。
have the best accountants I I know it's
拥有最好的会计师，我知道这一点
difficult I know so what if there was an
我知道这很难，但即便如此，如果……
easier solution if there was an easier
如果有更简单的解决方案就好了
solution I would support that you know
我支持的解决方案是，你知道的。
what I mean it's called it's called
我的意思是，它叫做，它叫做
economic freedom the economic freedom
经济自由
index okay well just tell the viewers
索引好的，那就告诉观众吧。
that give them more economic freedom and
这能让他们拥有更多的经济自由；
then they'll be rich yeah so this this
那他们就会发财了，对，就是这样
diagram here basically says the most
这里的图表基本上说明了一切。
free countries have less than 10%
自由国家的这一比例不到10%。
poverty in fact less than 7% poverty as
事实上，贫困率低于7%。
soon as you reduce economic freedom it
一旦你削减经济自由……
jumps to 30% poverty you reduce economic
贫困率飙升至30%，经济状况恶化
freedom again and it jumps up to huge
它再次获得自由，并跃升至巨大
huge amounts of poverty so the these
大量的贫困人口，所以这些
countries here are the least
这里的国家最少
economically free and these countries
经济自由的国家
are the most economically free the
经济上最自由的群体
countries that get in the way of your
阻碍你前进的国家
economic freedom have more poverty and
经济自由度越高，贫困程度就越重。
the countries that let people make
允许人们制造的国家
decisions for their own life what you're
他们为自己的生活做出决定，你是什么？
saying is if the governments of our
也就是说，如果我们的政府
countries cut taxes on us the three
这三个国家削减了对我们三国的税收。
multimillionaire sitting at this table
坐在这张桌子旁的是一位千万富翁。
that will improve the lives of the
这将改善人们的生活
ordinary British and American give a
普通的英国人和美国人给出了
real life example to feed their kids
现实生活中的例子，他们如何喂养孩子
I'll give you a real life example uh I
我给你举个现实生活中的例子，呃……
know of a company that was going to give
我知道有一家公司打算提供
pay Rises to its employees and then
员工薪酬上涨，然后
National Insurance went up and instead
国民保险费上涨了，取而代之的是……
of National Insurance is a tax on
国民保险是一种税
employment yeah I'm saying to reduce
是的，我的意思是减少就业。
that I'm saying to reduce tax on I want
我的意思是降低我想要的税收
your viewers the viewers here to be
你的观众，这里的观众
paying less tax while multimillionaires
千万富翁缴纳的税款较少
pay more tax good in theory but of if
理论上多缴税是好事，但如果
you could tax rich people 1% of their
你可以对富人征收1%的税。
wealth above 10 million uh I did a back
财富超过1000万，呃，我做了个反向
of a napkin cap calculation you might be
计算餐巾纸容量时，你可能会……
able to get 20 billion yeah right that's
能拿到200亿？呵呵，真是的。
if they don't leave that's if they don't
如果他们不离开的话，那就是如果他们不离开的话。
respond to it if they just happily pay
如果他们乐意付款，就回应他们。
it you get 20 billion that's less than a
如果你得到200亿，那还不到一个
week worth of current government
本周现任政府
spending
开支
so the government's out of control 1.2
所以政府已经失控了 1.2
trillion a year of government spending
政府每年支出万亿美元
is now what they spend okay so let's cut
这就是他们现在的支出情况，好吧，那我们就削减开支吧。
that get that 20 billion and cut the
拿到那200亿美元，然后削减……
taxes for the viewers cut their income
观众的税收减少了他们的收入。
tax so that works out about 250 a year
税的话，一年大概要交250元。
okay so let's do more let's make it 60
好的，那我们再多做一点，达到60个吧。
billion so then you tax 3% above wealth
十亿，那么超过这个数额的财富就要征收3%的税。
yeah do that right and then you also
对，照做就行了，然后你也
bring it down this is what governments
把它推倒，这就是政府的所作所为。
do make five or six yeah and then and
做五六个，然后……
that's what they did that's what they
他们就是这么做的，他们就是这么做的
did in the second world war and that's
二战期间确实如此，那就是
why my dad could afford a house actually
为什么我爸爸实际上买得起房子
that's not why you could afford a house
那并不是你买得起房子的原因。
okay well who's buy if Ordinary People
好吧，如果《普通人》这部电影有人买的话。
are losing their houses and the wealth
他们正在失去房屋和财富。
which they are yeah and we're getting
是的，他们确实如此，我们正在获得
richer yeah who is it who is now owning
更富有了？是啊，现在是谁在拥有它？
the houses if it is not us the
如果不是我们，这些房子……
government used to own the houses and
政府过去拥有这些房屋，
then they sold the government wealth is
然后他们把政府财富卖掉了。
collapsing government wealth is
政府财富崩溃是
collapsing but what they did is they
崩溃了，但他们所做的却是……
sold the houses to the people okay but
把房子卖给人们没问题，但是
but ordinary middle is also you can only
但普通的中间地带也是你只能
do that once and they did it for the
他们这样做过一次，就一直这样做了。
baby so you think it's our viewers who
宝贝，所以你认为这是我们的观众吗？
have got my houses now who where is the
我现在有房子了，谁在哪儿？
wealth going Daniel where is the wealth
丹尼尔，财富在哪里？财富在哪里？
going who has the wealth now who is
现在谁有财富？谁是
getting rich who is getting the wealth
谁在致富？谁在获得财富？
that is lost by our viewers I'll tell
我会告诉你，这是我们的观众所忽略的。
you where the biggest amounts of money
你拥有最多的钱
are going the biggest amounts of money
正在流向最大金额的资金
uh since the pandemic uh 11 trillion
自疫情爆发以来，已有11万亿美元。
went just to the value of seven
正好是七。
companies that own te technology so the
拥有该技术的公司
biggest seven companies in the USA 11
美国最大的七家公司 11
trillion has and you don't want their
万亿已经存在，而你不想拥有它们
billionaire owners to pay more tax well
亿万富翁业主需缴纳更多税款
would that help the UK well if you use
如果你使用，这对英国会有很大的帮助吗？
that money to reduce tax on working
这笔钱将用于减少劳动者的税收。
people then it it would help yeah they
那么人们就会觉得这会有帮助，是的，他们
own shares in the USA they're US
在美国拥有股份，他们是美国人
citizens so that doesn't help us here
公民们，所以这对我们这里没有帮助。
but it will help the American Consumer
但这有助于美国消费者。
and then we can export the American
然后我们就可以出口美国产品了。
Consumer and it will mean the American
消费者，这意味着美国
Consumer has money and then it will show
消费者有钱，然后就会显现出来。
British people how much you can achieve
英国人，你们能取得多大的成就？
by taxing Super Rich we can raise tax on
通过对超级富豪征税，我们可以提高税收。
our Super Rich here and then what I want
我们这里的超级富豪，还有我想要的
is these guys to be taxed so much that
这些人要缴纳如此多的税吗？
they start to sell assets and then
他们开始出售资产，然后
ordinary British people can buy assets
普通英国人也可以购买资产
again because what I want is our viewers
再次强调，我想要的是我们的观众。
to be able to own things to be able to
能够拥有物品，能够
own their own homes I when I hear this
他们拥有自己的房子，当我听到这话时……
um I admissibly don't know as much about
嗯，我承认我对这方面了解不多。
these issues as you guys do but when I
这些问题你们也遇到过，但是当我
hear that there's these seven tech
听说有这七项技术
companies in the US my brain goes can't
美国公司，我的大脑一片空白，无法理解。
we have one here yeah yeah can't we
我们这里有一个，对对，我们不能吗？
start and then so my brain goes how what
开始，然后我的大脑就开始想：怎么回事？
conditions do we have to create ones
我们需要创造哪些条件？
that we had yeah what conditions do we
我们当时的情况是，是的，我们有什么条件？
have to create to have one of those
必须创造才能拥有其中之一
seven tech companies here especially in
这里尤其有七家科技公司
this sort of AI World we're heading
我们正朝着这样的人工智能世界迈进。
towards where when I was reading through
当我读到那里的时候
the stats most of the investment in AI
统计数据显示，大部分投资都集中在人工智能领域。
which is going to be hugely
这将产生巨大的影响
destabilizing across every industry from
对所有行业都造成了不稳定
driving to to any form of knowledge work
驾车前往任何形式的知识工作
even podcasting I can play your podcast
即使是播客，我也可以播放你的播客。
now yeah which sounds exactly like me
没错，这听起来简直跟我一模一样。
which has a 4.6 star rating on Apple
在苹果产品评测中获得 4.6 星评分
which was written by AI in my voice
这是人工智能用我的声音写的。
published by AI Wild and the and who's
由 AI Wild 和谁出版
acing the value there well it's a
在那里获得高价值，嗯，这确实是一个
company in America called 11 labs and
美国一家名为11 Labs的公司
it's bloody open Ai and I why why can't
它明明是开放的AI，为什么我却不能用？
we have those companies here we need
我们这里有我们需要的那些公司。
them here because China and the US are
他们在这里是因为中国和美国
dominating this next
主导接下来
Revolution um and I I worry as a
革命，嗯，我担心……
bystander that if we don't create
旁观者，如果我们不创造
entrepreneurship friendly environments
有利于创业的环境
here we're going to we are going to
接下来我们要去……
become Indian yeah M so you if you want
成为印度人，是的，所以如果你想的话
businesses that to thrive you don't need
要想蓬勃发展，你不需要……
just a good environment for
这只是一个很好的环境
entrepreneurs you also need people to
创业者也需要人手
have money that they can spend MH and we
他们有钱可以花在MH和我们身上
are in a country where
身处一个国家
increasingly most of the people out
越来越多的人外出
there have almost nothing left over at
几乎没有剩余任何东西了
the end of the month they can barely pay
月底他们几乎都付不起钱了。
the bills those companies are selling
这些公司正在出售的票据
globally right so they don't need any
全球右翼，所以他们不需要任何
particular company to do well they just
特定公司表现出色，他们只是
they sell to anywhere so like open AI
他们的产品销往世界各地，比如 OpenAI。
chat GPT we're all using that Bloody
聊天 GPT 我们都在用那个该死的
product and pay our 20 $30 a month yeah
产品，每月支付 20 至 30 美元，是的。
where do they actually get their money
他们的钱到底是从哪里来的？
from right they get their money from
他们从右翼获得资金
selling data to to to the rich right my
向富人出售数据，我的
point was making the environment more
重点是使环境更加……
friendly for entrepreneurs because when
对创业者友好，因为当
I start a company I am at a I can't
我创办了一家公司，但我现在无法做到
explain the disadvantage I'm at at the
请解释一下我目前所处的劣势
moment if I start that kind of company
如果我创办那样的公司……
here in the UK there's no investors and
在英国，没有投资者，
then all the talent seems to flock over
然后所有人才似乎都蜂拥而至。
to San Francisco so the the guys that
去旧金山，所以那些家伙
built the British guys that built an AI
建造人工智能的英国人
company called fixer which I was going
我当时正要去一家叫Fixer的公司。
to invest in all British Lads from
投资所有英国小伙子
London they went over to San Francisco
他们从伦敦去了旧金山
they're like 25y olds they've just
他们就像25岁的人一样，他们刚刚
raised at a 60 million valuation they're
他们以6000万美元的估值融资。
in this room this building in San
在这个房间里，这栋位于圣的建筑物里
Francisco full of entrepreneurs and
旧金山到处都是企业家，
they're pumping knowledge and capital
他们正在注入知识和资本
into this room with all due respect
谨以此房，恭敬地进入此室
Stephen you're not a great example for
斯蒂芬，你并不是个好榜样。
the fact that it's impossible to start a
事实是，根本无法开始
successful online brand in the UK facts
英国成功在线品牌案例
um but I also realized that the problem
嗯，但我同时也意识到这个问题
of of but he started when things were
但他开始的时候，事情是
different but I I also realized I don't
虽然不一样，但我同时也意识到我并不
like using personal examples because
喜欢用个人例子，因为
there's a huge amount of privilege and
这里存在着大量的特权，
okay is there a chat gbt in Germany No
好的，德国有LGBT聊天室吗？没有
is there a chat gbt in in France no is
法国有LGBT聊天室吗？没有。
there a chat GPT in Australia no no is
澳大利亚有聊天 GPT 吗？没有。
there a chat GPT in ja it's China and
日语里有个聊天 GPT，那是中国的。
one sec SEC yeah exactly what you have
一秒钟，没错，就是你说的。
here is an extremely low labor extremely
这里劳动力成本极低
high Capital model which employs
采用高资本模式
extremely few people across the entire
整个世界范围内极少数人
world that is focused in basically two
一个主要关注两个方面的世界
cities yeah good luck competing with
城市？祝你好运，与它们竞争！
that H how do we create an environment
那H，我们如何创造一个环境
where the UK can start to build some of
英国可以开始建设一些……
these companies which are going to
这些公司即将
capitalize on this next technological
充分利用这项下一代技术
Revolution how if you were prime
革命，如果你是元首
minister what would you do I think you
部长，您会怎么做？我想您
need to look realistically about what
需要务实地看待什么
companies do we have a chance of growing
公司是否有机会发展壮大
you know I'm not an expert in AI but I
你知道我不是人工智能专家，但是
think trying to compete with San
想想看，试图与圣地亚哥竞争。
Francisco in London would will probably
弗朗西斯科在伦敦可能会
not work why try try and do it you know
行不通，为什么还要试？你知道的。
try and do it and listen I know that you
试着去做，听着，我知道你
can get a lot of likes saying let's just
说“我们就这样吧”可以获得很多点赞
invest in AI let's just invest only one
投资人工智能，我们只投资一个。
city in the world outside of China has
中国以外的世界城市有
Managed IT China has Managed IT by
中国托管IT公司已通过以下方式进行托管IT：
basically State capitalism you know this
基本上就是国家资本主义，你知道的。
is very similar in a sense to what we
从某种意义上说，它与我们非常相似。
had with micro Electronics in Japan in
日本微电子行业
the 8S right when you have a new
当你刚拿到一辆新的8S时
industry especially these industries
尤其是这些行业
which are very Capital intense and don't
这些行业是资本密集型的​​，而且不
employ many people you get a first move
雇佣很多人，你就能抢占先机。
Advantage they tend to win eventually
他们的优势最终往往会让他们获胜。
often they get undercut by cheaper
它们经常会被更便宜的竞争对手抢走生意。
Rivals and that does happen you know
竞争对手之间确实会发生这种情况，你知道的。
that does happen and you might stand in
这种情况确实会发生，你可能会被卷入其中。
AI I don't think AI is going to become a
我不认为人工智能会成为……
massive massive employer of course you
当然，你是大型雇主。
know a lot of countries are going to be
我知道很多国家将会……
like because basically it sounds good
因为它听起来不错
we're going to invest in I we're going
我们将投资于 I 我们正在前往
to invest in AI personally I think we
就我个人而言，我认为投资人工智能是我们
should be looking at what does the
应该看看这是什么
British person need you know we live in
英国人需要你知道我们生活在
a country where the housing stock is
住房存量为
falling apart if if we say AI when we
如果我们说人工智能，它就会崩溃。
talk about AI I think we're actually
谈到人工智能，我认为我们实际上
talking about technology because even a
谈论科技，因为即使是
podcast like a podcast like this you
像这样的播客，你
don't think this of this as an AI
不要把这看作是人工智能
company but actually now the editing
公司，但实际上现在是编辑
process the scripting process the
脚本处理过程
transcription process even YouTube
转录过程甚至 YouTube
itself is an AI company so it's it's
它本身就是一家人工智能公司，所以它是……
really technology we're speaking about
我们真正谈论的是技术
here and I'm wondering why we can't
我在这里，我想知道为什么我们不能
create a better environment in the UK to
在英国创造更好的环境
start launching and building some of
开始启动和构建一些
these technology companies we've even
这些科技公司，我们甚至……
seen I think we should and I think we
我认为我们应该这样做，而且我认为我们
should be looking we should be look at
应该看看我们应该关注
reducing taxes on people who who work
减少劳动者的税收
and make money this is what I've been
这就是我一直以来努力的方向，赚钱就是为了赚钱。
saying for the whole time what about
一直说着什么
people what about people who start
人们，那些开始的人呢？
companies
公司
yeah we should reduce their taxes on the
是的，我们应该降低他们的税收。
income that they make but then if they
他们赚取的收入，但如果他们
start owning A50 million pound company
开始拥有一家价值5000万英镑的公司
are you telling me if you come to me and
你是说如果你来找我的话
I say all right you want to start a
我说好吧，你想开始一个
company we we tax you very very little
我们公司对您的征税非常非常少
on a company that you start if that
如果你创办一家公司的话……
company becomes worth 20 30 40 million
公司市值达到2000万、3000万和4000万。
quid then we're going to start taxing
如果是这样，我们就要开始征税了。
you you're going to come and say to me
你会过来跟我说
oh no sorry 50 million is not enough for
哦不，抱歉，5000万不够。
me so can I ask a question on that so um
所以，我能问个问题吗？嗯……
my company was was valued at x 50
我的公司估值是原来的50倍
whatever 100 Millions um congratulations
不管怎样，1亿，嗯，恭喜！
I still had because I hadn't had an exit
我仍然有退路，因为我没有退路。
event yeah I still had 101,000 20,000 in
是的，我还有101,000和20,000。
my bank account are you saying at the
你是说我的银行账户在……
point when I sell the company or are you
我何时出售公司？或者你是？
saying just because I have shares from
仅仅因为我持有股份就这么说，
the company I think you can structure it
我认为你可以构建这家公司。
a number of ways you can structure a
你可以用多种方式来构建一个
number of ways my preferred way is to
有很多方法，但我更喜欢的方法是……
stop people from hoarding enormous a of
阻止人们囤积大量……
wealth for enormous amounts of time
巨额财富
that's my that's basically my preferred
那基本上就是我的首选
method there's also the wealth tax
另一种方法是征收财富税。
method there's also capital gains as a
另一种方法是资本利得法。
method there's a lot of different ways
方法有很多种。
it there's a lot of different ways but
有很多不同的方法，但是
you have to deal with the problem of if
你必须处理“如果”这个问题。
you do not do not tax very wealthy
你不对非常富有的人征税。
individuals and very wealthy families
个人和非常富有的家庭
their share of the pie will obviously
他们分到的那份蛋糕显然会
goow over time and they will and they
随着时间的推移，它们会……而且它们
are as we are watching squeezing our
我们正在看着我们被挤压
ordinary families you have to deal with
你必须面对的普通家庭
that my friend sold his company in the
我的朋友把他的公司卖掉了。
UK it's a company everybody knows um and
英国，这是一家人尽皆知的公司。
he I remember him saying to me at the
我记得他当时对我说……
time it was in the middle of the
当时正值中间
pandemic he got this big exit event I
疫情期间，他举办了一场盛大的告别活动。
think he'd made 300 million and he goes
他以为自己赚了3亿美元，然后他就走了
I'm off I go where you going he goes I'm
我走了，你去哪儿我就去哪儿，他去哪儿我就去哪儿。
going to go to Dubai in Monaco and live
准备去摩纳哥的迪拜居住
between the two and I I said explain to
我和他们俩之间，我说要解释一下
me why he goes well the amount of tax
我问他为什么税额这么高。
I'd have to pay in the UK is equivalent
我在英国需要支付的费用是等价的。
to me paying 20 million rent in the UK
对我来说，在英国支付2000万英镑的租金
for the next six or seven years which
接下来的六七年里，
he'd have to stay here for so he he went
他得留在这里，所以他就去了
and he pops back in every now and then
他时不时会回来。
but it meant that he could keep that 150
但这意味着他可以保留那150美元。
million whatever tax he would pay never
百万，无论他要缴纳多少税，他都不会支付。
had to pay it to the UK is living this
不得不付钱给英国，这就是现状。
highflying life now in Dubai drops into
如今在迪拜的奢华生活骤然跌落谷底
Monaco every now and then um and I
偶尔去摩纳哥，嗯，还有我
remember him saying to me well Steve I'd
记得他跟我说过，史蒂夫，我会
have to pay 20 million rent a year to
每年需支付2000万租金
live here and he went on to say the UK
他住在这里，然后又说英国
product is just isn't worth it he goes
他说，这产品根本不值这个价。
crime I'm going to get my Rolex robbed
犯罪！我的劳力士要被偷了！
off me he goes um the healthare system
他离开我，嗯，医疗保健系统
isn't the best the education system
教育系统并非最佳选择。
isn't necessarily the best and the
未必是最好的，而且
particular one was crime which is I'll
其中一项特别重要的事是犯罪，那就是我将
get I'll get i'll get mugged walking
我会被抢劫，我会走路的时候被抢劫。
through yeah London streets Stephen if
是的，穿过伦敦的街道，斯蒂芬如果
you allow British people who own 300
你允许拥有300个英国人
million pound of British assets to
数百万英镑的英国资产
technically live in Monaco and not pay
严格来说，我住在摩纳哥，却不用付钱。
tax then you will get crime and you will
征税会导致犯罪，然后你就会
have dirty streets and you will have a
街道脏乱，你就会……
bad Health Care system and you will have
糟糕的医疗保健系统，你将会……
education because if you give all of the
教育，因为如果你给予所有
wealth to a group of people who do not
财富流向一群不了解财富的人
tax there will be nothing left to
征税后将一无所有。
provide things like healthcare and
提供医疗保健等服务
education for ordinary people it's not
普通人的教育并非如此。
unconnected these people are not
这些人之间没有关联
technically living there they're moving
严格来说，他们住在那里，但他们要搬走了。
out my friends have moved out of the
我的朋友们都搬出去了。
country they don't come back to the UK
他们不会回到英国。
they've left and they leave with their
他们离开了，他们带着他们的
they built a company here they glob P
他们在这里建立了一家公司，他们遍布全球。
tax they typically build globally
他们通常会在全球范围内征收税款
business it's not that they P it was a
商业并非如此，他们P，那是一个
global they don't pay no tax they pay
全球范围内，他们不缴纳任何税款，他们缴纳
extortionate amounts of tax right anyone
任何人的巨额税款都属于违法行为。
who's here is paying extraordinary taxes
这里的人都在缴纳巨额税款
more than they've ever paid before 1%
比他们以往支付的金额多1%。
pays 30% 10% pays 60% of 1 trillion a
支付 30%，10% 支付 1 万亿的 60%。
year gu 300 million how much tax Rec
一年 gu 3 亿多少税 Rec
he's paid in his life I have no idea I
他这辈子赚了多少钱，我一概不知。
have no idea his business was Global
我完全不知道他的公司是Global。
that his biggest customer was the US
他最大的客户是美国。
it's I pay 60% and our viewers will pay
我支付60%，我们的观众也支付一部分。
30 40 50% do you think it's fair that
30%、40%、50% 你觉得这样公平吗？
your 300 million guy pays his two or
你那位身价3亿美元的家伙付给他的两个或
three I have no idea what he pays well
三，我不知道他给的薪水是多少。
it sounds like he didn't pay 50% well he
听起来他好像没付50%的钱。
dashed when before he got the tax bill
在他收到税单之前，他感到很沮丧。
but why did we allow it why did we allow
但我们为什么允许它发生？我们为什么允许它发生？
I I'm not allowed to not pay my tax what
我不允许不缴税。
could you have done to you are allowed
你本可以做你被允许做的事情。
to when you were in Japan you wouldn't
当你身在日本的时候，你不会
have paid UK taxes
已缴纳英国税款
yeah because I was working in Japan and
是的，因为我当时在日本工作。
I pay Japanese taxes because you're
我缴纳日本税款是因为你是
living in Japan this is the thing people
在日本生活，这就是人们会遇到的情况。
can live wherever they want now so but
他们现在可以住在任何地方了，但是
we're talking about this is I think we
我们正在讨论的这个，我认为我们
should stop obfuscating tax on people's
应该停止混淆视听，让人们不再为税收问题烦恼
work from tax on the ass they uh so I'm
他们靠税收赚钱，所以……
talking about entrepreneurs work
谈论创业者的工作
generates wealth so when if I if I ear a
创造财富，所以当我听到一个
billion pound of British houses yeah and
价值数十亿英镑的英国房产，是的。
then I say I live in Dubai yeah and I'm
然后我说我住在迪拜，是的，我是
getting the rent on a billion pounds of
收取十亿英镑的租金
houses which would probably be something
房子，那大概就是某种东西
like like that's going to be something
好像那会是件大事。
like 50 million a year so I'm getting 60
一年大概五千万，所以我能拿到六千万。
50 60 million a year of rent from
每年租金收入5000万至6000万美元
British people yeah and that gets paid
是的，英国人，而且他们还能拿到报酬。
to me from British people yeah and I pay
是的，英国人会给我付款。
and I don't pay tax I live in Dubai do
我住在迪拜，所以不用交税。
you think that's fair no all right so
你觉得这样公平吗？好吧，就这样。
let's change that let's let's make
让我们改变现状，让我们……
people pay tax on on their world
人们在他们的世界里缴纳税款
regardless where they live yeah the
无论他们住在哪里，是的。
question would be though how would you
问题是，你会怎么做？
tax people right and how would you
对税务人员来说，你们会怎么做？
actually structure it because regardless
实际上要把它组织起来，因为无论如何
of what you feel like is fair this is
你觉得这公平吗？
the thing it's not about fairness it's
关键不在于公平，而在于……
about what you can pragmatic and
关于你能务实做些什么，以及
practically do in the modern economy you
在现代经济中，你实际上会这样做。
might say oh I actually like for example
可能会说，哦，我其实很喜欢，例如
if we said what's fair a lot of people
如果我们说什么是公平，很多人
would say a flat tax is fair you make
你会说统一税率很公平，你赚的
one pound you pay 20% you make a million
你花一英镑，支付20%，就能赚一百万英镑。
pounds you pay 20% make 100 million
你支付20%的税，就能赚到1亿英镑
pounds you pay 20% so a lot of people
英镑要付20%，所以很多人都要付20%。
would say the fairest tax system would
会说最公平的税收制度是
just be a flat tax on everything right
对所有商品都征收统一税率就行了，对吧？
that would be a fair thing it's
那倒也算公平。
pragmatically can you do it is it
务实地说，你能做到吗？是的
actually good for society should people
实际上，这对社会有益的人
be excluded from that so it's not about
被排除在外，所以这与此无关。
fairness it's about pragmatically what
公平，从务实的角度来看，关乎什么？
can you get away with all right well
你能逃脱惩罚吗？
pragmatically what we can get away with
务实地讲，我们可以逃脱惩罚
is desperate poverty for our viewers
这对于我们的观众来说，是极度贫困。
kids if you want to have can we zoom out
孩子们，如果你们想的话，我们可以缩小画面吗？
just a minute right I want to zoom out
稍等片刻，我想缩小画面。
let's Zoom away from our viewers kids
让我们用Zoom远离观众和孩子们吧。
forget about them they're not I got I'm
别管他们了，他们不是我，我明白了。
a dad right I got three kids you're you
我是个爸爸，对吧？我有三个孩子，你是……
are a multimillionaire dad you probably
如果你是一位身价数百万美元的爸爸，你可能
don't have the same problems as our
我们没有遇到和我们一样的问题。
viewers do you know that do you know
观众朋友们，你们知道吗？你们知道吗？
that kids born into the top have a 60%
出生于上层家庭的孩子有60%
chance of dropping out of the top right
有可能从右上角掉下来
60% that's the number it's called
60%，这就是它所叫的数字。
persistence you can Google it um the
持久性，你可以谷歌一下。
persistence rates is actually only 40%
实际持续率只有40%。
for the richest so which means 60% drop
对于最富有的人来说，这意味着下降60%。
out in the second you think kids have a
在你认为孩子们有……的那一刻
60% chance of living in poverty POS not
60% 的概率生活在贫困线以下
poverty do you know what's interesting
贫穷，你知道什么才有趣吗？
we're all trying to aim at the same goal
我们都在努力朝着同一个目标前进
I think here I'm not sure we are but
我觉得我们在这里不太确定，但是
well that's fair that's fair maybe we're
嗯，这很公平，这很公平，也许我们是
not I suspect some of us are maybe
我怀疑我们当中有些人可能不是。
trying to protect our kids I want
我想尽一切努力保护我们的孩子。
widespread affluence through the
通过以下方式实现的普遍富裕
technological Revolution that's
那是一场技术革命。
happening and I don't want the people
事情正在发生，我不想让人们……
who create that to want to go somewhere
是谁创造了这种想要去某个地方的想法
else so you agree with me that we should
否则，你同意我的看法，我们应该
cut tax on wealth creators and raise tax
降低财富创造者的税收，提高税收
on wealth
关于财富
orders uh well broadly okay so let's do
订单，嗯，大致可以，那我们开始吧
it let's cut on people who are making
它让我们削减那些正在制造产品的人的开支。
let cut tax on people who are working
让我们给劳动人民减税
hard creating a good product making a
打造一款好产品并非易事。
good income and let's raise tax on
收入不错，那就提高税收吧。
people who are sitting there on 20 30 40
坐在那里的人有20、30、40
100 200 500 million pounds of assets
1亿、2亿、5亿英镑的资产
that they're going to give to their kids
他们打算把这些东西留给他们的孩子。
and they're going to use to dominate
他们将利用这一点来占据主导地位。
society and squeeze out the middle class
社会并挤压中产阶级。
so who's an example of someone who's
那么，谁能举例说明这样的人呢？
hoarding wealth she so his family owns a
她囤积财富，所以他的家族拥有……
tech company
科技公司
his wife's dad owns a tech compan which
他妻子的父亲拥有一家科技公司，
he will inherit and his kids will
他将继承遗产，他的孩子们也将继承遗产。
inherit his net worth that is quoted is
据称，他继承的净资产为
based upon his wife's but that company
根据他妻子的说法，但那家公司
already exists yeah it's created now
是的，它已经存在了，现在已经创建好了。
yeah it's worth billions but they they
是的，它价值数十亿美元，但是他们
have to reinvent that business every two
每两年就得对这项业务进行一次彻底的改革。
years like it's a so you think that the
多年来，就像这样，所以你认为
reason you think that if R's
你认为如果 R 的
father-in-law stopped managing the
岳父停止管理
company it would be valueless no I think
我认为，如果公司成立，那将毫无价值。
it it it hires hundreds of thousands of
它雇佣了数十万人
people and it's you know it's a big
人们，你知道，这是一个很大的问题。
company I don't know a lot about that
我对那家公司了解不多。
particular company but I know it's a
我知道是哪家公司，但我知道它是……
tech company Steve Jobs died okay is
科技公司史蒂夫·乔布斯去世了，这还好吗？
Apple valueless no let's not pretend
苹果毫无价值，不，我们别假装了。
that these creators are the sole reason
这些创作者是唯一的原因
these companies are are valuable sure
这些公司确实很有价值。
you know and what we're talking about in
你知道，以及我们正在谈论的是什么
many cases you know I was a Trader okay
很多情况下，你知道我以前是交易员，好吧。
and I'm worth a millions of quid and you
我身价百万英镑，而你
know now that is just assets I just own
现在我知道那只是我拥有的资产。
the assets I own the assets and that
我拥有的资产，以及这些资产。
will grow and it will grow and it will
它会增长，它会增长，它会
grow and it will grow and that will
它会成长，而且会继续成长，那将会
squeeze out and squeeze out and squeeze
挤出来，挤出来，再挤出来
out and squeeze out our viewers and I'll
出去，把我们的观众都挤出去，然后我就会
give that to my kids they don't even
把那东西给我的孩子们，他们根本不会要。
need to work they wouldn't even have
他们需要工作，否则他们甚至都没有。
even have to work they could just live
即使需要工作，他们也可以安享晚年。
on I could live on off the wealth is
我靠这笔财富就能生活。
that what you want do uh do you think
你想做什么？你觉得呢？
there are any opportunities for people
人们有哪些机会？
today like if you're born into a poor
今天，就像你出生在一个贫穷的家庭一样
family do you think it's possible that
家人，你们觉得有可能吗？
housing being and we can both agree
住房问题很糟糕，这一点我们都同意。
agree on that but do you think there are
同意这一点，但你认为有吗？
new opportunities that didn't exist for
以前不存在的新机遇
our parents or grandparents but they do
我们的父母或祖父母，但他们确实
exist for people today I think the
我认为，这些事物对当今的人们来说是存在的。
reality is for kids from poor
现实情况是，对于来自贫困家庭的孩子来说，情况更是如此。
backgrounds it is almost
背景几乎是
impossible to realistically get even
根本不可能真正扳回一城
Financial Security never mind wealth but
财务安全比财富更重要，但
why do you think you could do it I could
你为什么觉得你能做到？我能做到。
do it he could do it but you don't think
他能做到，但你不这么认为。
other people could do it well the first
其他人也能做得很好。
thing is I'm 38 now so I'm not not a kid
问题是我现在38岁了，不再是孩子了。
nowadays um listen I want every Mass
如今，嗯，听着，我想要每一次弥撒。
competition I've ever been in you know
你知道，这是我参加过的所有比赛中最棒的。
what I mean since I was a little kid I
我的意思是，从我还是个小孩子的时候起……
didn't even have a desk in my house you
我家连张桌子都没有。
know I was one of the top students at
我知道我曾是学校的顶尖学生之一。
LC and I still had to win my job by
LC和我仍然需要赢得我的工作。
cheating in a card game you know that's
在纸牌游戏中作弊，你知道那是……
the world that we live in I don't think
我认为我们所生活的世界并非如此。
that's a very replicable strategy and
这是一个非常容易复制的策略，
it's very easy for People Like Us who've
对于像我们这样的人来说，这非常容易。
made money to say oh AR we did it aren't
赚了钱就为了说“哦，AR我们做到了”，不是吗？
we great go out and you know you've said
我们出去玩很棒，你知道你已经说过
that you think if young people go and
你认为如果年轻人去……
work in Tech business they can get
在科技行业工作，他们可以获得
Financial Security if it was that easy
如果财务安全真那么容易就好了。
they'd all be doing it you know they're
你知道，他们都会这么做的。
not idiots our viewers are not idiots
我们的观众不是傻瓜，他们不是傻瓜。
they're trying trying they're trying
他们正在尝试，他们正在尝试
they want to find the good opportunities
他们想找到好的机会。
and they work listen I speak I'm the one
他们工作，听我说话，我就是那个人。
saying they're idiots you're the one who
说他们是白痴，其实是你自己。
says that they can't do it anymore I I
他们说他们再也做不了了。
see people do it all the time like I'm
我经常看到别人这样做，就像我一样
working in entrepreneurs people from
在创业者群体中工作的人
poor backgrounds and so so then so but
背景不好，诸如此类，但
then why are I VI you think all of our
那么，为什么我是 VI 你认为我们所有人
if it was that easy why is everybody not
如果真那么容易，为什么大家都不这么认为？
doing it I'll tell you why people aren't
做这件事之后，我会告诉你为什么人们不做。
doing it we went through a schooling
为此，我们接受了教育。
system that taught us how to get an
该系统教会了我们如何获得
office job okay right we went through a
办公室工作，好吧，我们经历过
schooling system to prepare us for a uh
教育体系让我们为……做好准备
a world that doesn't really exist
一个并不真正存在的世界
anymore which is the Industrial
不再是工业
Revolution world and you have to go
革命世界，你必须去
through a process of figuring out how it
通过一个弄清楚它如何运作的过程
really works so what what I see is the
确实有效，所以我看到的是
most often the people who do really well
通常情况下，那些表现非常出色的人
financially who are young they dropped
在经济方面，那些年轻人纷纷倒闭了。
out of school they dropped out of
他们辍学了。
University they started learning how to
大学期间，他们开始学习如何……
do things uh by doing their own research
他们通过自己做研究来做事
they start their own business or
他们开始创业或
co-found a business they take a very
他们共同创立了一家企业，他们非常
alternative path uh none of that was
其他途径？呃，那些都不是。
taught to us at school none of it's
学校里根本没教过我们这些。
taught to us in normal society we have a
正常社会教导我们，我们拥有……
school system that manufactures people
制造人才的学校系统
for a set of skills that are not
一套并非
particularly valuable anymore and we
现在尤其有价值了，而我们
also get them in debt for those skills
也让他们因为这些技能而背负债务。
um when people Sid step that and say
嗯，当人们 Sid 踩着那一步说
okay I'm not going to get into
好吧，我不想深入讨论。
University debt I'm just going to go off
大学债务，我打算就此打住
and actually figure out how the world
并真正弄清楚世界是如何运作的
works there's actually loads of
那里有很多工作机会
opportunities okay so I guess we've
机会还不错，所以我想我们有
sorted it then all our viewers need to
解决了这个问题，我们所有的观众都需要……
do is go and buy Dan's book become an
要做的就是去买丹的书，成为一名
entrepreneur and become a millionaire
创业并成为百万富翁
it's that easy why W you guys doing it
就这么简单，你们为什么要这么做？
to begin with they're idiots the viewers
首先，这些观众都是白痴。
are idiots they should be just being
他们都是白痴，他们应该只是……
more entrepreneurial it's as simple as
更具创业精神，其实很简单
that more entrepreneurial start a
更具创业精神的开端
business listen I come from East London
听着，我来自伦敦东区。
okay my friends can't feed their kids
我的朋友们连孩子都养不活。
okay and if it was as simple as going
好吧，如果事情像去那么简单的话。
out and be an entrepreneur I can bet you
我敢打赌，你肯定会出去创业的。
they would do it I can bet you they
我敢打赌他们会这么做。
would do it let us I'm sick of
会这么做，让我们……我受够了。
multi-millionaires telling kids who
千万富翁告诉孩子们谁
can't afford to turn the heating on you
你付不起开暖气的费用
just need to be more entrepreneurial
只需要更有创业精神。
it's sick Dan it's sick I this gives
丹，这太恶心了，这太恶心了，这让人很不舒服。
people mental illness it gives people
精神疾病会给人们带来痛苦
mental illness tell them the truth okay
精神疾病，告诉他们真相，好吗？
we your older generation we took the
我们，你们的老一辈，我们承担了
opportunities and now is almost
机会，现在几乎
impossible to out of poverty and don't
不可能摆脱贫困，而且也不要
just don't just stand up and wave you
别只是站起来挥手。
know your millions of pounds in front of
了解你面前的数百万英镑
them and say if you entrepreneurial like
告诉他们，如果你有创业精神，你会喜欢吗？
me you could do it you could have it
你可以做到，你可以拥有它
because it's sick because they can't
因为这病了，因为他们做不到
they can't feed their kids down they
他们没法喂养他们的孩子
can't turn the heating on don't tell
暖气打不开，别说了
them to be more entrepreneurial fix the
让他们更有创业精神，解决这个问题
system that drives more and more and
驱动越来越多的系统
more of them into poverty every
更多的人陷入贫困
generation I find it very strange that
我觉得这一代人很奇怪。
you think it would be easier to fix the
你认为修复这个问题会更容易吗？
entire global economic system than to
整个全球经济体系比
start a business and fix your own
创业并解决自己的问题
personal economics the the thing that
个人经济学，那件事
the thing that I know that gives people
我知道的能给人带来什么的东西
mental health issues is feeling that
心理健康问题是指感觉……
they have no agency in their life that
他们在自己的生活中没有任何自主权。
they can't do anything your video where
他们对你的视频无能为力。
you talk about if you don't have a rich
你说如果你没有一个富有的
dad you're screwed there's no such thing
爸，你完蛋了，根本没有这种东西。
as meritocracy you're never going to be
作为精英制度，你永远不会……
successful to me if I had have come
如果我来过，对我来说就是成功的。
across your content at 19 20 years old I
在你的内容中，我19、20岁。
would have been screwed I was so I'm so
我本来就完蛋了，所以我……
glad that I came across people who said
很高兴遇到这样说的人。
Daniel you weren't born into a a rich
丹尼尔，你并非生于富家。
family you don't have any Bank of mom
家里你没有任何银行账户
and dad but it's cheap and easier than
还有爸爸，但它便宜而且比……更容易
ever to start a business start by
想要创业，首先要从……开始
working for someone who's got a business
为一位拥有自己企业的人工作
then figure out what's your opportunity
然后弄清楚你的机会是什么。
and there's a way there is a way I've
而且还有办法，我有办法
actually worked with a lot of teenagers
实际上与很多青少年一起工作过
from poor backgrounds and one of the
出身贫寒，而且是其中之一
things we do is we tell them if it's
我们所做的就是告诉他们，如果是的话。
possible for someone else it is possible
对其他人来说，这是有可能的。
for you um I also worked in rural Uganda
嗯，我也曾在乌干达农村工作过。
um with a charity that did uh work with
嗯，和一个确实合作过的慈善机构
the poorest of the poor um one of the
最贫困的人，嗯，其中一个
most incredible things I ever saw was a
我见过的最不可思议的事情是
woman who started
开始
out literally picking food out of a
直接从食物中挑选食物
trash uh pile um and she was basically
垃圾堆，她基本上就是
sh they they shared with her how to
他们告诉她如何
start a chicken business which then
开办一家养鸡场，然后
ended up as a pig business which then
最终变成了一家养猪场，然后
ended up as a cattle business and she
最终她经营起了畜牧业，而她……
ended up uh making uh hiring 15 16
最终雇佣了15到16人。
people in her local community the power
她所在社区的人们的力量
of Entrepreneurship is that starting
创业的本质在于起步
with nothing you can
你什么都做不了
actually make improvements I'm not
实际上，我并没有做出任何改进。
saying everyone ends up as a millionaire
说每个人最终都会成为百万富翁
and I'm not saying everyone ends up uh
我并不是说每个人最终都会……
equal but I'm saying you can make
平等，但我的意思是你可以做到
improvements in your life and the thing
你生活中的改善以及这件事
that causes mental health issues is the
导致心理健康问题的因素是
feeling of having no agency or no
感觉自己没有自主权或无
control over your circumstances until
掌控自身处境直至……
the world changes the whole economic
世界格局改变了整个经济格局。
system I never told people don't work
我从没告诉过人们的系统不起作用
hard I never once said that never once
很难，我一次也没有说过那样的话。
said that never said that you said if
你说你从没说过你说过如果
your dad wasn't Rich you'll never be
你爸不富有，你永远也不会富有。
rich which is true in 99.9% of cases
富有，这在99.9%的情况下都是如此。
I've never told people don't work hard
我从未说过别人不要努力工作。
true 99% I've never told people don't
99% 属实，我从未告诉过别人不要这样做。
work hard okay and listen if you think
努力工作，听取你的意见。
that ugandans should be more
乌干达人应该更加……
entrepreneurial I've never been to
创业精神 我从未去过
Uganda maybe that's the problem out
乌干达或许就是问题所在
there maybe that's the problem in
也许这就是问题所在。
Nigeria maybe that's the problem in
尼日利亚或许就是问题所在。
India listen I've never said don't work
印度，听着，我从来没说过不要工作。
hard okay when I brought my book out
当我拿出书的时候，一切都很顺利。
last year the hardback I was at some
去年我买的那本精装本……
event and I come out I was drinking
活动结束后我出来了，当时我正在喝酒
London Bridge and uh I come out late it
伦敦桥，呃，我出来晚了。
was like it was like 1:00 a.m. and um
当时大概是凌晨一点，嗯……
some guy come up to me when I was
我当时正要离开的时候，有个男的走过来跟我搭讪。
unlocking my bike some guy from
帮我解锁自行车的，一个家伙
Newcastle which is the northeast of
纽卡斯尔位于东北部
England it's this quite a poor town
这是英格兰一个相当贫穷的小镇。
there's a lot of workingclass people
有很多工人阶级人士
there and um he said I've been watching
他说，我一直在观察
you on
你
YouTube and um I love your stuff and um
YouTube，嗯，我喜欢你的作品，嗯
this guy started crying this guy start
这家伙开始哭了，这家伙开始
crying on the street right in front of
在街上当着……的面哭泣
me he's like I work so hard Gary I work
他就像在说，我工作那么努力，加里，我工作
two jobs um my mom's sick and I'm trying
我同时做两份工作，嗯，我妈妈生病了，我正在努力。
to help I'm trying to support and and I
为了帮忙，我正在努力支持，而且我
don't understand why and and I'm sorry
我不明白为什么，我很抱歉。
that I'm
我是
crying but nobody ever told me that it
哭了，但从来没有人告诉我这一点
wasn't my fault before that's what he
以前那不是我的错，那是他的说法。
said to me okay and listen listen I
他对我说，好吧，听着，听着，
believe 100% aspiration ambition
相信100%的抱负和雄心壮志
entrepreneurial spirit I would never say
我绝不会说自己有创业精神。
see a kid that has that and say turn it
看到有孩子拿着那个东西，就说把它转过来。
off okay but the flip side of your if
好吧，但另一方面，如果你
you just work hard enough you can make
只要你足够努力，你就能赚到
it is if you didn't make it it's because
如果你没成功，那是因为
you didn't work hard enough and it's
你不够努力，而且……
your fault and I would like you to sit
这是你的错，请你坐下。
and think very hard before you send that
发送之前一定要仔细考虑。
message to young men and young women in
致年轻男女的信息
our
我们的
society meritocracy doesn't mean that
社会精英制度并不意味着
everyone uh ends up with the same result
每个人最终都会得到相同的结果
what what I'm trying to what here's what
我到底想表达什么？这就是我想表达的。
I'm trying to achieve I'm trying to
我正在努力实现……我正在努力
achieve the people who have ambition who
成就那些有抱负的人
can go for it are incentivized to do it
可以去做的人有动力去做。
and incentivized to build jobs and build
并有动力去创造就业机会和建设
companies about the ones that just want
关于那些只想……的公司
to work hard and have a good family and
努力工作，拥有一个幸福的家庭
take care of them and have a home and be
照顾他们，给他们一个家，并且……
able to turn the heating on and be able
能够打开暖气并且能够
to Financial Security they need to work
为了获得财务保障，他们需要努力工作。
for business don't they they need to
为了生意，他们难道不需要吗？
work for you yeah P they need to work
为你工作，是的，他们需要工作
they need to work for a business some
他们需要为一家企业工作一段时间。
business right if someone doesn't create
如果有人不创造，那么商业权利就无从谈起。
that business then where do they work
那家公司，他们在哪里工作？
for we now have by the way we now have
因为我们现在有，顺便说一下，我们现在有
11% of 11% of working age people are now
11% 的劳动年龄人口现在
declared too sick to work right we have
我们已经宣布病重无法工作。
a huge problem in the UK we also have
英国也存在一个巨大的问题，我们也有。
25% of uh people who are working age
25% 的劳动年龄人口
don't work uh it's one in seven men
不行，呃，七分之一的男人
don't work work at all do you think
根本不工作，你觉得呢？
they're lazy Dan I think the system is
他们很懒，丹，我觉得这个系统是
collapsing do you think think the system
你认为系统崩溃了吗？
is average British American working is
平均而言，英美两国工人是
lazy what I think is happening is that
懒惰，我认为发生的事情是……
the technology companies are totally
科技公司完全
transforming and disrupting everything
改变和颠覆一切
um and what happened is around the
嗯，事情大概是这样的……
post-war era we had good jobs we had um
战后时期，我们有很多好工作，我们……
you could work in a local thing what's
你可以参与当地的某个项目，那是什么？
happening now is that jobs are going to
现在的情况是，工作岗位将会减少。
the Philippines they're going to uh
他们要去菲律宾……
techn technology does three things it
科技做三件事：
makes jobs more simple which makes them
使工作更简单，从而使它们
replaceable
可更换
it makes jobs Global where you can move
它创造了全球性的工作机会，你可以搬到那里。
them to anywhere else and then
将它们送到其他任何地方，然后
ultimately it automates the job Al
最终它实现了人工智能工作的自动化。
together and gets rid of it uh through
一起把它除掉，呃，通过
code and software and what's really
代码和软件，以及真正重要的东西
going on in the last especially 5 years
尤其是在过去五年里发生的事情
since the pandemic is technology has
自疫情爆发以来，科技已经……
decimated the existing systems uh that
摧毁了现有的系统，呃……
we all relied upon when we grew up and
我们成长过程中都依赖过它，
when I say the uh education system isn't
我说教育系统不是
really working it's still pretending
实际上还在运作，只是在假装而已。
that there are office jobs available for
有办公室工作机会
people when they graduate and it's still
人们毕业的时候，仍然
pretending that there's like 1950
假装回到了1950年
scenarios available when actually my
当实际上我的场景可用时
kids are going to be disrupted by AI
人工智能将对孩子们的生活产生深远影响。
everyone's kids are going to be
每个人的孩子都会是
disrupted by AI um you know these sorts
人工智能带来的冲击，你知道的，就是这类事情
of things are the are the things that
事物是那些……
really we we also need to be talking
我们确实也需要谈谈。
about to all the founders and small
关于所有创始人和小
business owners listening I think you
各位企业主，我想你们……
need to hear this it's an update from my
需要听听这个，这是我的最新消息。
sponsor Fiverr they've just launched
赞助商 Fiverr，他们刚刚推出
something called Fiverr go and in short
一个叫做 Fiverr 的东西，简而言之
it's a huge game changer for you and
这对你来说将是一个巨大的改变，而且
your team it's a tool that's been
你的团队，这是一个已经存在的工具
created to help Freelancers train and
旨在帮助自由职业者进行培训和
control a personalized AI tool specific
控制一个特定的个性化人工智能工具
to them and in their style which means
对他们来说，以他们的风格来说，这意味着
that fiver Freelancers and their clients
那五个自由职业者及其客户
can now generate unique work almost
现在几乎可以创作出独一无二的作品
instantly purely by combining their own
仅通过结合他们自身的特性，就能立即产生效果。
unique style of freelance Talent with
具有独特风格的自由职业人才
personalized AI technology the big
个性化人工智能技术大爆发
unlock for me here is time and getting
对我来说，解锁的时机已经到了。
more of it back what might have taken me
更多的事情让我意识到，这可能要付出我的代价。
a few days or a week can now be done in
现在几天或一周的时间就可以完成了。
seconds with five ago you get what you
几秒钟前，五分钟后，你得到了你想要的
want and you get it straight away and if
想要的话，马上就能得到；如果
you need tweaks the original Talent is
你需要对原版《天赋》进行一些调整。
on hand for fine
手头有精美的
fivo is already available across 60
fivo 已在 60 个国家/地区推出
categories and that number is growing
类别数量还在不断增长
rapidly if it's something you'd like to
如果你想的话，可以尽快。
tap into head to fiver.com diary now and
现在就去 fiver.com 日记网站看看吧！
explore fiveo use code diary for 10% off
探索 Fiveo，使用优惠码 diary 可享 10% 折扣
your first order this is the moment
这是你的第一笔订单
where AI superpower meets human talent I
当人工智能的超能力与人类的才能相遇
I want to take this back to a point you
我想把话题拉回到你之前提到的那个点。
were talking about earlier which is
我们之前谈到的是……
about personal agency because I would
关于个人能动性，因为我会
like you Daniel to give the counter to
就像你丹尼尔一样，把反击的机会给了
your own argument because I want to make
请你提出自己的论点，因为我想提出
sure when we're talking about solutions
当然，当我们在谈论解决方案时。
to this problem start a business be
解决这个问题，可以创业。
entrepreneurial you can also understand
创业精神，你也能理解
how that might that works for people
这对人们来说可能有效吗？
with our brains and our mindset and
凭借我们的大脑和思维模式
whatever we had that made us do that our
无论我们当时拥有什么，促使我们那样做……
risk appetite our trauma whatever it
风险偏好，我们的创伤，无论它如何
might be but not everybody is wide in
或许如此，但并非每个人都胸襟宽广。
such a way so that's not necessarily the
这样一来，就不一定是……
best solution for and also we sit here
最佳解决方案，我们也坐在这里
with a bit of hindsight bias where we we
事后看来，我们难免会有些偏见。
were lucky and it worked out for us but
我们很幸运，事情最终对我们有利。
when you look at the stats around
当你查看相关统计数据时
businesses succeeding what you know the
企业成功的关键在于你所了解的
stat it's like 90% of businesses fail so
统计数据显示，大约90%的企业都会倒闭。
most of them are failing
他们中的大多数都失败了。
the ones that emerge from that people
从这些人中涌现出来的人
like me then we have a bias where we go
像我这样的人，我们对去哪里会有偏见。
well it work for us you do it too I
这对我们来说很有效，你们也可以这样做。
don't come from money so I have the same
我不是出身富裕家庭，所以我的情况也一样。
bias like I watched well I've I've built
偏见就像我观察到的那样，嗯，我已经建立了
I've built from scratch several times
我曾多次从零开始搭建项目。
because I got disrupted several times so
因为我多次被打断，所以
I've had to start with nothing several
我曾多次一无所有地开始。
times and build but you started type of
时间和建设，但你开始了某种类型
person right and when we say start from
正确的人，当我们说从……开始
nothing you actually started with a
实际上，你一开始并没有……
wealth of information and the whole game
丰富的信息和整个游戏
in building building Capital
在建筑资本方面
intellectual Capital having been through
知识资本经历了
it before being around that Mentor that
在接触那位导师之前，我就已经……
gave you the information also having
也给了你这些信息
access to a great market like having
能够进入像拥有这样庞大的市场。
access to a free market is is a big
进入自由市场是一个很大的优势。
thing I was born in Australia and I
我出生在澳大利亚，而且
moved to London at the peak of London's
在伦敦鼎盛时期搬到了伦敦
economic freedom so this can't be
经济自由，所以这不可能是
broadly applicable advice can it uh well
普遍适用的建议可以吗？嗯……
I think personal agency is broadly
我认为个人能动性涵盖范围很广
applicable the idea I got this friend of
我从这位朋友那里得到的想法是适用的
mine who woke up one day he went out
有一天，我儿子醒来后就出去了。
clubbing went out to a nightclub felt
去夜总会玩感觉
sick collapsed woke up and they had
生病晕倒了，醒来后发现他们已经
chopped off all four limbs right so uh
四肢都被砍掉了，对吧？
he had quadruple ampute um he was 19
他四肢截肢了，当时他19岁。
years old so he wakes up in bed and he
他几岁了，所以他醒来躺在床上，然后他
basically says I'm a quadruple ampute I
基本上就是说我是个四肢截肢者。
was I was fine 48 hours ago and now I'm
48小时前我还好好的，现在我……
a qu quadruple amputee and he decides to
一位四肢截肢者，他决定
make this decision in the in the
在……中做出这个决定
hospital room um that this is going to
医院病房，嗯，这将要……
be the best thing that ever happened to
成为有史以来最美好的事情
him and he makes that decision right
他做出了正确的决定。
even that is a consequence of his him
甚至那也是他造成的后果。
and his wiring what I'm trying to
以及他正在尝试做的接线
understand but he ended up he ended up
我明白，但他最终还是……
starting a clinic and it's a
开办一家诊所，而且是
multi-million dollar Clinic I mean it's
我的意思是，那是一家价值数百万美元的诊所。
incredible what can do the rule it's
难以置信，这条规则竟然能做到这样。
incredible what people but you only need
难以置信，但你只需要
a few people to succeed and the whole
少数人成功，以及整个
economy starts to improve we we actually
经济开始好转，我们实际上
in this UK we only at the peak of our
在英国，我们只处于巅峰时期
entrepreneurial like blitzing it where
创业精神就像闪电战一样，在
we're doing so well there was only
我们做得太好了，以至于只有
40,000 scale UPS 40,000 companies were
40,000 家 UPS 公司
creating jobs growth higher wages um
创造就业机会，促进增长，提高工资
investment into the company into the
对公司的投资
country you know it's only 1% of people
你知道，这个国家只有1%的人口。
who pay 30% of the taxes and 10% of
他们缴纳30%的税款和10%的税款
people who pay 60% of the taxes so you
那些缴纳60%税款的人，所以你
only need one in a 100 to actually
只需要百分之一就能成功
create something that's valuable and you
创造有价值的东西，你
get an extra 30% of taxes but so so that
额外征收30%的税，但也就这样了。
again is we need this one that advice
我们再次需要这个建议
for the what the people that end up
对于最终会变成什么样的人来说
getting into that 1% but who does
跻身那1%的行列，但谁又能做到呢？
everyone else work for like all jobs
其他人的工作都和所有工作一样。
growth comes from entrepreneurs so what
增长源于企业家，所以呢？
are you saying to those the 199% there
你是说给那199%的人听的吗？
are you saying go get a job well you you
你是说去找份工作吗？好吧，你
need wealth creators in the economy who
经济中需要财富创造者，他们
are building something like you take um
正在建造类似你服用的东西
gym shark people who work at gym shark
Gym Shark 的员工
they're super glad that this guy started
他们非常高兴这个人开始了
the company they're really happy that
公司方面他们真的很高兴
there's a company otherwise where would
否则还有一家公司会怎样？
they go what would they work where would
他们会去哪里？他们会在哪里工作？
they work so if Ben decides that he
它们确实有效，所以如果本决定他
doesn't want to start that company in
不想创办那家公司
the UK um or if he gets to 10 million
英国，或者如果他能达到1000万。
and
和
stops uh then all of those additional
然后就停止了所有这些额外的
jobs are are toast they're all gone so
工作全没了，全没了。
you encouraging the entrepreneurial
你鼓励创业
you're not encouraging everyone to
你并没有鼓励所有人这样做
become an entrepreneur you're saying
你是说要成为一名企业家？
those that have those that bias or that
那些抱有偏见的人，或者
I'm saying we need a system that
我的意思是，我们需要一个这样的系统：
encourages the people who can to do um
鼓励有能力的人去做这件事
and what about everybody else well every
那其他人呢？嗯，每个人
the flow on effect is that that creates
由此产生的连锁反应是：
jobs that creates wealth in the economy
创造经济财富的就业机会
um and free markets lift everybody up
自由市场让每个人都受益。
um free markets just means that
嗯，自由市场仅仅意味着……
everyone's trading with everyone um you
每个人都在和每个人交易，嗯，你
know it starts to like the whole thing I
我知道它开始喜欢上这一切了
mean it's it's just a tail as oldest
意思是说，它只是最古老的尾巴而已。
time as soon as economies are free and
一旦经济自由化，时间就会到来。
there are entrepreneurs starting things
有一些企业家正在创业。
and growing things everyone's life
以及每个人生活中不断生长的事物
improves everyone life get better um and
改善每个人的生活，让生活变得更好。
what's your what part of that do you
你负责哪一部分？
disagree with Gary I think it's it
我不同意加里的看法，我觉得就是这样。
doesn't work it doesn't work the only
不行，不行，只有
period listen the last 70 years are not
这段时间听着，过去70年并非如此。
normal Stephen the last 70 years are not
正常的斯蒂芬过去70年并非如此
normal the last 70 years in Europe and
过去70年欧洲的正常情况
the US where ordinary people like my dad
在美国，像我爸爸这样的普通人也生活在那里
could work for the post office on less
可以在邮局工作，收入可能更低。
than average wage and buy a house and
收入高于平均水平，还能买房。
support family it's not normal it's not
支持家人是不正常的，这不正常
normal in the world and it's not normal
这在世界上是正常的，但这并不正常。
in history most countries in the world
历史上，世界上大多数国家
do not like that most countries have a a
不喜欢大多数国家都有a
small Super Rich Elite and a very large
小规模的超级富豪精英和非常庞大的群体
group of extremely poor people that's
一群极其贫困的人
most of the country and it's most of
该国大部分地区，而且大部分地区
history in this country and it's most of
这个国家的历史，以及它的大部分
history in the US you know yeah we talk
你知道，在美国的历史，我们谈论它。
about Charles Dickens I read hard times
我读过查尔斯·狄更斯的《艰难时世》。
I read hard times and this is written in
我读过《艰难时世》，这是写在……
the 19th century when Britain was like
19世纪的英国就像
the industrial super of the whole world
全世界的工业巨头
and at the time the government was
当时政府是
talking about should we tax these
讨论我们是否应该对这些征税
industrialists and the industrialists
实业家和实业家
were saying if you tax us we'll throw
我们说，如果你们向我们征税，我们就扔掉
our factories into the sea and it just
我们的工厂都建在海边，仅此而已。
reminds me you know the only time we've
这让我想起你知道我们唯一一次……
ever really been able to provide decent
真的能够提供体面的服务吗？
living conditions for ordinary working
普通工人的生活条件
people was the period after the war
战后时期的人们
where we massively redistributed wealth
我们大规模地重新分配了财富。
and and now we're losing that that
而现在我们正在失去这一点。
holding of wealth in of the middle class
中产阶级的财富持有情况
can you acknowledge though that that was
你能承认那是吗？
a completely different time as it
这是一个完全不同的时代。
relates to being able to it was a
指的是能够做到这一点
different time but you
不同的时代，但你
I could you know of techy Nigeria today
我今天能了解一下尼日利亚的科技圈吗？
Brazil today the UK 300 years ago France
今天的巴西，就像300年前的英国，就像法国。
200 years ago there is only one specific
200年前只有一个特定的例子。
time that we have ever successfully
我们迄今为止最成功的一次
provided broad living standards for
为……提供了广泛的生活水平
ordinary people and it was a period of
普通人，那是一个……时期
time we protected a broadly equal wealth
在我们保护大致平等财富的时代
distribution and tax the rich at very
对富人进行分配和征税非常严格
high rates and you can acknowledge that
高利率，你可以承认这一点。
that's extremely hard to do because the
这非常难做到，因为
nature of the economy 100% 100 that's
经济的本质 100% 100% 就是这样
the reason why all of our grandparents
我们所有祖父母的原因
and our great-grandparents and our great
还有我们的曾祖父母和我们的曾祖父母
great grandparents lived in poverty and
曾祖父母生活贫困，
that's why I know I'm probably going to
这就是为什么我知道我可能会……
lose and that's why I bet on the economy
输了，所以我才押注经济。
getting worse and that's why I know
情况越来越糟，所以我知道
poverty is going to increase because it
贫困将会加剧，因为……
was extremely difficult to get the
获得该数据极其困难
unusually fair share for ordinary
普通人异常公平的份额
working people and I know we're losing
劳动人民，我知道我们正在失去
the argument and I know that farage will
这场争论，我知道法拉奇会
win and I know that Trump will win and I
我知道特朗普会赢，而且我知道他会赢。
know that and I know that things will
我知道这一点，我也知道事情会如何发展。
get worse I don't think I'm going to win
情况再恶化，我觉得我就赢不了了。
so if you if you know you're promoting a
所以，如果你知道你正在推广一个
a strategy that is not going to work and
这是一个行不通的策略。
it sounds like you think is
听起来你觉得是
incredibly almost impossible then why
那为什么呢？这简直难以置信，几乎不可能。
would you not be more practical in your
你难道不应该更务实一些吗？
solution Stephen if it was impossible I
斯蒂芬，如果这不可能的话，我的解决方案是……
wouldn't be here think it's possible of
不会在这里，认为这有可能
course it's possible of course it's
当然有可能，当然可以。
possible but you believe you're not
有可能，但你认为自己不可能。
going to win I'm a betting man Steve I'm
我肯定会赢，我是个爱打赌的人，史蒂夫，我是
a betting man I put my bets on you know
我赌徒，我把赌注押在他身上，你知道的。
I am if I get okay look okay so my
如果我看起来没问题，那我就没事了，所以我的
YouTube channel is growing really really
YouTube频道发展得非常非常快
quickly and you know I'm obviously like
很快，你知道我显然就像
starting a bit of a movement and there's
开始发起一场小小的运动，而且还有……
a lot of political support and if it
获得大量政治支持，如果
keeps growing we'll get more political
持续增长，我们将变得更加政治化。
support at the end of the day I'm trying
最后我还是想提供支持。
to tax the richest and most powerful
对最富有和最有权势的人征税
people in the world and most of these
世界上的大多数人，以及其中的大多数人
people will come out and attack me and
人们会出来攻击我，
they'll try and stop me and I do not
他们会想方设法阻止我，但我不会。
have billions of pounds hundreds of
拥有数十亿英镑的数百
millions of pounds to use to support my
数百万英镑用于支持我的
YouTube channel I'm counting on ordinary
YouTube频道“我指望普通人”
people like your viewers to support and
人们喜欢你的观众来支持你。
share my message now listen for most of
现在分享我的信息，请仔细聆听大部分内容。
history that has not worked and for most
历史经验表明，大多数情况下，这种做法行不通。
of History ordinary families live in
历史中的普通家庭生活
poverty I don't think it's impossible
我认为贫困并非不可能。
that we Ordinary People can win and get
我们普通人也能赢，也能获得成功
a fair share but I think it's worth
确实占了很大一部分，但我认为这是值得的。
fighting for Steve so I fight for it
我为史蒂夫而战，所以我也为他而战。
anyway he's he's right that for most of
总之，他说的没错，对大多数情况来说……
History you've had the super Elite and
历史上，你曾拥有超级精英和
then everyone else is down here and it's
然后其他人都在下面，就是这样。
massive wealth inequality is almost the
巨大的财富不平等几乎是
normal uh for the last five thousand
过去五千年都很正常
years and almost everywhere uh you've
多年来，几乎在所有地方，呃，你都
got kings queens dukes and peasants and
有国王、王后、公爵和农民，
surfs down there there have been
那里的海浪一直都很汹涌。
economic situations that have been
已经出现的经济形势
different uh Dubai is a really strange
迪拜真是个奇怪的地方。
situation it's a desert it's in
情况是，这是一片沙漠，它位于
inhospitable to live in it's the last
不适宜居住，这是最后一个
place in the world most people would
世界上大多数人会选择的地方
think or choose that they would want to
认为或选择他们想要
be and yet it's one of the most
是，但它也是最……之一
economically rich places in the world
世界经济富裕地区
right now they actually didn't start
实际上，他们现在还没开始。
with oil wealth they were able to borrow
凭借石油财富，他们得以借贷。
money to build Dubai but the low tax
建设迪拜需要资金，但税收却很低
environment has now attracted raed some
环境现在吸引了一些读者。
of the world's most talented people to
汇聚世界上最有才华的人才
go and build technology companies there
去那里创办科技公司。
and if you I don't know have you been
如果你不知道，你是否一直……
there recently I've been to Dubai few
最近我去过几次迪拜。
years AG now but I've been so at the
已经好几年了，但我一直都在那里
moment it is the most thriving
此刻它是最繁荣的
entrepreneurial community on Earth
地球上的创业社区
outside of the US but probably even
美国以外的地方，甚至可能更糟
rivaling the US that there are investors
与美国相比，也有投资者。
there's entrepreneurs and the wealth is
那里有企业家，财富也来源于此。
going through the roof um I've got two
简直要疯了，嗯，我有两个
friends who are personal trainers
朋友中有人是私人教练
fitness trainers one fitness trainer has
健身教练，其中一位健身教练有
decided to stop working uh more hours
决定停止加班
because he's hit 50 Grand a year and he
因为他年收入已经达到5万美元，而且他
now gets taxed at 40% so he's basically
现在他要缴纳40%的税，所以他基本上
decided he's going to earn right up to
他决定要一直赚到……
50,000 and then stop working and then
50,000，然后停止工作，然后
the other fitness trainer went to Dubai
另一位健身教练去了迪拜。
launched an online uh Fitness uh
推出了一项在线健身计划
community and has just bought a $350,000
社区，并且刚刚购买了一套价值 35 万美元的房产。
Ferrari uh and one entrepreneur is super
法拉利，还有一位企业家超级厉害。
pumped and super excited about building
非常激动，对建造工程感到无比兴奋
a business because he's not over taxed
因为他没有被过度征税，所以他经营一家企业。
the other entrepreneur has literally
另一位企业家实际上已经……
said I'm not willing to do this because
他说我不愿意这样做，因为
of how much I have to pay just want to
我只想知道我到底要付多少钱
be clear I've always campaigned for
明确地说，我一直都在为……而奔走呼吁
lower taxes on rich on working people
降低富人和劳动人民的税收
always always so but here's but here's
一直都是这样，但是，但是，这是……
the thing right if I was ask you you've
如果我问你，你说的没错吧？
just become one of the best selling
刚刚成为最畅销的书籍之一
authors in the country if your publisher
如果你的出版商是该国的作者，那么他们就是该国的作者。
came to you and said because you're in
来找你说因为你在
the top 1% of our authors we're going to
我们将选出我们作者中排名前 1% 的人。
Harve your royalties uh if you sign a
如果你签署一份协议，就可以获得你的版税。
second book with us you wouldn't sign a
你不会签第二本和我们合作的书吧？
second book with them you go to another
第二本书，你和他们一起去了另一个地方。
publisher who says we'll pay you more
出版商说我们会付你更多钱
royalties because you're so successful I
因为你太成功了，所以我要支付版税。
would have written this book for free
这本书我本来是免费写的。
then I would have written this book for
那样的话，我就会写这本书了。
free in fact the first time I got off of
事实上，我第一次下车时是免费的。
a deal I said I said don't pay me an
我说过，我说过不用付钱给我。
advance then give you royalties away why
预付版税，然后把版税白白送给你，为什么？
well because if what I'm saying all
因为如果我说的都是真的
right fine I'll give my royalties away
好吧，我把版税都捐出去。
I'll shut my YouTube channel down I'm
我会关闭我的YouTube频道。
saying we respond to incentives that if
我们说，我们会对激励措施做出反应，如果
your publisher if penguin came to you
如果企鹅出版社找上门来，那就是你的出版商了。
and said book number two you get half
还有那本书第二本，你得拿一半。
royalties because you're in the top 1%
因为你位列前 1%，所以可以获得版税。
would you sign with penguin or would you
你会和企鹅签约吗？还是你会……
go someone El from a 2 million job a
某人从一份价值200万美元的工作中走了出来
year to run a YouTube channel do you
你打算花一年时间运营一个YouTube频道吗？
think I do the work that I do for money
我认为我做这份工作是为了赚钱。
I'm not talking about that you do it for
我说的不是你做这件事的原因。
money I'm just saying if you had the
钱，我只是说如果你有钱的话
option to sign between two publishing
两个出版商之间签署协议的选项
contracts right and all things being
合同权利以及所有相关事宜
equal one's going to penalize you for
同等情况下，你会受到惩罚。
being in the to 1% and the other one's
跻身前1%之列，而另一个人的
going to reward you for being in the top
会奖励你名列前茅
1% would you you of course you would go
1%的人会去吗？当然会去。
with the normal like if all things being
一切如常，就像所有事情都是如此
equal you want to write a second book
也就是说，你想写第二本书
anyway it's the same for entrepreneurs
总之，对创业者来说也是一样的。
when entrepreneurs start companies we
当创业者创办公司时，我们
can either start them in high tax
可以让他们以高税收的方式开始。
economies or with a stroke of a pen
经济，或者只需一笔。
start them in low tax I think the rich
我认为富人应该从低税率开始。
world is going to have to start
世界终将开始
rethinking the fact that it allows
重新思考它允许的事实
people to very very wealthy people to
从普通人到非常非常富有的人
own enormous amounts of their physical
他们拥有大量的身体
wealth go live overseas and not pay tax
财富转移到海外，无需缴税。
I think that has to be Revisited for
我认为这需要重新审视。
sure because what you're saying is I
当然，因为你的意思是……
want the benefit of being able to sell
想要获得销售带来的好处
to the US market and the UK Market but I
针对美国市场和英国市场，但我
don't want the obligation of having to
不想承担这样的义务
pay us and UK taxes and you are correct
请支付我们和英国的税款，您说的没错。
that at the moment the US and UK
目前美国和英国
governments allow that and I think
政府允许这种情况发生，我认为
that's US taxes you on worldwide income
那是美国对你全球收入征收的税。
well only a small amount right so I
只有少量，对吧？
think that realistically I think that
我觉得，从现实角度来看，我认为……
the US and UK governments have to stop
美国和英国政府必须停止
that but the way I see it the US and UK
但依我看来，美国和英国
governments and increasing a lot of
政府和越来越多的
global governments are kind of being
全球各国政府某种程度上正在
bought up by the elites and you know we
被精英阶层买断，你知道我们
have ELO musk is basically the President
ELO乐队的马斯克基本上就是总统
right and we had richy sunak who father
对，我们还有里奇·苏纳克，他的父亲
was one of the richest men in the world
曾是世界上最富有的人之一
like if you're richy sunak who for our
比如，如果你是里奇·苏纳克，为了我们
American viewers was our prime minister
美国观众就是我们的总理
until very recently his father is one of
直到最近，他的父亲还是其中之一。
the richest men in the world he's got
他拥有世界上最富有的人。
700 million personal wealth he's going
他要去的地方有7亿美元个人财富。
to be making 3040 million pound passive
被动收入将达到30.4亿英镑。
income and you're getting paid 130 Grand
收入，你拿到了13万美元。
de to be prime minister when you're
当你……时，成为首相
making policy do you think maybe I'll
制定政策时，你认为我可能会……
ask my father-in-law at once you know
你立刻去问我岳父。
the fact is what you're seeing here is
事实上，你现在看到的是……
if you allow the rich I'm I'm never ever
如果你允许富人，我永远不会
against entrepreneurship I'm not against
我并不反对创业。
people getting rich if you allow the
如果你允许人们致富，那么……
rich to get richer and richer and richer
越来越富有，越来越富有，越来越富有
they squeeze the middle class and they
他们挤压中产阶级，而且
squeeze the poor class out of things
榨干穷人的利益
like housing of things like space in
比如住房空间之类的东西
cities of things like energy and of
城市，例如能源和……
things like owning a sharing government
比如拥有一个共享的政府
and media do you acknowledge that
媒体，你们是否承认这一点？
countries that adopt a anti-ri big
采取反欺诈措施的国家
government approach tend to collapse
政府的做法往往会失败
what like like this country in the
这个国家就像……
60s we needed a US bailout we needed an
60年代我们需要美国的救助，我们需要……
IMF bailout in 1976 but the US did the
1976年国际货币基金组织出手救助，但美国却……
same thing the US had even higher taxes
同样的情况，美国的税收甚至更高。
than us we we basically like you take
比我们，我们基本上就像你一样
you take all the countries that where
你把所有那些国家都列出来
the government becomes big they meddle
政府规模越大，他们就越会干预政治。
with your life they're involved in every
他们参与你生活的方方面面。
decision right half the economy I mean
我的意思是，正确的决定关乎半个经济体。
here's one other the things this period
这是这段时间发生的另一件事。
is known as the Golden Age of capitalism
被称为资本主义的黄金时代
it's the period of time when which
这是指以下时间段：
period thisi 50 years off the second
这段时期比第二段晚了50年。
world war oh it's the Golden Age of
世界大战，哦，那是黄金时代
middle class to be middle class you
成为中产阶级
don't care about the middle class no no
不在乎中产阶级，不不
of course I do the the but the 70 years
当然，我确实做了，但是那70年
after the World War II yeah where the
二战后，是的，在哪里？
government sold off all of its houses to
政府将所有房屋都卖给了
middle class people so we got housing
中产阶级，所以我们有住房
wealth but you can only do that trick
拥有财富，但你只能用那种伎俩。
once right so you can only sell off all
一旦正确，你就可以全部卖掉。
the houses to everyone once which is why
房子曾经属于每个人，这就是为什么
all the Baby Boomers own them well the
所有婴儿潮一代都拥有它们。
living s is collapsed after the houses
房屋倒塌后，居住区也随之坍塌。
were sold there was a long period where
在那里出售过很长时间，
the houses weren't sold between the
这些房子在……之间没有售出
second world war and the 80s pinpo
第二次世界大战和80年代的pinpo
living standards collapsing well I think
生活水平正在崩溃，我觉得是这样。
there's a few obviously big moments I
有几个显而易见的重要时刻，
think 2008 is a big moment I think Co is
我认为2008年是一个重要的时刻，我认为Co是
a big moment I think it's the 80s where
我认为一个重要的时刻是80年代，
you start to see the wealth distribution
你开始看到财富分配情况。
go what matters is actually the
真正重要的是
distribution itself so once you change
分发本身，所以一旦你改变了
the tax system it takes a bit of time
税收制度需要一些时间。
for the wealth distribution to change
财富分配发生变化
but once you start for me the big thing
但一旦你开始，对我来说，最重要的事就是……
is is the loss of wealth holding I want
这是持有财富的损失吗？我想要
ordinary families to be able to hold
普通家庭也能拥有
wealth and once you lose that you lose a
财富，一旦失去财富，你就失去了一切。
middle class and you will not find me a
中产阶级，你不会发现我……
single country in in the world now or
目前世界上只有一个国家或
the history of the world that has
世界历史已经
provided good broad living standards
提供了良好的生活水平
without allowing ordinary families to
不允许普通家庭这样做
own assets yeah I agree and take
拥有资产？是的，我同意并接受。
Singapore for example where everyone's
例如新加坡，那里每个人都……
encouraged to own properties they've got
鼓励他们拥有自己的房产
an amazing system in Singapore they've
新加坡的系统非常出色，他们……
taken this a massive government by the
政府采取了这一大规模行动。
way enormous government 25% of GDP they
政府规模庞大，占GDP的25%。
they own they own the houses they have a
他们拥有他们所拥有的房屋。
weal f they own all the houses they
如果他们拥有所有房屋，他们就会富有
don't own all the houses they have a a
他们并不拥有他们拥有的所有房屋。
sovereign wealth fund that circulates
流通中的主权财富基金
houses through they've they own the hous
他们拥有这些房子
they' solved they've solved Singapore
他们解决了，他们已经解决了新加坡问题。
owns the house they own the Singapore
他们拥有新加坡的房子
government owns an enormous share of the
政府拥有巨额股份
houses so do you think we should own
所以你认为我们应该拥有房子吗？
pension Pension funds people uh they
养老金，养老基金，人们，呃，他们
force not force their citizens but they
他们不强迫他们的公民，而是
uh direct their citizens into Home
引导他们的公民回家
Ownership you don't think Singapore and
所有权，你不认为新加坡和
government owns a large sh I just know
政府拥有大量船舶，我只知道
that the Singaporean government's only
新加坡政府唯一
25% of the economy but big sh of the
占经济总量的25%，但却是很大一部分
housing stock 75 the economy is I would
住房存量75，经济状况如何？我会
like to say by the way just to be really
顺便说一句，真的
clear I've never ever once advocated for
很明确，我从未提倡过
big government never a single time big
大政府从来没有一次是大的
government I want higher taxes on the
我希望政府提高税收。
wealth orders so we can tax wealth
财富秩序，以便我们能够对财富征税。
creators and working people less I don't
创作者和劳动人民较少，我不这么认为。
want to Big A government I want our
我想要一个强大的政府，我想要我们的
viewers to have more money I want our
观众们，我希望我们能有更多钱。
viewers to have more money and also I
观众们会有更多的钱，而且我
want to tax those super rich so that
想对超级富豪征税，以便
they stop squeezing ordinary families
他们停止压榨普通家庭
out of asset ownership it just yeah it
脱离资产所有权，就是这样。
see it it seems like an obvious solution
你看，这似乎是一个显而易见的解决方案。
it seems like yeah it's good solution it
看起来确实是个不错的解决方案。
seems like like hey who's got the money
感觉就像在问：嘿，谁有钱？
rich people not the money the assets the
富有的人不是指拥有金钱，而是指拥有资产。
asset who's got the assets rich people
拥有资产的富人
then let's just take them off them and
那我们就把它们取下来吧。
no no no I don't want I don't want to
不不不，我不要，我不要
redistribute I'm I'm I am the only
重新分配 我 我 我 我是唯一
person in this table anti-
这张桌子上的人反对
redistribution because the
重新分配，因为
redistribution is happening in front of
重新分配正在前面发生
our eyes the middle class is losing its
我们的眼睛，中产阶级正在失去它
assets government is losing its assets
政府资产正在流失。
those assets are being accumulated by
这些资产正在通过以下方式积累：
the rich I want to stop the
我想阻止富人
redistribution please please I'm I am
请重新分发，谢谢，我就是。
the most anti- rist redistribution
最反基督教的再分配
person in this game we need to stop the
在这个游戏中，我们需要阻止这个人。
redistribu of wealth away from ordinary
将财富从普通阶层重新分配出去
British and American families so the
英国和美国家庭也是如此
difference is for me it's very simple
对我来说，区别很简单。
which is I really truly believe that
我真的深信这一点。
free markets and low governments and
自由市场和低政府
less taxes creates more wealth in the
税收越少，财富就越多。
middle and freedom for the Heron is
苍鹭的中间地带和自由是
death for the fishes if we have complete
如果我们完全
Freedom multi-millionaires like you and
像你这样的千万富翁和自由
me will get richer and richer and richer
我会越来越富有，越来越富有。
every year and we will squeeze out and
每年我们都会挤出市场。
we will eat the middle class ask you
我们将吞噬中产阶级，问问你
though if wealth inequality could be
然而，如果财富不平等能够得到解决的话
solved but everyone does worse is that a
问题解决了，但每个人都做得更糟，是这样吗？
good solu obviously not the whole reason
好的解决方案显然不是全部原因
I do this because I don't want Ordinary
我这样做是因为我不想平凡。
People toap into public this is about
人们纷纷公开谈论这件事。
people being able to feed their kids so
人们能够养活他们的孩子
wealth inequality is not the problem
财富不平等本身并不是问题所在。
it's collapsing living stand that's
这是摇摇欲坠的住所。
quite contorted I mean quite contorted
相当扭曲，我的意思是相当扭曲
Logic the problem isaps living standards
逻辑问题在于生活水平
I am somebody who has made millions of
我是一个赚了数百万美元的人
pounds by understanding the simple fact
通过理解这个简单的道理，就能获得收益。
that living standards are falling
生活水平正在下降
because of growing wealth INE equality
因为财富增长导致平等性降低。
so living standards if they were to
所以，如果他们的生活水平……
increase but they were super rich yeah
增长了，但他们本来就超级有钱，是的。
is that a problem I think you do need to
那是个问题吗？我觉得你确实需要解决这个问题。
be worried about us extremely wealthy
担心我们这些极其富有的人。
Elites yeah I think what's interesting
精英们，我觉得这很有意思。
you look at the the founding of the
你看看……的创立
United States these guys the founding of
美国这些人是建国之初的
the United States conceptually is really
美国在概念上确实是
based on these ideas of distribution of
基于这些分配理念
power that's why you have the president
这就是总统存在的意义——权力。
and the house and the Senate and you
还有众议院、参议院和你
have this independent Judiciary they're
他们拥有独立的司法机构
like we cannot allow power to become
就像我们不能允许权力变成……
concentrated because they came from a
因为它们来自……所以集中起来了
Europe which had extremely concentrated
欧洲曾是高度集中的地区。
power and extremely wealthy Elites and
权力和极其富有的精英阶层
extremely broad poverty so I think that
极其广泛的贫困，所以我认为
allowing a small group of Society to
允许社会中的一小部分人
increasingly monopolize power and wealth
日益垄断权力和财富
over time is obviously something we
随着时间的推移，这显然是我们……
should be worried about but primarily
应该担心的是，但主要是
the reason I worry about wealth
我担忧财富的原因
inequality is because I see and I bet on
不平等是因为我看到了，而且我赌了。
and I make money on the fact that it
我靠这个赚钱。
causes living standards to Fall by the
导致生活水平下降
way I I actually really agree with you
我其实非常同意你的观点。
and the founding fathers of the US they
以及美国的开国元勋们
did um especially around the 1900s they
确实，尤其是在1900年代左右。
did want to break up monopolies and
确实想要打破垄断，
break up monopolies was one of the big
打破垄断是其中一项重大举措。
things that um they did trust busting uh
他们做的那些事，嗯，破坏信任……
where they broke up Standard Oil and all
他们把标准石油公司拆分了等等
of those sorts of things one thing I do
在这类事情中，我做的一件事是……
really really see happening at the
真的真的看到了正在发生的事情
moment is that we have a stupid outdated
眼下我们面临的问题是，我们有一个愚蠢的过时的东西
definition of monopolies where we use
垄断的定义，其中我们使用
monopolies the same way they used it
他们使用垄断的方式与垄断的方式相同。
when they had the oil uh companies that
当他们拥有石油公司的时候
owned all the oil in the technology
拥有该技术领域的所有石油
World a monopoly is formed through an
世界范围内，垄断是通过……形成的。
ecosystem so Amazon for example owning
例如，亚马逊拥有的生态系统就是如此。
AWS and Audible and this and this and
AWS、Audible、这个、这个、还有
this and Whole Foods it creates a a
这一点以及全食超市都创造了一种
fortress that's almost impossible to um
几乎不可能攻克的堡垒
to compete with and Google owning
与谷歌竞争并拥有谷歌
YouTube and Gmail and all of this they
YouTube、Gmail以及所有这些
create these fortresses through
通过以下方式建造这些堡垒
ecosystems one of the things that I do
生态系统是我所做的事情之一。
think we need to look at is compulsory
我们认为需要考虑的是强制性的
breakup of big Tech once you hit a
一旦达到某个临界点，大型科技公司就会分崩离析。
certain time because it's very difficult
需要一段时间，因为这非常困难。
because do you know billionaires have
因为你知道亿万富翁们拥有
two big fears right keep them up at
两大恐惧，现在依然存在
night uh having nightmares number two is
晚上做噩梦的第二个原因是
high taxes number one is that startup
高税收是导致初创企业的第一大问题。
entrepreneur who disrupts their business
颠覆行业的企业家
and they want to kill that early you
他们想尽早除掉你
know Steve Jobs at 24 years old
认识24岁的史蒂夫·乔布斯
disrupted IBM um and Jeff Bezos
扰乱了IBM和杰夫·贝佐斯
disrupted Walmart so they are terrified
沃尔玛的运营受到了干扰，所以他们很害怕。
of entrepreneurs in the middle um and
中层企业家
they want to create government
他们想要建立政府
regulations to say hey you know what
规定说，嘿，你知道吗？
let's cap entrepreneurs at 10 million
让我们把创业者的数量上限设为1000万。
you can get to 10 million it's okay for
你可以达到1000万，这没问题。
us we're way past that point but Gary's
我们早就过了那个阶段了，但加里的
our guy because he's going to cap
我们的人选，因为他要封顶。
everyone I never said cap anyone at 10
我从来没说过任何人的上限是10。
million by the way what do you think
顺便问一下，一百万，你觉得怎么样？
will happen people stop as soon as you
事情会发生，人们会立刻停下来。
have wealth taxes people just give up
征收财富税，人们就放弃了。
they just don't want telling me our
他们就是不想告诉我我们的
viewers if if they said if they knew
如果观众说他们知道的话
they could build a 20 30 million SS
他们可以建造一座耗资2000万至3000万英镑的SS
ridiculous they knew they would have to
他们明知自己不得不这样做，这真是荒谬至极。
pay 20 if you if you're if you're worth
如果你值这个价，就付20。
30 million 1% above is 200 Grand a year
3000万，1%以上就是每年20万美元。
so if I said if you you can have a 30
所以如果我说如果你可以拥有30
million pound company TR just bear in
这家百万英镑的公司TR只是在承受
mind right you make 5% a year on your
记住，你每年能赚5%的利润。
wealth right so if you got 300 million
财富，对吧？比如说，如果你有3亿美元
pound company you're going to be making
你即将成立的这家公司，价值一英镑。
15 million pound a year and I'm turning
一年1500万英镑，我就要转身了
to you and I'm going to say you know
对你来说，我想说你知道的
you've got to pay 200 Grand a year on
你每年要付20万美元
your 50 million pound revenue and
您的5000万英镑收入和
they're going to say you know what I'm
他们会说，你知道我是什么吗？
not going to start a business I don't
我不会创业。
want to be worth 30 million quid this is
想身价3000万英镑，这就是
you know this is ridiculous you know
你知道这很荒谬，你知道吗？
nobody is going to say oh my God I don't
没人会说“哦，我的天哪，我没有”
want to be multi multimillionaire
想成为千万富翁
because in 20 years time I'll have to
因为20年后我将不得不
pay 1% taxes but most Traders most
缴纳 1% 的税，但大多数交易者……
Traders are earning what most people
交易员赚的钱和大多数人一样多。
earn in lifetime Traders can earn in a
终身收入 交易者可以在……中赚钱
year most Traders don't stop talk about
一年中，大多数交易员都在不停地谈论
that a lot in my book right so most
在我看来，这很重要，对吧？所以大多数
Traders just keep going entrepreneurs
交易员们继续创业
are the same that they're motivated to
他们的动机与此相同
keep going but when you have Wealth
继续前进，但当你拥有财富时
Advisors and investors saying do not
顾问和投资者表示不要
build a company in the UK because
在英国创办公司，因为
they're anti- wealth L I'm not trying to
他们反对财富。我不是想……
make the UK anti- wealth I'm not trying
让英国成为反财富国家？我不是在尝试。
to make the UK and anti wealth I think
我认为，要让英国摆脱财富主义的桎梏。
the UK and the US need to be looking at
英国和美国需要考虑……
a situation where you cannot allow
你不能允许的情况
people who own enormous businesses that
拥有庞大企业的人
sell to your country to live in Dubai to
卖掉你的钱，去迪拜生活。
live in the Cayman Islands and not pay
住在开曼群岛，无需付费
tax and I I don't think that's a
税收，我不认为那是……
controversial position I've got a
我持有一种有争议的立场
question for both of you which is if you
问你们俩一个问题，那就是：
are a young person and you're 18 years
你是个年轻人，你今年18岁
old now and that you're listening to
现在年纪大了，你正在听
this but your objective really is an
但你的真正目标是
individualistic one you want to get rich
你想致富的个人主义者
and you have a great future for you and
你前途无量。
your family like all all of us have been
你的家人和我们所有人一样，一直都是
able to do what would your advice be to
如果能够做到，您会给什么建议？
them Gary at this moment in time this is
此时此刻，加里是这样的
such a hard question I know Dan's angry
这个问题太难了，我知道丹很生气。
at me for what I put in my video how to
就我在视频里讲的内容对我进行批评
get rich um somebody came around to my
致富……嗯，有人来找我了。
house and asked me this other day
房子，还有前几天问我这个问题
obviously I get asked it a lot because
显然，我经常被问到这个问题，因为
stupidly I'm very public about the fact
愚蠢的是，我把这件事公开得非常清楚。
that I'm rich um what I did is not
我很有钱，嗯，我做的事并不是……
replicable what I did is not replicable
我所做的操作无法复现。
it's not I'm sorry I'm sorry but it's
不是“对不起，对不起”，而是……
not people always say why don't you
人们并非总是会问：你为什么不……
teach me to trade like it's hard it's
教我怎么交易，这很难啊
hard trading and it's dangerous and I
艰难的交易，而且很危险，我
think a lot of young men are getting
我认为很多年轻男性都得到了
sort of sold into trading and becoming
有点像是被卖给了交易行业，然后就变成了
gambling addicts um
赌瘾患者
you know work hard and I would I
你知道，努力工作我也会这么做。
wouldn't even say don't become an
甚至不会说不要成为
entrepr I've never ever said these
企业家 我从未说过这些
things work hard you know if you think
事情进展得很顺利，你知道，如果你这么想的话。
that you have an opportunity in Tech
你在科技领域有机会
entrepreneurship go for it understand
创业精神，放手去做，理解它
it's risky I think that sometimes this
我觉得这样做有风险，有时候这样
message just become an entrepreneur and
信息很简单，就是成为一名企业家。
you make it is a bit dangerous because I
你这样做有点危险，因为我
think most people who try to become
认为大多数试图成为
entrepreneurs fail and I think it's
创业者会失败，我认为这是常态。
super super dangerous the reality is and
现实情况非常非常危险。
you know maybe D like this maybe you
你知道，也许D喜欢这样，也许你
won't like this I think it is very very
我觉得你不会喜欢这个，这非常非常
difficult for a young man or a young
这对年轻人或年轻人来说很困难
woman from a poor family to become rich
一个出身贫寒的女人如何致富
and I think it's increasingly hard even
而且我觉得越来越难了
to just get those basics of Financial
只想掌握这些金融基础知识。
Security so listen obviously reduce your
所以，安全起见，显然要减少你的
spending if you can don't buy into this
如果可以的话，不要花钱，也不要参与这种活动。
like Balenciaga stay away from
像巴黎世家那种垃圾，离它远点。
that
那
but work hard study hard try to get a
但要努力工作，努力学习，争取获得……
good job but also understand we are
做得好，但也要明白我们是
shrinking the seats on the Lifeboat
缩小救生艇上的座位数量
that's what we're doing we used to allow
这就是我们正在做的，我们过去允许这样做。
50% to be secure then it's 40% then it's
为了安全起见，50% 就降到 40%，然后是……
30% then it's 20% you know you got
30% 就变成 20% 了，你知道的。
family in Nigeria if a young person from
如果一个年轻人来自尼日利亚的家庭
like shanty town in Nigeria I came to
就像我来到尼日利亚的贫民窟一样
you and said Stephen what could I do to
你和斯蒂芬说，我能做什么？
get rich you would have to say to him
你得跟他说，让他发财。
realistically listen you are in a
听着，你现在处在一个
difficult situation here you need to
这里情况很棘手，你需要……
work really really hard but if you are
非常非常努力，但如果你是
able to make enough money to to support
能够赚到足够的钱来支持
a family be proud of yourself what I
家人应该为自己感到骄傲，我
would actually say to them so yeah I
其实我会跟他们这么说，所以，是的，
have got family in Nigeria um for people
我在尼日利亚有家人，嗯，为了人们
that don't know I'm by Blood half
那些不知道我是半个血亲的人
Nigerian I would say to them that
我会对尼日利亚人说，
knowledge is really your life raft so
知识就是你的救生筏。
obviously there's a big Tech boom
显然，科技行业正在蓬勃发展。
happening in Nigeria which is liberating
尼日利亚正在发生解放性的事件
a lot of people from that situation so I
很多人都经历过那种情况，所以我
would try and tell them to get on the
会试着告诉他们上车
life raft that is like knowledge of this
就像拥有这种知识一样，救生筏也是一种救生工具。
new Revolution so from Nigeria you can
尼日利亚的新革命，你可以
learn to code and then the the great
学习编程，然后就是伟大的
thing now is that we're we literally
现在的问题是，我们实际上……
have actually this is quite interesting
这其实挺有意思的。
we're building a tech company in San
我们正在旧金山创办一家科技公司。
Francisco called flight cast it's live
弗朗西斯科打电话来说，飞行直播开始了
everyone can go look at at flight.com
大家都可以去flight.com网站查看。
and the lead developer oh and guest
还有首席开发人员，哦，还有嘉宾
radar the lead developer of guest radar
雷达是访客雷达的主要开发者
is a Nigerian guy but how many of those
他是尼日利亚人，但有多少这样的人呢？
jobs in the Nigerian Tech sector are
尼日利亚科技行业的就业机会包括：
going to kids that grew up in the shanty
去见那些在棚户区长大的孩子们
towns I have no idea cuz I worked in
我不认识那些城镇，因为我之前在那里工作。
people ask me tell me how to do what you
人们问我，告诉我该怎么做你做的事
did all right I worked in Canary Warf
我做得还不错，我在金丝雀码头工作。
it's in East London I could see the
它在伦敦东区，我能看到
building from my house going up there
从我家往上走的那栋楼
was not a single other kid from East
东区没有其他孩子。
London the whole time I was there do you
我在伦敦的那段时间，你一直都在那里吗？
know to Dan's point about this remote
我知道丹关于这个遥控器的观点。
work Revolution where like work now has
工作革命，就像现在的工作一样。
you can work from anywhere and in our
您可以在任何地方工作，并且在我们的
company third web San Francisco me some
旧金山第三方网络公司给我一些
of the stuff that we now have are in the
我们现在拥有的东西都在……
Philippines because they just have like
菲律宾，因为他们就像
great creatives there it's obviously
那里有很多优秀的创意人才，这一点显而易见。
more cost effective isn't this a huge
更具成本效益，这难道不是一个巨大的优势吗？
part of what's going on in our economy
这是我们经济中正在发生的事情的一部分
this this digitalization and this
这种数字化和这种
remotify B your workers in the
远程管理你的员工
Philippines very very well
菲律宾非常好
um most of these people they used to
嗯，这些人中的大多数过去……
have a half decent wage on office and
办公室工作能拿到一份还算体面的工资，
now they're locked in their bedrooms
现在他们都被锁在卧室里了。
barely paying the bills yeah um in the
勉强能付得起账单，嗯……
Philippines not in the Philippines the
菲律宾不在菲律宾
Philippine guys are balling out control
菲律宾小伙子们玩得太嗨了，简直无所不能。
no I'm saying the Philippines is booming
不，我的意思是菲律宾正在蓬勃发展。
at the moment so you think the average
目前来看，你认为平均水平
person in the Philippines is living a
菲律宾的某人正在生活
luxurious life have you if you uh what's
你是否过着奢华的生活？呃，那是什么？
happening at the moment do you think the
你认为目前正在发生的事情是……
average person in the Philippines is
菲律宾人的平均年龄是
living a luxurious life there is there
在那里过着奢华的生活
is this thing called remote foreign
这东西叫远程外国
workers and this is a huge boom and the
工人，而且这是一次巨大的繁荣，而且
economic the kidchen move to the
经济因素导致儿童搬迁
Philippines then it's great you get
那你去菲律宾真是太好了
great quality of life in the Philippines
菲律宾的生活质量很高。
you know when I looked at the thums of
你知道吗，当我看着大拇指的时候
Manila they should just get J they I
马尼拉他们应该直接拿下J他们我
don't know why they're not getting the
不知道他们为什么没收到
laptops out uh the the poverty in the
笔记本电脑……贫困……
Philippines is horrific I'm listen
菲律宾的情况糟透了，我听着呢。
Philippines a beautiful country an
菲律宾是一个美丽的国家
amazing country I love the Philippines
我爱菲律宾，一个美丽的国家！
number in there at at a rate that's
里面的数字以这样的速率增加
never what is the life like for your
永远不要去想你的生活究竟是什么样的。
average Filipino well would you agree
普通菲律宾人，你同意吗？
though that their economy is just
尽管他们的经济只是
getting flooded with money at the moment
目前正处于资金高峰期
like money is flowing in there money is
就像钱在源源不断地流入那里一样。
flowing in but it is not giving a good
水流进来了，但效果并不好。
quality of life your average Filipino
普通菲律宾人的生活质量
that's not true remote foreign workers
远程外籍员工的情况并非如此。
well we can remote foreign workers
我们可以远程雇佣外国工人。
Filipino viewers to tell us
菲律宾观众会告诉我们
what's can actually support the often
实际上，什么可以支持经常
support their en a look I don't know
支持他们，我不知道。
what the average wages in the phili just
费城的平均工资是多少？
to bring it back to this point though so
不过，还是回到这一点上来吧。
I wanted to know from Gary he said work
我想从加里那里了解情况，他说工作。
hard if you're a young guy listening to
如果你是一个正在听歌的年轻人，那就很难了。
this now um I was reading this really
我现在正在读这个
interesting article yesterday from the I
昨天我收到的一篇文章很有意思。
think it was from major newspaper
我认为它来自一家大型报纸。
talking about the lost boys and it goes
谈到迷失男孩，然后就……
to show that I think it's one in seven
为了表明我认为概率是七分之一。
young men that is at a working age now
现在正值工作年龄的年轻人
are out of work so there's lots of talk
大家都失业了，所以有很多闲言碎语。
around young men in particular and how
尤其是在年轻男性群体中，以及他们如何
they're struggling you'd say work hard
你会说他们很艰难，努力工作。
Gary You' say work hard no blena but the
加里，你说努力工作，没有布莱娜，但是
big thing the big thing is recognize the
最重要的是要认识到这一点。
situation that you're in and I would
你目前的处境，我会
encourage them to support my work and
鼓励他们支持我的工作；
follow my channel because the lifeboats
请关注我的频道，因为救生艇
are shrinking and trust me we're going
正在萎缩，相信我，我们会消失的
to get out kids in the lifeboats and we
把孩子们救上救生艇，我们
all know that all right and if those
大家都知道这一点，如果那些
life boates are shrinking if you don't
如果你不采取行动，救生艇的数量正在减少。
if you don't stop the from going
如果你不阻止这一切发生
down it is not you and you and me who
倒下的不是你，也不是你和我，是谁
are going to go down we will be fine if
如果要下降，我们会没事的
you don't fight the political fight I
你不参与政治斗争
guarantee you people like Daniel will so
我保证像丹尼尔这样的人会如此
you're saying that they should also get
你的意思是他们也应该得到
involved in the political fight you have
参与政治斗争的人有
to you have to that's what our
你必须这样做，这就是我们的
grandparents did Grand if they want to
祖父母如果愿意的话，可以做“Grand”这个称呼。
become millionaires like you and me and
像你我一样成为百万富翁
Dan well it sounds like Dan's got better
丹的情况听起来好多了。
advice for that than I do okay well I'm
对此我有什么建议吗？好吧，我……
going to ask Dan as well but I just
我也会问问丹，但我只是
wondering I'm wondering how your your
我想知道你怎么样了
advice ties into sort of
建议与某种……有关
like the young the young person who's
就像年轻人，那个年轻人
trying to liberate themselves from where
试图将自己从哪里解放出来
you came from or where I came from you
你来自哪里，或者我来自哪里？
know what I don't think I'm the guy to
我知道，我觉得我不是那个人。
say that man because you know I had this
说这话吧，因为你知道我曾经有过这种经历。
unusual gift from a young age I was very
从小我就收到了一份不同寻常的礼物，我非常喜欢它。
very very good at maths and I just
我数学非常好，而且我只是
followed that um and you know you know
然后，嗯，你知道，你知道
my sister she's a poet and she wrote a
我姐姐是一位诗人，她写了一首诗。
really successful Grime of musical about
非常成功的 Grime 音乐
DIY R's first album all right she comes
DIY R 的首张专辑《All Right She Comes》
from obviously the same family as me
显然和我来自同一家庭
poor family she works so hard she works
她家境贫寒，但她非常努力工作。
so so hard two degrees she can barely
太难了，两级学位她几乎都拿不到
pay the rent all right so I don't want
交房租没问题，所以我不想
to turn around to our young kids and say
转身对我们的孩子们说
well I've got this Talent follow your
嗯，我有这项天赋，跟着你走吧。
talent because it doesn't work Stephen
天赋，因为这行不通，斯蒂芬
true it doesn't work yeah wait my sister
确实不行，等等，我妹妹
does great work but financially for
工作做得很好，但经济上却……
young people following your passion
年轻人追随你的热情
following your talent unless you come
除非你来，否则就追随你的天赋吧
from Rich family realistically very very
来自富裕家庭，现实中非常非常
really works and I know it worked for
确实有效，我知道它对……有效。
the three of us at this table but let's
我们三个坐在这张桌子旁，但我们……
not pretend that everyone experiences
不要假装每个人都有这种经历
the same things that we experienced what
我们经历过同样的事情
would you say to that D and what's your
你会对那个D说什么？你的
answer I think there's two economies
我认为有两种经济体。
going on at the moment there's a dying
目前发生的事情是，有人正在垂死
economy which is the Industrial
工业经济
Revolution economy um and that is all
革命经济，嗯，就这些了。
the office jobs and the factory jobs and
办公室工作和工厂工作
all of that sort of stuff which is very
所有这些事情，都非常
much being automated away and moved
许多东西正在被自动化取代和转移。
globally um and at the same time there's
在全球范围内，与此同时还有
this new bubbling up digital economy um
这种正在蓬勃发展的新兴数字经济
which I'd call the entrepreneur economy
我称之为创业经济
or the digital economy um both of these
或者数字经济，嗯，两者兼而有之。
economies are kind of Co coexisting
经济体之间存在某种共存关系。
one's going like that one's going uh
一个像这样，另一个像这样，呃
like that um and if you want to be
就像那样，嗯，如果你想的话
economically successful you need to
经济上成功，你需要
stand next to the biggest piles of money
站在最大的钱堆旁边。
that you can um you know unfortunately
很遗憾，你可以……你知道的。
being a poet uh doesn't pay a lot of
当诗人收入并不高。
money and we all know that that's not a
金钱，我们都知道那不是……
surprise if you came from a very rich
如果你出身富裕家庭，那可能会让你感到惊讶。
family and you were a poet you'd
家人，你是一位诗人，你会
probably be one of the 60% who fell out
可能是那60%掉队的其中一员。
of a rich family uh as well um if you
出身富裕家庭，嗯，还有，嗯，如果你
want to be economically successful you
你想在经济上取得成功吗？
need to say what is the thing that's
需要说明一下，那东西是什么。
economically booming right now Gary saw
目前经济形势一片大好，加里看到了
the finance industry at that particular
金融行业在那个特定时期
time but if we actually look at the
时间，但如果我们仔细看看……
finance industry now it's in Decline um
金融业现在正处于衰退期。
and trading is being rep uh replaced by
交易正在被……取代
AI robots um people who worked in your
人工智能机器人，嗯，那些在你公司工作的人
career are going to be replaced by uh it
职业生涯将被它取代
systems that basically do similar jobs
基本执行类似任务的系统
it's going to be you know these things
你知道，这些事情
happen we're going through a massive uh
碰巧我们正在经历一场巨大的……呃
technological change but at the same
技术变革，但与此同时
time it's never been easier to learn
现在学习从未如此容易
skills for free uh on YouTube it's never
在 YouTube 上免费学习技能？从来没有过。
been easier to join communities where
加入社区变得更加容易
you can get mentoring and get support
你可以获得指导和支持
there are communities of angel investors
天使投资人社群也存在。
who do invest in in startups uh it's
谁会投资初创公司呢？嗯，是
never been cheaper or easier to start a
现在创业比以往任何时候都更便宜、更容易。
company there's never been more software
公司从未有过如此多的软件
and Technology to scale and grow you
以及用于扩展和发展的技术
know in just a in a short space of time
在很短的时间内就知道
I would say do what Gary's done Gary
我会说，学加里那样做吧，加里。
publishes online he's built a personal
他在网上发布了自己建立的个人网站。
brand he's attached it to a recurring
他将其与一个反复出现的品牌联系起来
Revenue model uh he's got yeah I also
收入模式，嗯，他有，是的，我也有。
worked for three for free for four years
为三家公司免费工作了四年
I'm not sure how replicable that is you
我不确定这种情况是否可复现。
know so build a personal brand attach it
知道这一点，就要打造个人品牌并加以利用。
to a business model that is that is
这是一种商业模式，即
where money is Flowing um these are
资金流向何处？嗯，这些是
these are positive things you can do we
这些都是你可以做的积极的事情
all have to play the cards we're dealt
我们都必须接受命运的安排，并尽力打好手中的牌。
you can always find someone who's done
你总能找到做过这件事的人。
better with better cards or someone
用更好的牌或者其他人会更好
who's been dealt better cards and you
谁的牌更好？还有你。
can always find someone who's been dealt
总能找到一个被分配到特定任务的人
worse a cards no matter who you are on
更糟糕的是，无论你是谁，牌都会很烂。
the planet there's someone better
地球上还有更好的人。
there's someone worse you have to play
还有比你更糟糕的对手。
the cards that you dealt you cannot sit
你发给你的牌，你不能坐下
around waiting for the economic system
围绕着等待经济体系
of the world to be changed you have to
要想改变世界，你必须
say you know what these are the cards I
你知道吗，这些是我手中的牌。
was born at this particular time in this
出生于此时此地
these circumstances these are my
这些情况，这些都是我的
strengths these are my weaknesses I'm
这些是我的优势，也是我的劣势。
going to play the cards that i' I've
我要打出我手里的牌。
dealt um personal agency is what gets
个人能动性才是关键所在。
people to feel good about their life to
让人们对自己的生活感到满意
make progress and as soon as you play
取得进展，并且一旦你开始玩
the victim mindset soon as you say oh
一旦你说“哦”，受害者心态就立刻出现了。
you know what the answer to all my
你知道我所有问题的答案是什么。
prayers is Gary's going to change the
祈祷加里会改变什么
system uh you're in serious trouble can
系统提示：你遇到严重麻烦了。
I just say one thing back on that um if
我只想就此回应一句，嗯……
we become a society of of individuals
我们变成了一个由个体组成的社会。
who think only individually and and
那些只考虑个人利益的人
never consider broader societal problems
从不考虑更广泛的社会问题
we will become a society that becomes
我们将成为一个这样的社会
unable to fix societal
无法修复社会问题
problems I'm somebody who has made
我是一个制造问题的人。
millions of pounds betting on the
数百万英镑押注于此
collapse of society the collapse of the
社会崩溃，崩溃
middle class um I don't want to be
中产阶级？嗯……我不想成为中产阶级。
giving stock tips on the Titanic okay I
给泰坦尼克号股票提供建议，好吧，我
I understand I understand that we live
我明白，我明白我们生活在
in individualized societies and and it's
在个体化的社会中，而且它是
not popular to say hey you need to
说“嘿，你需要……”并不受欢迎。
protect your Society um if you don't
如果你不保护你的社会，那就不要这样做。
protect your Society your Society is
保护你的社会，你的社会是
going to collapse and and the British
即将崩溃，还有英国人
public the American public have a choice
美国公众有选择权。
to make here here to protect these what
为了保护这些，在这里做什么？
do you want people to do I want them to
你想让人们做什么？我希望他们这样做。
get involved with watch my channel
参与观看我的频道
subscribe to my channel content on
订阅我的频道，获取更多内容
YouTube Instagram Tik Tok share it with
YouTube、Instagram、TikTok，分享给你的朋友们
your friends share it with your mom
你的朋友把它分享给你的妈妈
understand and then push for change push
理解之后，再推动变革
for change like our grandparents did
为了像我们祖父母那样做出改变
push the politicians to tax working
敦促政客们对劳动征税
people less and tax extremely wealthy
减少人口数量，并对极少数富人征税。
wealth orders more so vote for the
财富秩序更倾向于投票支持。
greens vote for whoever gives you that
绿党投票给任何能给你带来那种感觉的人。
whoever gives you your share of the PIP
不管是谁给你分配你的PIP份额
basic listen this is not football okay
听着，这不是足球，好吗？
I'm not here M of the GRE I'm here to
我不是来考GRE的，我是来……
protect the working class so that's
保护工人阶级，就是这样。
their sort of that would be their social
他们那种类型的社交
and sort of um political energy would be
而某种政治能量会是……
to stand up and fight but in their in
站起来反抗，但在他们之中
their personal lives are you telling
你在讲述他们的私生活吗？
them to start businesses take big risks
他们创业要承担巨大风险
work really hard go for it because they
努力奋斗，勇往直前，因为他们
can also I would defer to you guys on
我也可以把意见交给你们。
that you know I'm not a businessman I'm
你知道我不是商人，我是
an economist that's what I am you know I
我是一名经济学家，你知道的。
made my money by being an economist I'm
我靠当经济学家赚了钱。
a very very good Economist my
一位非常非常优秀的经济学家
predictions will be right people can go
预测会是正确的，人们可以走了
and watch my predictions at the
请关注我的预测。
beginning of covid I predicted the
新冠疫情初期，我曾预测过
entire Co crisis exactly correctly in
整个Co危机完全正确
May 2020 you know this is you know I'm
2020年5月，你知道这是，你知道我是
good at this I'm and listen I'm never
我擅长这个，而且听着，我从不
going to come here and say I'm a better
我要来这里说我更优秀
businessman than you and I don't I'm
比你我更像商人，我不是。
pretty sure that I'm not I'm a very very
我很确定我不是，我是一个非常非常
very good Economist this will happen is
一位非常优秀的经济学家认为，这种情况将会发生。
there something that I can do if I'm sat
如果我坐着，我可以做点什么。
here listening at home I understand
在家听着，我听懂了
everything you said I believe everything
你说的每一句话我都相信。
you said I I I believe that it's going
你说我相信它会……
to get worse for me do you think I
你觉得我的处境会变得更糟吗？
should still take responsibility of my
仍然应该承担我的责任
situation and fight to make my life
处境和奋斗，为了我的生活
richer better moreful 100% 100 100% cuz
更富有、更好、更富足 100% 100 100% 因为
you you know and I'm sure you know if
你，你知道，而且我相信你也知道如果
you're average British or American if
如果你是普通的英国人或美国人，
you don't do that you're not going to be
你不那样做，你就不会……
able to turn the heating on you have to
要打开暖气，你必须
do it you have to do it and I've never
去做吧，你必须去做，而我从未……
once you I think my opinions are often
一旦你认为我的观点经常
mischaracterized to being anti- ambition
被误解为反对野心
you've read my book do you think I'm
你读过我的书吗？你觉得我……
anti- ambition no I work my tits off to
反野心？不，我拼命工作
make money and I want every single young
赚钱，我希望每个年轻人都能赚钱。
person in this country to be able to
在这个国家，一个人能够
make money if they want to if that's
如果他们想赚钱，那就去赚钱吧。
what they want to work towards but we've
他们想要努力的方向，但我们已经有了
created a society where it's almost
创造了一个几乎
impossible for young listen I've been
对于年轻人来说，这是不可能的，我一直都在
there I've been at LC I've been at
我一直都在LC，我一直都在
Oxford I've been in the city I've been
牛津，我去过这座城市，我去过
in the media I've been in politics all
在媒体行业，我一直都涉足政坛。
all of the guys at the top are a bunch
所有那些高层都是一群人
of Rich idiots we are not allowing these
我们不允许这些有钱的傻瓜这样做。
smart kids from ordinary backgrounds to
来自普通背景的聪明孩子
get into those spaces why why do we
进入那些空间，为什么？为什么？
pretend we're not doing that do that I
假装我们没做那件事，做那件事，我
disagree with that you're talking about
我不同意你刚才说的。
two types of elite spaces Elite space of
两种类型的精英空间 精英空间
elite universities yeah and you're
精英大学，没错，你也是。
talking about the elite space of
谈论精英领域
derivatives trading there's the real
衍生品交易才是真正的
economy yeah where entrepreneurs do
经济，是的，企业家们在哪里？
their work then there's the first
然后是他们的第一个作品
derivative which is the banking system
衍生品，即银行系统
and then there's the second derivative
然后还有二阶导数。
which is rates Traders like yourself
这会给像您这样的交易者评分。
right these are these These are places
对，这些就是这些地方。
that normal people don't want to end up
普通人不想落得这样的下场
most normal people who grow up in normal
大多数在正常环境下长大的正常人
households don't uh wake up one day and
家庭不会突然有一天醒来，然后
say I want to be a rates Trader on a
假设我想成为一名利率交易员
double derivative of the economy making
经济的双重导数
bets most people want to start a
大多数人都想开始打赌
business that employs people and they
雇用员工的企业
want to grow that business and be
想发展壮大这项业务并成为
successful do you think that starting a
你认为创业成功吗？
business is a realistic High success
商业是一个现实且成功的行业。
probability chance of ordinary poor
普通穷人的概率
people becoming rich I I know that
我知道人们变得富有。
economies Thrive when entrepreneurs are
当企业家活跃时，经济才能繁荣发展。
active
积极的
and it's not just the entrepreneurs they
而且不仅仅是企业家们
create is our viewers can do and most of
创作是我们的观众可以做到的，而且大多数
them will end up rich you only need 1%
他们最终都会变得富有，你只需要1%就够了。
to improve the whole economy there's a
为了改善整体经济，需要……
really interesting stat that says
这项统计数据非常有趣，它表明
globally around 65% of ultra high net
全球约 65% 的超高净值人群
worth individuals are
有价值的人
self-made approximately 19% primarily
白手起家约占19%，主要
primarily inherited their wealth and
主要继承了他们的财富
about 16% inherited wealth but
约16%的财富为继承所得，但
significantly grew it through their own
他们通过自身努力实现了显著增长。
Ventures so 65% of the ultra high worth
风险投资占超高价值资产的 65%。
individuals globally are self-made does
全球个人都是白手起家的。
that not mean that if I want to become
但这并不意味着如果我想成为
an ultra high Networth person it's going
对于一位超级富豪来说，这将会……
to come down to listen we are just come
我们下来听听，我们刚到。
off the back of the golden age of
在黄金时代的背景下
capitalism when ordinary people like my
当像我这样的普通人身处资本主义之中时，资本主义就成了他们的问题。
dad you know I grew up in ilford it's in
爸爸，你知道我是在伊尔福德长大的，它就在……
East London it's a very immigrant area
东伦敦是一个移民人口非常集中的地区。
most of my friends I grew up with come
我从小一起长大的大多数朋友都来了
from Pakistani Indian immigrant
来自巴基斯坦印度移民
backgrounds they come over with nothing
他们的背景一无所有。
they worked really hard they made money
他们非常努力，赚到了钱。
they had their own assets we had a
他们有自己的资产，我们也有
period where Ordinary People could make
普通人也能有所作为的时期
money and could make wealth so obviously
金钱，以及由此产生的财富，显而易见。
we are now in a period where there are
我们现在正处于这样一个时期：
rich people who made money during that
那些在那段时间赚到钱的富人
period but it's over now I'm seeing
这段时间结束了，现在我看到了
ordinary people making money all the
普通人都在赚钱
time okay so you're telling our viewers
时间到了，所以你是要告诉我们的观众
they're idiots why are they not making
他们是白痴，为什么他们不做
money I'm not telling anyone they're an
钱，我不会告诉任何人，他们是……
idiot I'm saying that if it's that easy
我是说，如果真那么容易的话，那我就是个白痴。
okay all right fine go and buy Dan's
好吧，行，去买丹的
book read it and become a millionaire
读这本书，你就能成为百万富翁
because Dan thinks it's easy to become a
因为丹认为成为一名……很容易
millionaire being an entrepreneur but I
我是一名百万富翁，也是一名企业家，但我
suspect having not been an entrepreneur
怀疑他并非企业家
that most of the people who've read your
大多数读过你文章的人都这么认为。
book are not millionaires everything
书并非百万富翁的一切
you've touched has turned to Gold you
你触碰过的东西都变成了黄金。
turned yourself to Academia you got an
投身学术界，你得到了……
amazing qualification you turned
你拥有令人惊叹的资格。
yourself to banking you became 2 million
你自己通过银行业务赚到了200万美元。
a year you turned yourself to being a
一年来，你把自己变成了……
writer you become Sunday Times
你成为《星期日泰晤士报》的作家
bestseller you turn yourself to content
畅销书作家把自己变成内容创作者
creating you get 800,000 followers and
创建后你将获得 80 万粉丝，
you and now you sit there after all of
你，现在你却坐在那里，一切都结束了。
that evidence and say oh no it's all
那些证据，然后说哦不，全都这样了
over guys it's all I'm smart enough to
伙计们，这就是我唯一聪明到能做到的。
do it but you guys are not smart enough
去做吧，但你们不够聪明。
to do if if you think you can teach
如果你认为自己可以教书，那就去做吧
you've got your book if you think you
如果你认为你拥有这本书，那么你就拥有了它。
canach you say you're smart enough but
你说你足够聪明，但是
they're not smart enough I I wonder if
他们不够聪明，我想知道是否
um we do have a bit of an education
嗯，我们确实接受过一些教育。
problem at the at the heart of this
问题的核心在于此
because I was thinking about your sister
因为我一直在想你妹妹
and I was like right if I was the CEO of
我当时就想，如果我是CEO的话……
Gary's sister what would I do there's
加里的妹妹，我该怎么办？
two things I do right now the first is
我现在正在做的两件事，第一件事是……
okay where's where what what Marketplace
好的，市场在哪里？
is really valuing an ability to write
真正重视写作能力
and write an impactful way I go write
并以有影响力的方式写作。
you need to start an Instagram page
你需要创建一个 Instagram 页面
because I've seen what happened with J
因为我亲眼目睹了J的遭遇。
sh this guy's pulling in tens of
嘘，这家伙赚了几十万
millions a year because he took like you
每年数百万美元，因为他像你一样……
know nice words that were motivational
知道一些激励人心的美好话语。
poetic put them on there and I also
把它们诗意地放在那里，我也
YouTube needs to get to YouTube because
YouTube 需要回到 YouTube，因为
if she can talk like you then she's
如果她能像你一样说话，那她就是
going to do exceptionally well on
将会表现出色
YouTube as well um but the old there's
YouTube也一样，嗯，但是以前的那个地方……
not going to be a great economy
经济形势不会太好。
necessarily for someone who's doing
对于正在做某事的人来说，这是必不可少的。
poetry in many other places other than
除了……之外，诗歌在许多其他地方也有
one I'm saying is the internet but in
我说的其中之一就是互联网，但在
school we don't teach this there's no
学校不教这个，没有
YouTube class for YouTube and and it's
YouTube 课程，专为 YouTube 用户开设，而且它是
such a huge part of the economy I mean I
我的意思是，这在经济中占据了如此巨大的比例。
mean me and you have seen that it's
我的意思是，你已经看到了这一点。
there's been this decentralization of
这种去中心化现象已经出现。
media where the megaphone was growing at
媒体的影响力正在不断增强。
20% a year the me the megaphone was
每年20% 我拿着扩音器
people watching start a YouTube become
人们开始观看 YouTube 频道
ENT it's the Internet isn't e I'm not
ENT，互联网不是e，我不是
say works for most people stepen for
说对大多数人来说都有效，为此而努力
most people no it doesn't work it
大多数人都认为这行不通。
doesn't work why are we pretending it
行不通，我们为什么要假装行得通？
does but I what what I what I would say
确实如此，但我会说什么呢？我会说什么呢？
is if in school we taught young kids a
如果在学校里我们教小孩子一个
couple new things and we stopped
添置了几件新东西，我们就停了下来。
teaching them about Pythagoras's Theorem
教他们毕达哥拉斯定理
which by the way chat gbt is going to do
顺便一提，聊天GBT会这样做
for you with your eyes closed and we
闭上眼睛，我们为你而来
taught them about the new economy of the
向他们讲解了新的经济模式
internet about the ability to start a
互联网上关于创业能力的信息
shop and I it's crazy that I the school
商店和我，这太疯狂了，我竟然去了学校
system was designed in such a way where
系统设计的方式是这样的：
they put me in exclusion unit because I
他们把我关进了隔离病房，因为我
was so preoccupied with doing business
他当时一心扑在生意上。
deals at school and my Headmaster came
学校里发生了一些事情，我的校长来了。
on T National TV on what I lied to and
在T国家电视台，我谈到了我撒谎的事情。
said yeah we unexp beled him eventually
他说，是的，我们最终没能让他明白。
because he made the school so much money
因为他为学校赚了很多钱。
but the system was punishing me for
但这个制度却在惩罚我
Entre for entrepreneurship and it wasn't
创业精神，但并非如此
teaching me anything about the the new
教我任何关于新事物的事情
economy which is which is technology St
经济就是技术圣
do you think it matters if the
你认为这重要吗？
percentage of young people who are able
能够
to Achieve Financial Freedom and have a
实现财务自由并拥有
family is shrinking so do I think it
家庭规模在缩小，我也这么认为。
matters if the percentage of young
如果年轻人的比例很重要的话
people that are able
有能力的人
to are you saying attain wealth and have
你是说要获得财富并拥有
a family yeah Achieve Financial Freedom
一个家庭，是的，实现财务自由
and have a family I think that's a
组建家庭，我认为这就是……
really big problem listen I think that's
真是个大问题，听着，我觉得那就是……
a really big problem I agree I know
我同意，这确实是个大问题，我知道。
listen and I know you've got this
听着，我知道你能行。
podcast and I know you inspire young
播客，我知道你激励了年轻人
people and I think that's a good thing I
人们，我认为这是一件好事。
think it's a good thing that you inspire
我觉得你激励他人是一件好事。
young people to go out and work hard and
年轻人应该走出去努力工作
try and Achieve something but I'm an
尝试取得一些成就，但我是一个
economist and what I see is the
经济学家，我看到的是
percentage of young people who make it
成功人士的年轻人比例
shrinking and I think if you combine
缩小，而且我认为如果你结合
those two things you reach a really
这两件事你真的能做到
dangerous place because we go and tell
危险的地方，因为我们去告诉
the young people it's there for you to
年轻人，这就是你们的处境
start a business and at the same time
创办企业，同时
the number of people who make it is 10%
成功率是10%。
5% 2% 1% and there will always be that
5%、2%、1%，而且永远都会有这些。
one person who makes it there will
成功到达那里的人将
always be that Steven Bartley in every
永远是史蒂文·巴特利，无论何时何地
country in the world who's making it
世界上哪个国家正在制造它
through you know what I'm saying but the
虽然你知道我的意思，但是
systematic issue matters Stephen C can
系统性问题很重要，斯蒂芬·C 可以
we can we not change the education
我们无法改变教育
system so that when I was 16 and they
系统，所以当我16岁的时候，他们
threw me in the exclusion unit which
我被关进了隔离病房，
made me which would could so easily have
让我很容易就能……
made me think that I was a failure
这让我觉得自己是个失败者。
because my brothers who went Jason went
因为我的兄弟们去了杰森那里
to LSC okay and became very much like
对LSC来说没问题，而且变得非常像
you and now works in my company um
你现在在我们公司工作，嗯。
managing my investments he in that
他负责管理我的投资。
education system was rewarded so I sat
教育体系得到了奖励，所以我坐了下来。
there as a kid thinking rich and
小时候，我自认为很有钱。
successful my older brother Jason
我哥哥杰森很成功
because he can do maths and I thought
因为他会数学，所以我想
I'm going to be a failure because I like
我注定要失败，因为我喜欢
this thing called entrepreneurship and I
这件事叫做创业精神，而我
have ADHD so I can't pay attention in
我有注意力缺陷多动障碍，所以无法集中注意力。
lessons what I'm saying is if the
我的意思是，如果
education system was designed in such a
教育体系就是这样设计的。
way where people like me who were
像我这样的人，曾经是
entrepreneurial who were interested in
对创业感兴趣的人
the internet and couldn't stop playing
上网玩个不停，根本停不下来。
video games were clapped for and said oh
电子游戏赢得了掌声和赞叹声。
my God double down on that yeah um I
我的天啊，再加倍下注吧，嗯，我
think the net benefit when you think
思考时要考虑净收益。
about what the backbone of the economy
关于经济支柱是什么
is which is entrepreneurs starting
是那些创业者开始
businesses would be profound for this
企业对此将产生深远的影响。
country here yeah but that but but I I
这里是这个国家，是的，但是但是，但是我
think that I believe there needs to be
我认为有必要有
such a radical overhaul of our education
对我们的教育进行如此彻底的改革
system if we want to stand a chance of
如果我们想有机会，就必须建立这样的系统。
capitalizing on what the economy is
利用经济现状
today yeah I I think I think you could
今天，嗯，我想，我想你可以
probably change the education system in
可能会改变教育体系
a lot of ways that could improve it but
有很多方法可以改进它，但是
you're kind of changing the education
你正在改变教育方式。
system on the Titanic what my my
泰坦尼克号上的系统，我的天哪
perspective is I can tell you with a
从某种角度来说，我可以告诉你……
very very high rate of certainty if you
如果你有非常非常高的确定性，
don't fix this problem of the wealth
不要解决财富问题。
being sucked out of the middle class 95
被吸出中产阶级 95
98% of people will be in poverty in this
届时，98%的人将生活在贫困之中。
country in 70 years I agree with you
70年后，我同意你的看法。
this is the thing I agree that you can't
这是我同意你不能做的。
have a group of people at the very top
拥有一群最高层人员。
that own all the assets and all the
拥有所有资产和所有
money or else I mean it's going to come
钱，否则我的意思是，它就会来了。
from somewhere and I remember the day
不知从何而来，我记得那一天
that I printed off the jobseekers
我把求职者的名单打印了出来
allowance form when I was stealing
我偷东西时的零用钱单
Chicago town piz 10 years ago in my room
十年前我在芝加哥的房间里
in Mosside in Manchester I remember what
在曼彻斯特的莫赛德，我记得什么
it feels like to not have my parents
感觉就像失去了父母。
speaking to me to be have all these ccj
跟我说话是为了让我拥有所有这些 ccj
letters and baith letters on my desk and
我桌上有信件和两封信，
really have no answer how how to get out
真的不知道该怎么逃出去
of the situation to the point that I was
情况发展到我……的地步
like shoplifting I'd call the justy
就像商店行窃一样，我会报警。
driver and then trying to persuade him
司机，然后试图说服他
just to give me the food that was that
只是为了给我那些食物而已。
was that was 10 years ago for me so I I
那是我十年前的事了，所以我……
it's not I've not forgotten the the
不是的，我没有忘记。
those years of my life so I understand
我生命中的那些年，所以我明白
what it is to be in that situation and
身处那种境地会是什么感觉？
on an individual level I need need some
就我个人而言，我需要一些
answers because I'm not going to wait
答案，因为我不会再等了。
for these people in the
这些人真是操死了
parliament to fix my life for me so I
议会应该为我解决我的生活问题，所以我
need some individual answers and then I
需要一些个别答复，然后我
do also care about the bigger picture so
也要关注大局，所以
I'm not like here as someone that just
我不是那种会来这里的人，只是
wants to acrew loads of wealth myself of
想自己积累大量财富
course listen let's be honest no one
当然，听着，说实话，没人
like there's not many human beings that
好像没多少人是这样似的。
wouldn't like more money so I try and
我不想要更多钱，所以我尝试……
acknowledge that bias but what I'm the
承认这种偏见，但我是……
the the the big issue I have is is is
我最大的问题是……
how and from my personal experience as
如何以及根据我的个人经验
someone that now employs hundreds and
现在雇佣了数百名员工的人
hundreds and hundreds of people here in
这里有成百上千的人
London up in Manchester in our offices I
我在伦敦曼彻斯特的办公室。
there are a set of things that would
有一系列事情会
make me leave this country if it became
如果它变成这样，就让我离开这个国家吧
increasingly less uh friendly to
对……越来越不友好
entrepreneurs I reckon if we come back
我认为，如果我们回归，企业家们会……
here in 5 years time I reckon I'll
我估计五年后我会在这里
employ 500 more people in the UK and
在英国再雇用500人，
actually as you look around this room
实际上，当你环顾这个房间时……
you can see the age of them these are
你可以看出它们的年代，这些都是
young people yeah um there are things
年轻人，嗯，有些事
you could do to make me not do that I
你可以做些什么来阻止我那样做？
mean it's probably worth pointing out
这意味着这一点可能值得指出。
that we're not taxing wealth and you're
我们不会对财富征税，而你
leaving the country anyway Stephen no I
无论如何都要离开这个国家，斯蒂芬，不，我
haven't left the country okay you're
你还没离开这个国家，好吧，你是
going I'm I'm a tax resident here I pay
我是这里的税务居民，我缴纳税款
my taxes here and I have zero intent in
我的税款在这里，我完全没有这方面的意图。
changing that I'm also on Dragon you
我也改了，我现在也在玩龙了
know so we're investing a lot of money
我知道，所以我们投入了很多资金。
in UK businesses but listen I want to
在英国企业中，但是听着，我想
raise I want to tax only high levels of
我希望只对高收入人群征税
wealth only high levels of wealth and
只有高水平的财富和财富
listen don't get me wrong I understand
别误会，我明白。
very rich people will complain and very
非常富有的人会抱怨，而且非常
rich people will say just like they did
有钱人会像他们以前那样说。
in Dickens I'm going to throw my
在狄更斯笔下，我要扔掉我的
businesses I'm going to throw my taxes
我要把税款投入到这些企业中。
my my businesses and my factories into
我的我的企业和我的工厂
the sea Stephen your viewers are here
大海，斯蒂芬，你的观众们在这里
you listen Steven your viewers are here
史蒂文，你听着，你的观众都在这里。
you are a very wealthy person they are
你是一个非常富有的人，他们是
are paying 20 30 40 50% you should be
你应该支付 20%、30%、40% 或 50% 的费用。
paying your fair share Stephen you
斯蒂芬，你该支付你应尽的份额了。
should I think that I should
我应该认为我应该
pay more tax especially when um I don't
缴纳更多税款，尤其是我不缴纳税款的时候
think my kids should get should should
我觉得我的孩子应该得到应该应该
benefit from my wealth and maybe this is
从我的财富中获益，也许这就是
a controversial opinion but I actually
这是一个有争议的观点，但我其实
don't I don't think I should be able to
不，我不认为我应该能够……
pass down my assets to my children you
把我的财产传给我的孩子们
can't it's 40% tax I think it should be
不行，税率是40%，我觉得应该是这样。
more 4 yeah let's not pretend rich
没错，别装富了。
people don't successfully pass their ass
人们无法成功地通过他们的屁股测试
their children I'm just telling you now
我现在就告诉你他们的孩子
I do think I'd be robbing my children of
我确实认为我会剥夺孩子们的权利。
something from the background that I
背景中的一些东西
came from if my CH my child gets
如果我的孩子被操了，就会发生这种情况。
if my child has gets tens of millions
如果我的孩子继承了数千万美元
let's say even when I die I don't think
假设我死了，我也不认为
that should happen well I agree people
那应该会发生，我同意大家的看法。
say when I talk about my sister people
当我谈到我的妹妹时，人们会说
like why don't you just give your sister
你为什么不直接给你妹妹呢？
a load of money listen my sister works
一大笔钱，听着，我姐姐在工作。
hard she's a smart person she works hard
她很努力，她很聪明，也很努力。
she produces good work I want to live in
她创作的作品很棒，我想住在她那里。
a society where people like my sister
这是一个像我姐姐这样的人都会遇到的社会
are able to support themselves with the
他们能够靠此养活自己
work that they do but we we're
他们所做的工作，但我们是
destroying that Society who would pay
摧毁那个愿意付出代价的社会
her the the customers you know this the
她，还有顾客们，你们都知道这一点。
situ so you want her to start a business
所以你想让她创业
she is a business yeah yeah and I want
她是个生意人，对对，我想要
people like her to be to be taxed less
像她这样的人应该少缴税。
so that what I want is ordinary working
所以，我想要的只是普通的工作。
people to be tax less so they have more
人们应该少缴税，这样他们就能有更多钱。
money in their pocket listen the reason
他们口袋里有钱，听听原因
we had the thriving art scene in the 60s
六十年代我们拥有蓬勃发展的艺术氛围。
is because we had a thriving middle
这是因为我们拥有一个繁荣的中产阶级。
class that could go and buy the new
能够去购买新东西的阶层
fashions and buy the new records and
时尚潮流，购买新唱片，以及
then that created this thriving art
于是，这便催生了这种蓬勃发展的艺术。
scene now we have a middle class which
现在我们看到的是一个中产阶级，
is struggling to pay the bills so they
他们难以支付账单，所以
can't they can't buy stuff they you know
他们买不了东西，你知道的。
my syst makes theater shows the only
我的系统让剧院演出成为唯一
people who go to the theater are rich
去剧院的人都是有钱人。
people now but back back in the day you
现在的人是这样，但以前的人却是那样。
know theater was something that was more
我知道戏剧是一种更……的东西。
accessible you want you want the Arts
方便你接触艺术
I've got to mate use a fashion designer
我得找个时装设计师。
right nowadays there's all of the
现在到处都是
business is super fast super cheap super
生意超级快，超级便宜，超级
disposable fashion or unbelievably
一次性时尚，或者令人难以置信的
expensive high-end because that's the
昂贵的高端产品，因为那就是
economy we've created I want you go to
我们创造的经济，我希望你去……
Japan which is a less unequal Society
日本是一个不平等程度较低的社会。
the restaurants are good quality
餐厅品质很好。
restaurants for ordinary people because
面向普通人的餐厅
a good capitalist Society will produce
一个良好的资本主义社会将会生产
things for the people with money in the
为有钱人准备的东西
case of theater where have the theater
剧院的例子，那里有剧院
consumers moved to where are they
消费者搬到了哪里？
getting their entertainment now well
他们现在的娱乐生活很不错
what you have is a very rich group of
你拥有的是一个非常丰富的群体
people who will still go to the theater
那些仍然会去剧院的人
and they will pay a lot but then you
他们会付很多钱，但之后你
have a large group of people who are
有一大群人
relatively cash scarce and they will try
现金相对短缺，他们会尝试
to get their entertainment in cheaper
为了更便宜地获得娱乐
ways of course you know what I mean
当然，你知道我的意思。
they're spending their time watching
他们把时间花在观看
your YouTube channel well exactly my you
你的YouTube频道，嗯，正是如此。
which is Free by the way yeah but you
顺便说一句，它是免费的，但是你
get paid from it you get the YouTube
从中获利，你就能获得 YouTube 的收益。
Honest it's only in the last couple of
说实话，这种情况只发生在最近几个月。
months that I started to make any money
几个月后我才开始赚钱。
because I don't do my own um editing so
因为我自己不做剪辑，所以
and you I mean you'll know but in the
我的意思是，你会知道的，但是在……
first few years you're paying yourself
头几年你要自己付工资。
to do it you know what I mean like I
你知道我的意思，就像我
think people some times massively
有时候人们会非常认真地思考这个问题。
overestimate the amount of money this is
高估了这笔钱的数额。
entrepreneurs entrepreneurs go through 2
企业家们要经历2
three four 5 years worth of struggle to
三、四、五年的奋斗
get to the point where they're
达到这样的程度
successful and it feels pretty horrific
成功了，但感觉相当可怕
that you say oh finally when I make it
当你终于成功时，你会说“哦，终于成功了”。
you take it um and then the advisers to
你接受它，然后是顾问们
entrepreneurs just 10 million is quite a
企业家们只有1000万美元，这相当可观。
lot of money so you know you can be
很多钱，所以你知道你可以
worth 9 million and not be paying
价值900万美元，却不用支付
anything more but what if I just raise 1
还有什么比这更贵的吗？但如果我只加1呢？
million for investment into my company
一百万美元投资我的公司
but that then like I do if I'm if if I'm
但是，如果我是，就像我那样，如果我是
raising money all the way along and my
一路筹集资金，而我的
investors are saying I'm sorry I don't
投资者们说，对不起，我没有
invest in the UK economy because it's
投资英国经济，因为它……
wealth taxes and all that sort of stuff
财富税以及诸如此类的东西
it's anti- wealth uh and then I just
它是反财富的，然后我就……
have to move my company overseas well I
我不得不把公司搬到海外，嗯……
want to create a situation where the UK
想要创造一种英国的局面
consumer is so strong that you have to
消费者力量如此强大，以至于你必须
invest in the UK you don't have to be
在英国投资，你不必非得是
here to sell to
这里是来卖东西的
them if you're looking to take the next
如果你想参加下一轮比赛，请参考以下建议。
step in your Tech Career you'll want to
在你的科技职业生涯中，你会想要迈出这一步
hear about our sponsor Inuit I've always
我一直都听说过我们的赞助商因纽特人。
believed that if you want to do your
相信如果你想做你的
best work you have to put yourself in
最好的作品需要你全身心投入。
the right environment you want to work
你想要的工作环境
with the best you want to work with the
与你最想合作的人一起
best tech technologists who are leading
最优秀的技术专家们正在引领潮流。
Innovation with data and Ai and this is
利用数据和人工智能进行创新，这就是
what you can expect into it they're
你可以期待它们包含以下内容：
growing their Tech careers building an
发展他们的技术职业生涯，构建
AI driven expert platform that connects
连接专家的AI驱动型平台
people to all the money they deserve The
人们应该得到他们应得的所有钱
Cutting Edge Tech they are developing in
他们正在开发的尖端技术
products like Turbo Tax Credit Karma
类似Turbo Tax Credit Karma的产品
Quick Books and MailChimp are helping
QuickBooks 和 MailChimp 正在提供帮助
around a 100 million customers and
约1亿客户和
businesses put more money in their
企业投入更多资金用于……
Pockets having a mission-driven culture
Pockets 拥有以使命为导向的文化
is something I really align with because
这一点我非常认同，因为
it's all about solving complex customer
一切都是为了解决复杂的客户问题。
problems with rapid experimentation to
快速实验存在的问题
move faster
加快速度
quite similar to the culture I want to
和我想要的文化非常相似。
Foster at my companies if this sounds
如果这听起来像福斯特在我公司的话
like you and you want to grow your Tech
就像你一样，你想发展你的科技事业。
Career working alongside the best check
与最优秀的同事一起工作，开启职业生涯
out intuit.com careers they also offer
访问 intuit.com 招聘网站，他们还提供其他职位。
hybrid work and a very inclusive culture
混合办公模式和非常包容的文化
with offices in Atlanta New York San
在亚特兰大、纽约和圣安东尼奥设有办事处
Diego the Bay Area Toronto and around
迭戈，多伦多湾区及周边地区
the world head over to in
世界前往
nitc careers to explore their
探索 nitc 职业生涯
opportunities quick one I want to talk
机会稍纵即逝，我想谈谈
to you about our sponsor whoop a
向您介绍我们的赞助商，哇哦！
business I'm also an investor in and if
我也是这家公司的投资者，而且如果
you follow me on Instagram you probably
如果你在Instagram上关注我，你可能
noticed that recently I've picked up
我注意到最近我拿起
running which I'm very much enjoying and
我非常享受跑步这项运动。
it started out as a challenge but it's
一开始是个挑战，但现在
now evolved into something I do almost
现在演变成了我几乎一直在做的事情
daily it is one of those things that's
这是每天都会发生的事之一。
pushing me to be better every single day
每天都激励我变得更好
but here's the thing to me progress
但对我来说，关键在于进步。
isn't just about pushing harder it's
不仅仅是更加努力，而是
also about training in a smarter way
也包括以更智能的方式进行训练
which is where my whoop comes in whoop
这就是我发出欢呼声的原因！
doesn't just track my workouts it tells
它不仅能追踪我的锻炼情况，还能告诉我
me how ready my body is to take them on
告诉我我的身体是否准备好迎接它们
before I've even started the workout a
在我开始锻炼之前……
few years ago we ran a study called
几年前，我们进行了一项名为……的研究
project p are and it found that Runners
项目 p 是，并且发现跑步者
who adjusted their training based on
他们根据以下内容调整了训练：
their recovery scores improved their 5K
他们的恢复成绩提高了5公里跑成绩。
times by an average of 2 minutes and 40
平均慢2分40秒
seconds while reducing injury Risk by
几秒钟内即可降低受伤风险
over 30% and they did it while training
超过30%的人做到了，而且他们是在训练期间做到的。
less so if you're looking for this type
如果你正在寻找这种类型的房源，那么这种可能性就小得多。
of guidance when it comes to your
在您相关事宜上提供指导
training head over to join. woop.com CEO
前往训练地点加入。 woop.com 首席执行官
and get a 30-day trial with zero
并获得 30 天免费试用。
commitment that's join. woop.com
加入即承诺。 woop.com
CEO let me know how you get on so so do
CEO，让我知道你的进展如何，所以……
we all agree on this premise though that
我们都同意这个前提，
Gary's saying which is the very the
加里说的正是……
ultra Rich which we can classify as
超级富豪，我们可以将其归类为
being worth more than you're saying we
我们比你说的更有价值
say 10 10 million is the line that we
比如说，1000万就是我们所说的这条线。
campaign for okay we we think that they
我们认为他们发起的竞选活动是可以的
should pay a greater share of the tax
应该缴纳更大比例的税款
and then the qu if you agree with that
然后，如果你同意的话，就回答这个问题。
premise the question then becomes yes
前提是，那么问题就变成了“是”。
but how yeah well they already do 1% pay
但是，他们确实已经支付1%的工资了。
30% I want to be clear that's the top 1%
30% 我想明确指出，这是前1%
of taxpayers which is not the top 1% of
纳税人中，并非收入最高的1%的纳税人
richest people mind you I'm also not
请注意，我也不是最富有的人。
necessarily saying um what's fair I'm
不一定非要说“嗯，什么是公平的”，我是
saying what's practically possible right
说出实际可行的事情
so like you could you could come up with
所以就像你可以想出……
the world's most Fair on a back of a
世界上最公平的背面
napkin this is what's fair but whether
餐巾纸，这才是公平的，但是是否
you can implement it is a very difficult
你能做到这件事非常困难。
thing the problem is wealth is
问题在于财富
completely mobile now it's really you
现在完全移动化了，这真的是你。
can live work from
可以居住和工作
anywhere the houses Dan yeah it's land
丹，房子在哪儿，是的，那是块地。
is that mobile you going rip you can't
那是你的手机吗？你要撕碎它？你不能
rip the country out of the out of the
把这个国家从……中剥离出来
sea there's very few I've never met any
大海里很少有，我从来没见过。
seriously wealthy people who own a lot
拥有大量资产的超级富豪
of houses you honestly think that the
你真心认为这些房子
entire housing stock of the UK is not
英国的全部住房存量并非如此。
valuable yeah no it is but 78% is owned
确实很有价值，但78%的股份都归他人所有。
by Baby Boomers they just own they've
婴儿潮一代，他们只是拥有他们所拥有的
they've bought a house in 1992 they own
他们在1992年买了一栋房子，他们拥有这栋房子。
the house personally I think that that
我个人认为那栋房子……
house ownership especially when you
拥有房产，尤其是在你
consider mortgages is relatively
考虑抵押贷款相对而言
unequally distributed that is by the way
顺便一提，这是分配不均的情况。
the most equally distribut young people
分布最均匀的年轻人
have now had the commercial property the
现在我们已经拥有了这处商业地产。
land the natural by Pension funds so
土地自然由养老基金提供
you're the viewers own it do they no
你们是观众，你们拥有它吗？他们没有
they're owned by if they own a pension
如果他们拥有养老金，那么他们就归谁所有。
fun most of those commercial what the
那些商业广告大多很有趣，它们是什么？
distribution of Pion what is the
π介子的分布是什么？
distribution of Pensions what percentage
养老金分配比例是多少？
of Pensions is owned by top 1% the I
养老金由收入最高的1%的人持有。
wouldn't know off the top of my head but
我一时想不起来，但是
with pensions but I know I know that OB
虽然有养老金，但我知道我知道，OB
obviously wealth concentrates at the top
财富显然集中在顶层。
but here's the one thing keep in mind
但有一点需要记住。
wealthy group are not necessarily a
富裕群体未必是
static group there was a study of the
静态组中有一项研究
richest people in 1900 and most of those
1900 年最富有的人以及其中的大多数人
families are poor today or they they've
如今，许多家庭都很贫困，或者他们已经……
gone down in value today uh if the
今天价值下跌了，呃，如果
richest people in 1900 had have just
1900 年最富有的人刚刚
simply kept their wealth there'd be
只是把财富留在那里而已。
16,000 more billionaires but but they
还有16000名亿万富翁，但是他们
they don't um you know in Wealth
他们不，你知道，在财富方面。
Management in Banks yeah they have this
银行管理层，是的，他们有这个
thing called the um succession planning
所谓继任计划
so succession planning is where they try
所以，继任计划就是他们尝试的地方。
and figure out how to not to screw it up
并想办法避免搞砸。
across generations and they're they're
跨越世代，他们是……
notoriously bad at it it's very hard to
他在这方面出了名的差劲，所以很难……
keep wealth in Generations down in the
将财富代代相传。
century we had two world wars and a
上个世纪我们经历了两次世界大战和一场
holocaust that redistributed
重新分配的大屠杀
wealth I would prefer not to have that
我宁愿不要那种财富。
again yeah yeah yeah I'm with you I want
没错没错没错，我和你在一起，我想要
a affluent middle class I I really do so
富裕的中产阶级，我真的这么认为。
where's the we going to come from you
我们该从哪里来？
want to just you're going to create your
你只想创建你的
entrepreneurs
企业家
entrepreneur entrepreneur economies that
企业家经济
are friendly towards wealth creation and
乐于创造财富，
Entrepreneurship was the last time you
创业是你上一次……
had a government that wasn't let's grow
有一个不支持增长的政府
let's grow let's
让我们成长吧
grow it's not working for the people
发展对人们来说行不通。
Daniel no the problem is is that they
丹尼尔，不，问题是他们
need to step back they need to let
他们需要后退一步，他们需要放手
shrink let shrink let shrink our viewers
缩小，缩小，缩小我们的观众群。
should keep close ey on Donald Trump and
应该密切关注唐纳德·特朗普和
Elon Musk because they're doing what
埃隆·马斯克，因为他们正在做什么
you're asking it'll be interesting to
你问这个问题会很有趣
see what happens right it's too soon to
看看接下来会发生什么，现在下结论还为时过早。
tell if you were trying to grow the UK
告诉我你是否试图发展英国
economy would you not take America
经济方面，你难道不想拿美国来说事吗？
approach because they seem to be much
因为他们看起来很多
more successful at growing growing their
更擅长发展壮大他们的
economy I think I mean of course when we
我觉得经济方面，我当然是指当我们
talk about slashing of the state they're
他们谈到要大幅削减国家预算。
going to use these examples like oh
我会用这些例子，比如哦
there's this wasteful government
这是一个浪费严重的政府
building everybody wants to slash
每个人都想砍掉的建筑
government waste of course I'm not going
政府浪费，我当然不会去。
to fight against slashing government
反对削减政府预算
waste um I'm from the UK you know I saw
浪费……嗯，我来自英国，你知道，我看到了
the austerity years I've seen what's
我亲眼目睹了那些紧缩岁月的种种……
happened to local Services I've seen
我看到当地服务部门也发生过类似情况。
what's happened to things like the
诸如此类的事情都发生了什么？
police like like education you know
警察就像教育一样，你知道的。
especially things like Youth Services um
尤其是像青少年服务之类的事情
you slash the state you fire a load of
你削减了国家，你发射了一大堆
people you know
你认识的人
what does the state okay yeah if you can
州政府怎么样？好的，如果你可以的话。
get rid of State corruption yes 100% if
彻底根除国家腐败，是的，百分之百赞成！
you can get rid of State waste 100% you
你可以100%消除国家浪费
know this is how single moms feed their
我知道单身母亲就是这样养活她们的。
kids
孩子们
Stephen you want to stop that no I'm
斯蒂芬，你想阻止这一切吗？不，我是
saying that slashing the
声称削减
state I don't think it's going to work
我认为这样做行不通。
um to be honest I think tariffs is is
嗯，老实说，我认为关税是……
not an uninteresting discussion I think
我觉得这并非一个无趣的讨论。
yeah of course tax avoidance is
当然，避税是必然的。
something you need to get rid of really
你真的需要扔掉它。
I would like to take a step back look at
我想退后一步，重新审视一下……
the country and say what is the state of
该国现状如何？
the country what what the people need
国家需要什么？人民需要什么？
you know we have a country here where
你知道我们这里有一个国家，
the housing stock is falling apart and
房屋破败不堪
we're letting it fall apart because
我们任由它分崩离析，因为
those houses are owned by ordinary
这些房子都是普通人拥有的。
people who don't have any money if you
如果你没钱，那些人……
want the country to work for ordinary
希望国家为普通民众服务。
people you need Ordinary People to have
你需要的普通人
money I'm always reminded of Mr Beast he
一提到钱，我总是会想起Mr Beast。
goes to places in Africa and he spends
他去非洲各地旅行，并在那里度过时光。
500 quid and he gives a kid eyesight who
他花了500英镑，让一个孩子重见光明。
would have been blind for the rest of
余生都将失明
their life for 500 quid why are kids in
他们的生命只值500英镑，为什么孩子们会……
Africa blind who could be given sight
非洲盲人，如果能够重见光明，将会怎样？
for 500 quid because they don't have any
因为他们没有货，所以要价500英镑。
money this is what happens when you
金钱，这就是当你……时发生的事情
drain your middle class you this will
榨干你的中产阶级，这将
end up like that you know you know I've
最后会变成那样，你知道，你知道，我已经
got a friend who went to India last week
我有个朋友上周去了印度。
he said there were people lying on the
他说有人躺在……
street outside with rotting limbs you
外面街道上满是腐烂的树枝
know that is what happens when you when
要知道，这就是当你……时发生的事情
you disempower when you take the money
你拿走钱就等于剥夺了别人的权力。
away from your middle class you've got
远离你的中产阶级，你已经……
to protect the middle class if the
为了保护中产阶级，如果
middle class had money then there would
中产阶级当时有钱。
be unbelievable business opportunities
难以置信的商业机会
for selling goods and services like your
用于销售您的商品和服务
business to the middle class so would
企业对中产阶级来说也是如此。
you tax Daniel more
你对丹尼尔的税收更多
I don't know if Daniel's worth more than
我不知道丹尼尔是否值更多钱。
10 million pounds it sounds like he is
听起来他有1000万英镑。
um is I mean I think I want to make it
嗯，我的意思是，我想把它做出来。
clear right you people you make 5% on
你们这些人很清楚，你们能赚到 5%
your wealth so if Daniel's worth 100
你的财富，所以如果丹尼尔身价100
million he's making 5 million we're
他赚了100万英镑，我们赚了500万英镑。
only trying to tax you 1% I think if you
我想他们只是想向你征收1%的税，如果你
are worth 100 million you're making 5
价值1亿美元，你赚了5
million pound passive income you can
你可以获得百万英镑的被动收入
afford to pay a million pound tax a year
每年能负担得起缴纳一百万英镑的税款吗？
you're going to still keep getting rich
你还会继续发财的。
the truth is even if we were to tax
事实是，即使我们对税收征税。
these billionaires 1% a year they would
这些亿万富翁每年会赚1%的钱。
still squeeze the rest out this is not
继续挤出剩下的部分，这不是
this is not about morality this is just
这与道德无关，这只是
cold hard economic analysis that I have
我拥有的冷酷无情的经济分析
made a lot of money betting on so
通过赌博赚了很多钱
closing arguments then chaps um I'll
结案陈词，伙计们，嗯，我会
start with you Gary based on everything
从你开始，加里，一切都基于你。
we've discussed today um what is I'm
我们今天讨论了……嗯，我是什么？
going to ask you to to give me two
我要请你给我两个
perspectives which is if I'm a young
如果我是一个年轻人，我的看法是……
individual in this country right now
这个国家现在的这个人
what should I do to protect myself and
我应该如何保护自己？
my family and to feed my family what
我的家人，以及如何养活我的家人。
kind of behaviors what strategy should I
我应该采取什么策略来应对这类行为？
drop there but also then from a
掉到那里，但也会从那里掉落
government level I know we have some
我知道政府层面有一些
politicians that listen because they
那些倾听的政治家，因为他们
message me what should politicians be
请告诉我政治家应该具备哪些素质。
doing to to fix the issue that we're all
我们正在努力解决我们面临的问题
clearly identify which is the collaps of
明确指出哪个是崩溃
the middle class the collaps of sort of
中产阶级的崩溃
working-class people and the the the
工人阶级和
increased wealth of the rich I think
我认为富人的财富增加了。
what I would like young people to
我希望年轻人……
understand is that this gets worse this
需要注意的是，这种情况会变得更糟。
getss much much worse it will get much
情况会变得更糟，而且会变得更加糟糕。
worse um relatively quickly uh poverty
情况恶化，贫困状况迅速恶化。
will increase relatively quickly it will
它将相对快速地增长
become
变得
increasingly difficult almost impossible
难度越来越大，几乎不可能
to make any serious money prepare
要想赚大钱，就要做好准备
yourself for that prepare yourself when
为此做好准备
you consider your finances when you
你在考虑财务状况时……
consider your plans for having a family
考虑一下你组建家庭的计划
um
嗯
this gets worse and it's going to be
情况会越来越糟，而且会……
really really hard it's going to be a
真的非常非常难，这将是一个
big mental health problem for a lot of
对很多人来说，这是一个严重的心理健康问题。
young people um so speak to people and
年轻人嘛，所以要和人们交谈。
understand that um my YouTube videos are
请理解，我的YouTube视频是
there G's economics people don't
那里的G经济学家们不这么认为
understand what's happening um after
了解接下来发生了什么
that you've got to do all the right
你必须做所有正确的事情
things yeah I mean I don't disagree with
是的，我的意思是，我并不反对。
you you've got to work hard you've got
你必须努力工作，你拥有
to study the right things um I I think
要学习正确的东西，嗯，我想
it's a great shame we have made subjects
很遗憾，我们已经把一些人当成了臣民
like the Arts um a thing which you
就像艺术一样，嗯，一件你……的事情
you're not allowed if you come from po
如果你来自波多黎各，你就不允许来。
poor backgrounds you cannot work in arts
出身贫寒的人无法从事艺术行业。
I'm sorry you can't pay the bills you
很抱歉你无法支付账单。
can't so you have to go and study Ai and
不行，所以你得去学习人工智能。
Computing and you know maybe social
计算机，还有社交，你知道的。
media although we have to be honest
媒体，尽管我们必须坦诚相待
social media doesn't pay for most people
对大多数人来说，社交媒体并不能带来收入。
um you have to realize the reality of
嗯，你必须认清现实。
your situation it's very very very very
你的情况非常非常非常非常
bad that doesn't mean you don't work
不好并不意味着你就不工作。
that doesn't mean you don't Aspire you
但这并不意味着你没有抱负。
work damn hard because you have to but
你必须拼命工作，但
if you manage to make enough money to
如果你能赚到足够的钱
even support a family you should be
即使要养家糊口，你也应该如此。
proud of yourself that that's the number
为自己取得这样的成绩感到自豪吧
one thing um but
有一件事，嗯，但是
recognize this can be changed this can
认识到这一点是可以改变的。
be changed our grandparents our
改变了我们的祖父母
great-grandparents fought for our
曾祖父母为我们而战
biggest share of the pie and they got it
他们得到了最大的一份蛋糕。
they got Healthcare they got education
他们获得了医疗保健，他们接受了教育。
they got housing they got food our young
他们有了住处，有了食物，我们的年轻人
people can have that as well but they
人们也可以拥有那种东西，但是他们
won't get it unless they fight for it so
除非他们争取，否则他们得不到。
I would encourage people
我会鼓励人们
to educate themselves support my work
他们通过学习来支持我的工作
get involved politically but also work
参与政治活动，同时也要工作。
hard support your friends and family try
尽力支持你的朋友和家人
and make money because you'll have
并且赚钱，因为你将拥有
to if you don't play politics I
如果你不参与政治，我
guarantee you the other side will play
保证对方会出手
politics and that means your kids and
政治，以及你的孩子，都与政治息息相关。
your grandkids live in poverty so you
你的孙辈生活在贫困之中，所以你
have to do both with regards to
这两方面都必须做到
politicians um I got mixed feelings
政治人物……嗯，我心情很复杂。
about a lot of politicians the truth is
关于很多政客，真相是……
I think a lot of politicians are very
我认为很多政客都非常
rich and and ultimately they don't care
有钱人，而且最终他们根本不在乎
they're protected a crisis of inequality
他们受到保护，免受不平等危机的影响
looks fantastic from the top and I think
从上面看真是太棒了，我觉得
that's why the three of us can sit here
这就是为什么我们三个可以坐在这里的原因。
and say things will be fine because for
并说一切都会好起来的，因为
us they will be fine and for our kids
对我们来说，他们会没事的，对我们的孩子来说也是如此。
they will be fine but for our viewers
他们会没事的，但对于我们的观众来说……
kids they won't be fine um the
孩子们，他们不会没事的。
politicians are not going to try and
政客们不会尝试这样做。
save you I'm going to try and make sure
为了救你，我会尽力确保
they do it but I don't think they will
他们会这么做，但我认为他们不会。
listen my plan is not to get concessions
听着，我的计划不是争取让步。
from politicians my plan is to get 5
我的计划是从政客那里争取5个席位。
million followers on the internet and
在互联网上拥有数百万粉丝
Bully the politicians so that they have
欺凌政客，让他们……
to give us what we need so I would
为了给我们提供所需之物，所以我愿意
support people to get behind me get
支持人们支持我
behind my campaign but also understand
在我的竞选背后，我也理解
what's happening educate your friends
发生了什么事？告诉你的朋友们
and your family and just crucially to
还有你的家人，以及至关重要的……
understand this is going to be a long
请理解这将是一个漫长的过程。
fight so be strong keep your people
奋战到底，坚强起来，守护你的人民
around you but be ready for what's to
你周围发生的一切，都要做好准备。
come I am I see hint and some of the
来吧，我来了，我看到了暗示和一些
things you've said recently of you going
你最近说过的一些关于你要去的事
into politics yourself at some point
你迟早会投身政治。
Stephen I'm in politics but I me
斯蒂芬，我涉足政坛，但我……
politics actively listen I I do not want
政治积极倾听我不想
to be an MP I do not want to be
我不想当国会议员
Chancellor I do not want to be prime
总理，我不想当首相。
minister if we get to a point where I
部长，如果我们到了那种地步，我
feel that that is something that is
感觉那是……
achieved when is the best way to fix
何时达到最佳修复效果
this problem I will be open to it this
这个问题，我会持开放态度。
is not plan a this is not you know would
这不是计划，你知道的。
you like to be prime minister I suspect
我怀疑你很想当首相。
probably not right like this is I'll be
可能这样不太合适，我会……
honest I I am quite uncomfortable with
说实话，我对此感到很不自在。
even the level of um public profile that
甚至公众知名度的水平
I have at the moment which is you know
我现在有的，你知道的
it's much less than what you have but it
虽然比你拥有的少得多，但它
stresses me out and it's weird we spoke
这让我很紧张，而且我们居然还聊过天，感觉很奇怪。
about it before we were shooting um I
关于拍摄之前的事，嗯……
don't want to can you imagine I I don't
我不想，你能想象吗？我不想
want to be prime minister I don't want
我不想当首相。
to be an MP um but I'm serious about
想当国会议员？嗯，我是认真的。
this work that I do and if we reach a
我所做的这项工作，如果我们能达到一个
point that I think that is the best way
我认为这是最好的方法。
to do it I will consider it but I would
我会考虑这么做，但我不会
much rather be able to influence the MPS
我更希望能够影响MPS。
from the sideline to influence the
从场边施加影响
politicians from the sidelines and for
边缘政治家和为了
that person you just gave advice to who
你刚才给的那个人，
should they be voting for well we don't
他们应该投票吗？我们不投票。
have an election for listen
举行选举以听取意见
politics is not football politics is not
政治不是足球，政治不是
football okay this is not about I'm
足球，好吧，这跟我无关。
labor I'm conservative I'm Republican
我是劳工，我是保守派，我是共和党人
I'm Democrat you're losing your houses
我是民主党人，你们正在失去你们的房子
here you you're losing your houses your
你们正在失去你们的房子
kids will be in poverty and you're going
孩子们会陷入贫困，而你却要离开。
to see both Trump and the Republicans
既要见特朗普，也要见共和党人。
and Karma and labor who are supposed to
还有业力和劳动，他们本应……
be on the opposite side of the political
站在政治的对立面
spectrum they will both fail because
频谱方面，它们都会失败，因为
they will not take action on growing
他们不会对增长采取行动
wealth inequality and I'll be right on
财富不平等，我马上就来。
that you know bring me back in a few
你知道，过几天就把我带回来。
years I'll be right on that and um that
几年后我会说到做到，嗯……
shows you it's not about I think this
这说明这不是关于我认为这件事的问题。
factionalism is unbelievable damaging to
派系斗争对……的危害难以置信
our societies especially in the US where
我们的社会，尤其是在美国，
there's so much hatred behind it where
这背后隐藏着太多的仇恨
suddenly I'm on this side you're on that
突然间，我站在这边，你站在那边。
side we're going to shake hands after
我们这边之后会握手。
this nothing we will you know it's
这没什么，我们会让你知道的。
there's no hatred here but if you allow
这里没有仇恨，但如果你允许
yourself to be divided from half of your
你将自己与你的一半分开
country and you allow we're seeing it
国家，你允许我们看到这一点
growing tensions racial tensions gender
日益加剧的种族和性别紧张局势
tensions if you allow yourself to be
如果你允许自己处于紧张状态
divided they will win they will win so
分裂他们就能赢，他们就能赢。
you need to vote for whoever is going to
你需要投票给即将上任的候选人。
protect your houses and if you want to
保护你的房屋，如果你想……
know who that is come and check Gary's
知道那是谁吗？过来看看加里。
economics before the election and I will
选举前的经济形势，我将
tell you who it's going to be
告诉你会是谁
Daniel nice closing arguments personal
丹尼尔的结语很精彩，个人观点也很棒。
and social a a few things um I read
还有一些社交方面的事情，嗯，我读过。
Gary's bookin it's brilliant and
加里预订的房间很棒，
regardless of um regardless of whether
不管……不管是否
you actually like economics it's a
你其实喜欢经济学，这真是……
brilliant story it's a really I read it
故事很精彩，我读过了。
in about two or three days um and it'll
大概两三天后，嗯，就会
it'll eventually be a good movie as well
它最终也会成为一部好电影。
um I agree with a lot of what Gary's
嗯，我同意加里的大部分观点。
saying um there is a collapse of the
据说，嗯，出现了崩溃……
middle class uh and it probably will get
中产阶级，嗯，而且它可能会……
worse uh and the traditional middle
更糟的是，还有传统的中间地带
class jobs that came out of the back of
课堂上出现的那些工作
the Industrial Age mature Industrial
工业时代成熟的工业
Revolution system th those are
革命制度就是那些
collapsing and it's globalizing we're
崩溃，而且全球化，我们正在
seeing technology move opportunities all
看到技术带来的机遇
over the world um and wealth inequality
世界各地的财富不平等
it has a cause uh wealth inequality
它有其原因，即财富不平等。
itself is a scoreboard and there's a
它本身就是一个记分牌，而且还有一个
cause for what led up to wealth
导致财富积累的原因
inequality and the cause in my mind is
我认为造成不平等的原因在于……
technology technology is moving the
科技正在推动……
those opportunities around and it's
周围有很多机会，而且是
changing things we already have big
改变我们已经拥有的东西
governments we have huge amounts of
政府我们拥有大量的
taxes we're at record levels of tax taes
税收方面，我们目前的税收水平创历史新高。
um uh wealth has never been more mobile
嗯，财富从未像现在这样容易流动。
it's not about what's fair it's about
这不是关于公平的问题，而是关于……
what you can practically get away with
你实际上可以逃脱惩罚的
it's about what you can actually
关键在于你实际能做到什么。
Implement um and uh it's going to be
实施嗯，而且它将会是
very very as Gary said it's going to be
正如加里所说，情况确实会如此。
very very very hard to tax people who
对那些人来说，征税是非常非常非常困难的。
have digital businesses who can live and
拥有能够生存和发展的数字企业
work from anywhere I know that firsthand
在任何我熟悉的地方工作
um that it's incredibly mobile with that
嗯，它在这方面非常便携。
said at a micro level oh sorry at a
微观层面上说哦，对不起
macro level big picture we do know that
从宏观层面来看，我们知道这一点。
there is a correlation between economic
经济与经济之间存在相关性。
freedom where the government gets out of
政府退出的自由
your way and low poverty rates and we
你的方式和低贫困率，以及我们
know that as soon as governments become
要知道，一旦政府……
big uh high taxes High regulations it
高税收、高监管
actually drops down a category and we
实际上，它下降了一个类别，而我们
see poverty goes up from 10% to 30% so
看到贫困率从10%上升到30%
triples um so constricting economic
三倍，嗯，所以限制经济
freedom is never a good idea uh if you
自由从来都不是个好主意，呃，如果你
look at the data at a micro level
从微观层面分析数据
there's never been a greater opportunity
现在正是绝佳的机会。
for anyone who's ambitious and
对于任何有抱负的人来说，
entrepreneurial to go and start a
有创业精神，去创办一家
company it's cheaper than ever to start
现在创办一家公司比以往任何时候都更便宜。
a company you can do what Gary's done
一家公司，你可以做到加里所做的事。
which is publish content build a
即发布内容并构建
following uh figure out how to monetize
接下来，我想办法实现盈利。
it uh you can create products and
呃，你可以创建产品，
services and sell them to anywhere in
提供服务并将其出售给任何地方
the world um you're an example of
世界啊，你就是个例子
someone who started with nothing and
一个白手起家的人
became a millionaire in your 20s and
20多岁就成了百万富翁
then again in your 30s with a completely
然后到了30多岁，又完全
different thing he became a millionaire
他做了一件完全不同的事情，他成了百万富翁
in his 20s and then again in his 30s
他二十多岁时，以及三十多岁时，都曾有过这样的经历。
is's a bestselling author and a content
是一位畅销书作家和内容创作者
creator I did it in my 20s my 30s and
创作者 我在20多岁、30多岁的时候都做过这件事，
now my 40s um starting from scratch so
现在我四十多岁了，一切都要从头开始。
it's it's not normal that three guys our
这不正常，三个男人
agage could have done that over and over
艾格本可以一遍又一遍地这样做。
again it's because we are living in a
这又是因为我们生活在一个
time where there is incredible
那是令人难以置信的时刻。
opportunities but you have to be tapped
机会，但你必须主动争取。
into those opportunities you never heard
抓住那些你从未听说过的机会
about it at school you never heard about
学校里关于这件事你从来没听说过。
it at University you're going to have to
在大学里你必须……
learn the skills to get tapped into
学习融入社会所需的技能
those OPP opportunities but there are
那些 OPP 机会，但也有
definitely ways that you can succeed in
当然，有很多方法可以让你取得成功。
the world that we're living in and on
我们所生活的世界以及……
that macro Point who should we be voting
那个宏观问题：我们应该投票给谁？
for because some of your thinking in
因为你的一些想法
policy suggestions through this
通过这种方式提出的政策建议
conversation align more with Trump Elon
对话更符合特朗普和埃隆·马斯克的观点。
the American Mission now where they're
美国传教团现在在哪里
welcoming millionaires they're trying to
欢迎百万富翁们，他们正试图
create a really entrepreneurship
创造真正的创业精神
friendly environment they're doing the
他们营造了友好的环境
Doge dismantling of sort of government
道奇解散某种政府
waste I I agree with Gary it's not
我同意加里的说法，这不是浪费。
football you don't have a team you swing
足球，你没有固定的球队，你只是摇摆不定。
you should be a swing voter you should
你应该成为一名摇摆选民
vote every single election you should
你应该参加每一次选举，都要投票。
make them work hard for your vote and
让他们努力争取你的选票
you should is Trump going to succeed
你应该看看特朗普会成功吗？
though you should see it's too soon to
不过你应该明白，现在还为时过早。
tell but he made a prediction so I'm
告诉他，但他做出了预测，所以我……
inviting you to make a prediction he
他邀请你做出预测。
said five years time we come back here
我们说五年后我们会回到这里。
we're going to see that Trump I think I
我们会看到特朗普，我认为我
think a lot of very wealthy people are
我认为很多非常富有的人都是
going to move move to the USA um you're
准备搬家，搬到美国，嗯，你是
going to get a lot of people from all
将会吸引来自四面八方的很多人
over the world he's playing to win and
在世界各地，他都以胜利为目标而战。
he wants rich people and entrepreneurs
他想要的是富人和企业家。
and investors to come into the US and be
并吸引投资者进入美国。
based there he's creating golden visas
他以那里为基地，正在创建黄金签证。
and open visas and the success metric
以及开放签证和成功指标
here is the middle class get richer and
这是中产阶级变得更加富裕的过程。
more affluent what I actually think will
更富裕的人，我真正认为会
happen as a result of all of that you
这一切都是你所经历的一切的结果。
will see Rising living standards in the
将会看到生活水平的提高。
USA and you'll see a detriment to the
美国将会受到损害。
places where those people live it's not
那些人居住的地方并非如此。
a good thing to have the people who pay
有付费者是一件好事
the majority of the taxes which is 1% of
大部分税收，即1%
people paying 30% of taxes if those
如果这些人缴纳30%的税款
people leave the bills get spread across
人们离开后，账单就会分摊到各个方面。
everybody else well we'll have to do a
至于其他人，我们得做一件事。
part two and we shall see um I want to
第二部分，我们拭目以待，嗯，我想……
thank you both for the work that you do
感谢你们二位所做的工作。
because I'm a big fan of both of you I
因为我是你们俩的忠实粉丝
watch Gary's videos all the time helps
经常看Gary的视频很有帮助。
me to understand another perspective on
让我理解另一种视角
what I'm typically hearing out out on
我通常听到的关于
the Internet or that I hear on Twitter
互联网上或者我在推特上听到的
about what's going on in the world and I
关于世界上正在发生的事情，以及我
think I really respect and admire people
我觉得我真的很尊重和钦佩人们
that can do what both of you have done
它可以做到你们俩所做的一切。
today which is to exchange and listen to
今天的主题是交流和聆听
ideas in the pursuit of answers uh and
在寻求答案的过程中产生的想法
that's why I'd highly recommend anybody
这就是为什么我强烈推荐任何人
regardless of whether you agree with
无论你是否同意
everything or some things or or or just
一切或某些东西或或或或只是
a little bit to go and follow Gary's
稍微走一点，然后跟着加里走。
Channel on YouTube called Gary's
YouTube 频道名为 Gary's
economics because it's a great source of
经济学，因为它是一个很好的来源
information from someone who has done it
来自做过这件事的人的信息
from understands the world from another
从另一个角度理解世界
perspective but also someone who's
既有远见，又具备……
providing a narrative which I actually
提供一个我实际上
think there's we kind of talked about
我想我们之前也谈到过这个。
before you started there's a big gap in
在你开始之前，存在一个很大的差距
the market for there are a lot of people
市场上有很多这样的人
like me and Dan out on the internet that
就像我和丹在网上那样
are talking about entrepreneurship and
正在谈论创业精神和
finance and how to make money but there
金融以及如何赚钱，但是……
aren't enough people talking about
难道讨论的人还不够多吗？
wealth inequality from the perspective
从以下角度看财富不平等
as Gary sees
加里眼中的世界
um and that are providing more sort of
嗯，而且它们提供了更多类型的
uh collectivist and sort of society
呃，集体主义社会
wide Solutions and answers and sort of
广泛的解决方案和答案以及各种
explanations as to why that's ultimately
解释其最终原因
happening I do think I do think because
我觉得这件事正在发生，因为
I know you Dan I hope I know myself I do
我知道你，丹，我希望我也了解我自己。
think that we we all want the UK to
我们都希望英国
survive and I think we all believe that
生存下去，我想我们都相信这一点。
the way that the UK survives isn't
英国得以生存的方式并非如此
necessarily a couple of ultra rich
必然是一对超级富豪
people getting more money it is sort of
人们收入增加，这有点像……
social mobility and it's allowing people
社会流动性，它使人们能够……
that are at the very bottom to create
处于最底层以创造
opportunities and to succeed we all
机会和成功，我们所有人
agree upon that even if we agree
即使我们同意，也同意这一点
disagree sorry on the causes and the
我不同意这些解释，抱歉。
solutions to that um I'd also highly
对此，我也有很高的期望。
recommend everybody to go check out the
建议大家去看看
trading game because everybody's talking
因为大家都在谈论交易游戏，所以大家都在谈论它。
about this this book and I think it's
关于这本书，我认为它是
what four weeks at the moment on the
目前是四周前
Sunday Times besteller list four weeks
《星期日泰晤士报》畅销书榜单连续四周
number one number one four weeks number
排名第一，连续四周排名第一
one which is an incredible achievement
这是一项了不起的成就
but it speaks to what's in this book the
但这正说明了这本书的内容。
way that the story is told but also the
故事的讲述方式，以及
timeliness of this message so I'd highly
这条消息非常及时，所以我强烈推荐
recommend everybody to go check it out
推荐大家去看看。
I'm going to put a link below so that
我会在下方放一个链接，以便
everybody can go and do it and if you
每个人都可以去做，如果你
just look at some of the um the the
看看其中一些……
testimonials for this book it's profound
这本书的评价非常深刻。
I hear people describe it as like
我听人这样描述它：
Unforgettable on one end and then sad on
一方面令人难忘，另一方面又令人伤感
the other end because that's the nature
另一端，因为这就是它的本质。
of the reality it speaks to and I highly
它所反映的现实，我非常
recommend everybody to go check out Dan
推荐大家去看看丹
priestley's entreprene Revolution but
普里斯特利的创业革命，但
also your website has all of your
你的网站上也有你所有的
resources and tools on it so I'll link
这里有一些资源和工具，我会附上链接。
that on the screen what's the uh Danel
屏幕上那个是什么？呃，丹尼尔
priest.com Danel priest.com thank you
priest.com Danel priest.com 谢谢
both for your generosity really really
非常感谢您的慷慨解囊
appreciate it thanks for bringing us
非常感谢你带我们来。
together no matter where in the world it
无论身处世界何处，我们都在一起
seems like everyone is drinking matcha
好像每个人都在喝抹茶
and there's a good chance that that
而且很有可能如此。
matcha you're drinking is made by a
你喝的抹茶是由……制成的
company that I've invested more than
我投资超过一家公司的资金
seven figures in who are a sponsor of
七位数的赞助商
this podcast called perfect Ted because
这个播客叫做“完美泰德”，因为
they're the brand used globally by cafes
这是全球咖啡馆普遍使用的品牌。
like blank Street Coffee and Joe and the
就像空白的街咖啡和乔和
juice and many many more not only can
果汁等等，不仅可以
you get perfect Ted match in cafes but
你在咖啡馆里能找到和Ted完美匹配的人，但是
you can now also make it at home much
现在你也可以在家自己做了。
cheaper in seconds using our flavored
使用我们风味独特的产品，只需几秒钟即可节省更多。
matcha powders that I have here in front
我面前这些抹茶粉
of me perfect Ted matcher is ceremonial
对我来说，完美的泰德配对是仪式性的
grade and source from Japan it is smooth
这款产品等级和产地均来自日本，质地顺滑。
it is naturally sweet not like those
它是天然的甜味，不像那些甜的。
bitter grassy matches that I tried
我试过的苦涩的草火柴
before perfect Ted and if you are one of
在完美泰德之前，如果你是其中之一
those people that have told yourself you
那些曾对你说过话的人
don't like matcha it's probably because
不喜欢抹茶可能是因为
you haven't tried our perfect Ted matcha
你还没尝过我们完美的泰德抹茶
and you can find perfect Ted matcha in
你可以在Ted Matcha找到完美的抹茶
the UK and Tesco sainsbury Holland and
英国和荷兰的 Tesco Sainsbury 超市
Barett and in waitrose or Albert Hine if
Barett 和 Waitrose 或 Albert Hine 如果
you're in the Netherlands and on Amazon
你身处荷兰，正在使用亚马逊。
in the USA or'll get the full range
在美国，或者将获得全系列产品
online at perfect ted.com where you can
在 perfect ted.com 网站上，您可以……
get 40% off your first order with code
使用优惠码即可享受首单40%折扣
Steve even
史蒂夫甚至
40 this has always blown my mind a
40 这件事一直让我感到震惊
little bit 53% of you that listen to
53% 的人听过这话
this show regularly haven't yet
这个节目经常还没有播出。
subscribed to the show so could I ask
我订阅了该节目，所以可以问一下吗？
you for a favor if you like the show and
如果你喜欢这个节目，就请你帮个忙吧。
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen to
我们每周都会听你的节目。
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈将帮助我们找到合适的客人
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do thank you so
请继续做我们正在做的事情，谢谢。
much much
很多很多
[Music]
[音乐]